<string id="pda_krysyka_name"><text>PDA Rat</text></string>
<string id="mil_vasilev_name"><text>Unknown</text></string>
<string id="pda_krysyka_desc"><text>A PDA sealed tight. Contains secrets of the bandit group under the leadership of boss Borov.</text></string>

<string id="marsh_treasure"><text>According to Frol, there was supposed to be a weapons cache somewhere around here... Probably been cleaned out ages ago.</text></string>
<string id="vodka_rad"><text>Bootleg vodka</text></string>
<string id="vodka_rad_descr"><text>There was one dealer in the Zone, tried selling cheap vodka. The dealer's now on the other side cursing his greed.</text></string>
<string id="food_bread_rad"><text>Radioactive bread</text></string>
<string id="enc_food_bread_rad"><text>Was normal bread once... Now it's radioactive... If you're sick of living, you can eat it.</text></string>
<string id="nazar_treasure"><text>Hunters' stash</text></string>

<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, bro... Gonna shoot the breeze?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_1"><text>And no coughin' to you too... What we chattin' 'bout?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_2"><text>Just this and that... sit a bit, crack open a bottle...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_3"><text>Well, pour it out...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_31"><text>Beat it, I don't drink with just anyone...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_91"><text>Then get lost!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_41"><text>Let's take a swig...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_42"><text>Motherf... We're out of the nectar...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_5"><text>Ohhh... That hit the spot... Could use a sniff of bacon...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_6"><text>Listen, pal... Heard any-y-thing interesting?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_71"><text>Just for you, bro... Found a PDA on a corpse recently, had info about a stash... Too lazy to trek there myself, but since you're a solid mate, you can 'ave it.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_73"><text>You're something... dude, what's there to be interestin' here, this ain't Rio-de-Zhytomyr... Boring as hell!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_81"><text>If I got nothing better to do, I'll swing by, take a looksie...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_82"><text>Alright, if you got sumthin' - give me a shout...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_0"><text>How's life, pal?... Let's hang out?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_1"><text>No problem, fo' sho... Get your ass over here...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_2"><text>Fo' real, could use some grub...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_3"><text>Let's pour it out, and we'll find some grub, don't worry...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_31"><text>Beat it, I don't drink with just anyone...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_91"><text>Then get lost!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_41"><text>Let's do it then, for the boys...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_42"><text>Nah, man, if I had any...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_5"><text>For the boys, fo' real...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_6"><text>Man, whistle sumthin' interesting... Eh?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_71"><text>Interesting? Heard some chatter at a gatherin', seems like there's a stash that ain't been touched... I ain't draggin' my ass that far, got enough suckers here to work with, if it ain't too much trouble, write down the tip...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_73"><text>Catch a bird, it'll whistle for ya...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_81"><text>Nah, too much trouble for me too, if I pass by - won't even bend down...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_82"><text>Chill out, twerp...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_0"><text>Greetings to the bosses! What y'all chattin' about?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_1"><text>Greetings, greetings. Sucker. Even though Borov ordered us not to touch you, don't push it...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_2"><text>Boring without vodka... And in prison right now it's dinner time, they're givin' pasta!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_3"><text>Don't croak, better pour some for the brothers...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_31"><text>Beat it, I don't drink with just anyone...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_91"><text>Then get lost!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_41"><text>Alright, brothers. So it don't go sideways!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_42"><text>Right, gonna chat with Borov and then pour.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_5"><text>Mmmm, respect! Should've started with this...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_6"><text>What's new to hear? Heard any-y-thing interesting?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_71"><text>What's new... Yesterday we took three Duty boys with the guys, they just sit on their posts like pretzels, and then right away: "guys, don't do it"... "can show ya loot"... What loot, they think they can mess with our heads and slip away quiet-like, then come back with the whole gang... Heh... And he's like: "there's a stash real close", what a moron, eh? Ah, screw it all... That stash of his... Now... Oh! There it is!.. Check it out...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_73"><text>What's new? What's new here, it's all the same old thing!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_81"><text>Ha, half a day's trek there, they were definitely messin' with our heads...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_82"><text>Later, when you got a half-liter, drop by...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_0"><text>Well! Look who I see! How many years, how many winters!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_1"><text>Beat it, can't you see I'm tired after yesterday...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_2"><text>Well come on, let's fix our health...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_3"><text>Yesterday we drank everything, totally broke...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_31"><text>Beat it, I don't drink with just anyone...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_91"><text>Then get lost!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_41"><text>Always keep a little medicine for health... Let's go!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_42"><text>Oops! And I'm empty today...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_5"><text>Ohhh... Benefactor...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_6"><text>What they sayin' at your place? Any more loot spots?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_71"><text>You bet! Don't make too much noise, I saw how Borov's lackeys were hidin' loot here... Won't take it myself, 'cause it's strict with us, might wake up with a shiv in your liver, but you came - you left, nobody'll notice. And when you're passin' by, drop in, we'll think of a couple more deals... Deal?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_73"><text>All the loot spots Borov took for himself, we get the crumbs...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_81"><text>Deal!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_82"><text>Alright, I'm outta here, bye...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, little brother... How's it going?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_1"><text>Nothing special, seems like... You want something or just passing by?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_2"><text>Just like that... it's quiet here, figured I'd sit a bit, fix our health...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_3"><text>Health is good, pour some, I guess...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_31"><text>My health is fine, not drinking today...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_41"><text>Well, let's have a little bit...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_42"><text>Could use someone pouring for me...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_5"><text>Strong... Son of a bitch... Could use a sniff of bacon...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_6"><text>Yeah... That hit the sp-o-ot... Probably don't know anything interesting?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_71"><text>Recently pulled a stalker out of an anomaly with Wolf, or rather what was left of him... Yeah... He had a note with coordinates. Said there's hidden loot there... But Wolf said not to go there. Here are the coordinates: write them down, if it's worth it, tell me later... Deal?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_73"><text>Nah, I'm new here, haven't gone deep yet... Come back in a week, maybe I'll learn something...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_81"><text>Deal... I'll take a look...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_82"><text>Alright, we'll talk more when there's time...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, how's stalker life?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_1"><text>Hey there to you too, Marked One... So-so... Taking it slow...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_2"><text>Maybe five drops each on the chest? To fix our health...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_3"><text>Wouldn't hurt! Treat me, since you're so kind...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_31"><text>My health is fine, not drinking today...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_41"><text>Well, let's have a hundred fifty for courage...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_42"><text>Just a sec, gotta run to Sidorovich real quick...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_5"><text>Cough cough, damn... What'd they make this from, a stool? Almost came back up...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_6"><text>Anything can happen here... Tell me something...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_71"><text>Recently a couple stalkers came to Sidorovich... I was sleeping in Sidorovich's anteroom. Well, not really sleeping, more like half-watching... They wanted to trade some gear from him, on credit, so to speak... They said there's a rich stash with loot, even described the place... But Sidorovich didn't give them anything - what a cheapskate, eh? Thought about going myself, but can't work up the nerve. Here's the place, see? If there's anything good, you won't forget about me?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_73"><text>What's to tell... It's the Zone, it is what it is, wish I could get out of here...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_81"><text>If there's anything worthwhile, I won't forget...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_82"><text>We'll get out, someday...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_0"><text>Why are you so gloomy?... Maybe you need help?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_1"><text>What's there to be cheerful about? So depressing, could hang myself...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_2"><text>Well, let's have some, not for drunkenness sake, but for mood...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_3"><text>Ah, let's do it! Maybe it'll help...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_31"><text>My mood is fine, not drinking today...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_41"><text>So... Hold steady... For HOPE!</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_42"><text>Damn! I remember for sure: had a bottle! And it's GONE!</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_5"><text>For her, dear one... Thanks, good men still exist...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_6"><text>They say you can find loot nearby, haven't heard?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_71"><text>Yeah, they say there's a stash with loot, and not that far from here... But whoever went to check, nobody came back. Let me show you on the map: right here...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_73"><text>Nah, haven't heard... I don't really listen to chatterboxes...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_81"><text>Won't go specially, but if I'm nearby, I'll take a look...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_82"><text>That's right, less you know - better you sleep...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, guy... Maybe we'll have a drink?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_1"><text>Hey there... What's the talk about...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_2"><text>Let's sit, wag our tongues over some good snacks...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_3"><text>Snacks are on me, come on pour it, what are you waiting for?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_31"><text>No time for me to wag tongues, gotta move soon...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_41"><text>There she is, dear one, clear as a tear!</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_42"><text>Got snacks... But her, dear one, no...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_5"><text>Phew, good stuff! Went right through to my ass... Good!</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_6"><text>I understand... what's the word in the Zone?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_71"><text>Day before yesterday cracked open a couple bottles with the soldiers... Had a sit... They run here from Agroprom pretty often, Sidorovich supplies them with vodka. So they told me they caught a zombified stalker, well, you understand, he mumbles and grabs for his gun. The commander ordered to take him alive, send him to the eggheads on the mainland - for experiments, yeah... I think better would've been a bullet to the temple right away... Yeah, what was I talking about?.. Ah, well, this zombie had a drawing right on his hand, like a tattoo, but not a real one, more like someone carved it with a knife... Like a map. Their commander checked it against the landmarks - and it looks like there's a stash with loot not far from here. About right here...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_73"><text>Lot of things to hear, about anomalies, about monsters, can't tell everything at once, come back again, we'll talk...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_81"><text>Yeah, better right away... without suffering...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_82"><text>I'll come back, we'll talk...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, brother... How are things with you guys?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_1"><text>Mutants sometimes attack... But otherwise seems everything's normal...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_2"><text>Let's drink to getting acquainted?.. Or command won't allow it?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_3"><text>What command... Our sergeant is an old serviceman, understands that in the Zone you can't do without this. So don't worry - pour it.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_31"><text>It's not about command, just not in the mood...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_41"><text>Well! For good people!..</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_42"><text>Would pour some, but had to spend the last half-liter on health...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_5"><text>For us, that is! Have a snack, here's some sausage...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_6"><text>Thanks... What's the word here? Maybe some news?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_71"><text>No special news. But heard about Max Luber? Bandits from Dark Valley caught him with his buddy... Bullet - Luber's friend - went after their trail... And before that he said that Max's buddy managed to drop a map marking a place with hidden loot... Here! Bullet asked someone to go there, but Prapor didn't allow it, said there's already too few fighters left at the post. Anyway, here's this place, take it so the bandits don't get it.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_73"><text>Don't think I heard anything special, just small stuff...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_81"><text>Alright, I'll take it...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_82"><text>Well, see ya later, we'll meet again...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_0"><text>Greetings, serviceman!</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_1"><text>Same to you... Where'd you come from?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_2"><text>Just wandering the Zone slowly... How about a hundred grams?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_3"><text>What kind of question is that! Two hundred grams never hurt anyone...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_41"><text>Take two fifty and no snacks...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_42"><text>Gonna dump these artifacts on Barkeep and come back...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_5"><text>Ha, went down smooth... Why chase such nectar with food...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_6"><text>That's for sure, just wasting good stuff... Tell me something...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_71"><text>Few days ago Bes was visiting here, good man, even though he's a loner... No offense, right? We helped him out a bit with ammo, talked about this and that... He didn't have anything valuable, so he told us about a stash he found. No loot there though, but judging by the signs, someone often hides stuff there. If you're interested, scout it out, see whose it is...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_73"><text>What's to tell... It's the Zone, it is what it is, if it wasn't for us, the infection would've spread all over the world long ago...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_81"><text>I'll try to scout it out...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_82"><text>Well, bye then, savior of the world...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, man, your face looks familiar, haven't we met before?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_1"><text>Who knows, I only remember those I'm friends with...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_2"><text>Well, come on, not for cursed drunkenness, but for friendship...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_3"><text>Well now, seems like I remember... Come on, pour it!</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_41"><text>So... Hold steady... For Friendship!</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_42"><text>Damn! I remember for sure - had a bottle! And it's GONE!</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_5"><text>For reliable friends! With whom you won't perish even in the Zone!</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_6"><text>They say you can find loot nearby, haven't heard?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_71"><text>Haven't told anyone, but I'll tell you as a friend. There's a tip about one stash... Found out about it by accident. Maybe there's nothing there, maybe there's a shitload of loot. If you're a real friend, you'll share, I think?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_73"><text>Nah, haven't heard... Gathered everything that was nearby, and what's further out, only Strelok knows...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_81"><text>No question! For a friend nothing's too much...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_82"><text>Strelok? Well, well... I have a question or two for him...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, let's talk, you don't mind?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_1"><text>Have a seat... What's the talk about...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_2"><text>Maybe five drops each for lubrication?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_3"><text>Snacks are on me, come on, pour it, what are you waiting for?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_41"><text>Hold the glasses steady, or I won't see the edges...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_42"><text>Got snacks... But her, dear one, no...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_5"><text>It burns... Ooh! Lubricated like oil...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_6"><text>Isn't it depressing sitting here all day?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_71"><text>Nah, what's to be depressed about? Barkeep delivers snacks, supposedly pays for protection... Loners pass by often, share the latest info... Plus there's stuff to shoot at. \nFunny story: bandits been getting cocky lately, setting up ambushes... So there's one lying there, pretending to be a wounded stalker, sending SOS on all frequencies. And a pair of burers ran into him... As soon as this "wounded" guy heard their screams, he grabbed his legs and bolted, not looking where he was going. Flew right into our camp and headfirst into the awning support - crash! Noise, crackling, stench - this lover of easy loot shit himself to the ears... Then he was shaking and promising to make everyone rich, said he hid loot and marked it on the map... What a fool, really... None of us gonna risk our asses for some loot. We're a barrier! Protecting the world from evil. If you're interested, here's his mark...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_73"><text>Depressing, of course, but at least you feel useful - protecting the World from evil!</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_81"><text>Yeah, he was funny... I'll check it out if I get a chance, though I think it's bullshit...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_82"><text>Well then, won't distract the hero...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, little brother... How's life?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_1"><text>Bandits are driving me crazy! Don't have enough nerves! They keep coming and coming!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_2"><text>Blow off some steam... Let's relax a little...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_3"><text>I'm not boiling over, just haven't had a normal drink in a while... Pour it, since you offered...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_41"><text>Let's drink to tomorrow, so we can see it!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_42"><text>I'm empty right now, gonna get some loot and buy from the dealers...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_5"><text>Come on! To dying of old age!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_6"><text>There... That helped a bit... What are they saying?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_71"><text>Everyone tries to keep their thoughts to themselves. It's the Zone, brother... But I heard that a couple guys, running from the military, dropped their loot... Was gonna take it myself, but don't think I'll make it there... So if you want, help yourself, otherwise it'll be lost completely - those guys got killed by bandits in another raid the other day. Shame, they were good stalkers, solid buddies...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_73"><text>Everyone tries to keep their thoughts to themselves. It's the Zone, brother... Even friends try not to plan for tomorrow... So they don't jinx it...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_81"><text>Yeah... A lot of good people are gone...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_82"><text>That's for sure! Alright, friend, see you tomorrow...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_0"><text>What was all that shooting about?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_1"><text>We shoot to scare enemies and ourselves...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_2"><text>Let's have two fifty for courage?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_3"><text>Pour it out!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_41"><text>Take two fifty! So we're not the worst off!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_42"><text>Wait a bit, I'll check what's going on here...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_5"><text>Phew! What nasty stuff, but it's strong...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_6"><text>Heh, what did you want, lemonade? What interesting news have you heard?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_71"><text>Bes and his guys killed a ten marauders near the swamp, I went there later... The corpses, of course, were thoroughly torn apart by beasts, quite a sight... I see something glinting in this mess, pulled out a small bottle with a stick, tiny one, souvenir-sized, about fifty grams. Yeah... Seems this bastard swallowed it when things got hot. In this bottle was a piece of paper, with a map and a mark about hidden loot. Here's this map, try to get there, I couldn't...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_73"><text>Yeah, everything's as usual, one died in an anomaly, another got shot, and the third just vanished without a trace... Those are our "interesting" news...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_81"><text>If I can get there, half is yours...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_82"><text>Alright, don't get depressed... See you around.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, mind exchanging a few words?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_1"><text>What's there to chat about? If it was business...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_2"><text>Maybe we'll toast to getting acquainted? Why not?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_3"><text>Got nothing to toast with... If you got some, bring it out, don't just talk...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_31"><text>Don't want to right now. Not feeling it...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_41"><text>Got it, got it! Let's drink to kindred souls!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_42"><text>Sorry, friend, I'm out too...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_5"><text>You talk too much... drinking, like living, should be done quietly...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_6"><text>A philosopher appeared! Well, enlighten me, how should one live...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_71"><text>Everyone lives their own way, and you can't learn someone else's life... There was Lucky Lyovka, heard of him probably? Always bragged about how lucky he was, how women loved him, how all monsters avoided him... Didn't live day by day, always hiding loot, setting up stashes. Couldn't drink with him, couldn't have fun normally, saved artifacts, didn't sell to local dealers, thought he'd dump everything on the mainland and live like cheese in butter... And where is he now? Not even a strand of hair left, completely dissolved in "Fruit Punch". And now other lucky ones are looking for his stashes... But I think there'll be no happiness from that loot, and it's not needed by those who, like me, live only for one day...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_73"><text>Why should I enlighten you... If you have a life path, then you'll walk it, and if not - then you won't get one anyway...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_81"><text>Maybe you're right, but I think: you need to care about tomorrow...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_82"><text>Fate, then... And I believe in humans...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_0"><text>How's it going, friend?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_1"><text>Slowly, a bit depressing, honestly...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_2"><text>Let's have some for mood? Just a little bit?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_3"><text>You bring the bottle, I'll bring everything else...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_31"><text>Nah, get lost...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_41"><text>Agreed! Give me the glasses...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_42"><text>Got everything else, no bottle though...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_5"><text>Good stuff, damn! Burned right through my guts!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_6"><text>Tell me something more interesting...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_71"><text>More interesting? Hmm... What should I make up... Ah! Alright, I'll tell it like it is... You know Yurik? Just a kid, tried to go after loot alongside experienced stalkers. His head's really weak for drinking, steps on a cork and carries on like a bucket... Yesterday he sat here with us, his tongue went like a broom... Got carried away, like he'd wipe everyone's nose, because he knows where loot is hidden. We made fun of him, so he started getting cocky - showing everyone his PDA with a mark on the stash location. Nobody believed him, of course, where would a snot-nose from Cordon get such info... Like there's some loot here... Would you have believed him?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_73"><text>My tongue's getting tangled, I'll tell you something tomorrow...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_81"><text>No, wouldn't have believed... Yurik's quite the bullshitter...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_82"><text>Till tomorrow then, friend...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, how are things with you guys?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_1"><text>It's fun here, you want - go to Bar, you want - chat with the Duty guys or make bets at the arena. Lots of rumors going around - Bar's almost in the center of the Zone...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_2"><text>Maybe we'll have a shot glass each? To getting acquainted...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_3"><text>Not bad either... Come on pour it, I'll take you to the arena after, tickle our nerves...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_41"><text>Come on, for spirit!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_42"><text>I'll run to "100 Roentgen" for a bottle and back... Wait!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_5"><text>Well come on...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_6"><text>What rumors are going around, what interesting stuff are they saying?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_71"><text>Lots of things... Seems there's a teleporter straight to the Monolith, though they name no less than a ten different places. A new breed of monsters appeared - they fight with electricity, total chaos... Duty keeps fighting with the Freedomers over the Zone, always hearing: either these guys killed those, or those killed these, but what's to divide? There's enough Zone for everyone... Recently caught a Freedomer and led him to their basement for re-education, psychiatrists too... So that Freedomer threw something into the bushes, I went later, found his PDA, and it had stash coordinates. Here. Let's look together, what's there? It should be around here somewhere...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_73"><text>Come by the Bar in the evening, our guys will gather, we'll chat... You can hear lots of useful stuff, just don't forget to bring drinks...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_81"><text>Too far, I'm going in the other direction for now...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_82"><text>Alright, I'll come...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, old man. How's life?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_1"><text>Hitting like a wrench... In the head... what do you need?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_2"><text>Why are you so angry! Let's have some for mood?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_3"><text>Had enough of everything! Roll it out...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_41"><text>Alright! Spit on everything... Let's go!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_42"><text>I'd rather get lost...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_5"><text>Well come on... At least they haven't forgotten how to make vodka yet...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_6"><text>Yeah, pure as a komsomol's tear... What's bugging you?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_71"><text>Just bastards all around... You do good for people, and they smear you with shit. I found one stash, thought to get there with one bastard together, so there'd be someone to cover my back. So this infection slipped away quietly, even managed to gut my backpack... Ugh... People... Bastards! Maybe you can beat him there? Here's this stash...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_73"><text>Enough freaks starting with M, can't trust anyone... Always trying to pull some dirty trick...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_81"><text>I'll try, if I can. I'll try to restore your faith in people.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_82"><text>You're angry, I'm getting away from you...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, brother, haven't we met before?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_1"><text>Yeah, your face was flashing around, seems like, what's your name?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_2"><text>Call me Marked One, everyone calls me that...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_3"><text>Alright, Marked One, so Marked One, well let's drink to getting acquainted? Got some with you?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_31"><text>Well alright, Marked One. Would've had some for getting acquainted, but not feeling it right now...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_41"><text>You bet! Here! Strong as a monk's mother...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_42"><text>No, don't have any... Had to give away all my supply for ammo...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_5"><text>Ha! True! Strong! Well then, brother Marked One, now there's two more good people in the Zone...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_6"><text>They say you can find loot nearby, haven't heard?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_71"><text>Well, since you're a good person, and good people should help each other, I'll tell you like a confession, Marked One... Zombies lately started wandering right here very often, and here's the puzzle - all approaches to the base are blocked by Duty guys, even a mouse couldn't get through, but these still appear. They mumble something, stretch their hands... Creepy! Yesterday night I was having a cultural rest - Barkeep the bastard won't pour on credit anymore, what a cheapskate, eh? So anyway, I dozed off, I feel a stench and heaviness pressed down, I open my eyes - there he is, the walking corpse. I was completely paralyzed, couldn't move hand or foot... Not from fear, of course, just from surprise... And the corpse says something nasally, listened closer, numbers it seems, again and again the same thing. I closed my eyes, opened them - nobody there... Only the stench remained. And the numbers kept ringing in my head, looked later - seems like coordinates. But far from here... That's the story, brother...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_73"><text>All the loot that was in easy places got cleaned out completely... Need to push toward the Zone center, they say it's a Klondike there...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_81"><text>Seems the vodka was bootleg, where'd you get it?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_82"><text>A Klondike, you say? Well, well...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_0"><text>Why so cheerless, friend?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_1"><text>Just thinking, need to get out of the Zone... Each day gets worse and worse. Monsters get more dangerous and angrier, weather's shit, anomalies you can't tell where, and worst of all - people are turning into beasts...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_2"><text>Alright, forget it! Let's better have a drink...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_3"><text>Well come on, got something?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_41"><text>Wouldn't offer if I didn't have any...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_42"><text>Damn devil! There was another bottle! Someone stole it!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_5"><text>Eh-h-h, not Chardonnay, of course, but not bad either!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_6"><text>Why don't you go after loot?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_71"><text>It's a long story... You in a hurry? Seryoga Earless and I were friends, always went on deep raids together... Sometimes we'd get all the way to the "Brain Scorcher", saw those phantoms and more... \nPour a bit more... Yeah, Seryoga... His ear got shot off in Chechnya, that's where the nickname came from. How many times we covered each other's backs... On the last trip we ran into a pseudogiant, not particularly dangerous creature, if you don't rush at it like an idiot. But it happened that this beast slammed its paw on the ground, Seryoga got thrown, well, probably no more than half a meter, right into "Fruit Punch", with his whole body... Face, hands... everything. Meat flowed like jelly from his skull... And he was conscious... Pour some, my soul burns... I left him there. And left my soul there too. We had a stash, I won't take it, don't want to... If you find it, remember Seryoga...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_73"><text>I can't... The Zone broke me... Another day or two and I'll go try to get out...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_81"><text>I'll remember...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_82"><text>Right... Probably...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_0"><text>Hello, let's talk?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_1"><text>Hello, why not? You, I see, aren't one of those shitheads...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_2"><text>No, not one of them... Let's have a hundred grams each?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_3"><text>Well... Not bad... Pour it...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_41"><text>Well, let's drink to getting acquainted...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_42"><text>Eh, ran out, dear one...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_5"><text>To getting acquainted... Phew, where'd you get this... Pure nastiness...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_6"><text>Yeah, not Smirnoff! What's the word in the Zone?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_71"><text>Well, heard something... Seems there are rich stashes, left by dead stalkers. There are secret clan stashes, but nobody said they found one. A PDA completely by chance came into my hands, marking a stash location, I can share with you... I probably won't make it there myself...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_73"><text>Come by the Bar in the evening, our guys will gather, we'll chat... You can hear lots of useful stuff, just don't forget to bring drinks...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_81"><text>Thanks, if I'm in those parts, I'll check...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_82"><text>Alright, I'll come...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, old man. How's life?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_1"><text>Hitting like a wrench... In the head... what do you need?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_2"><text>Why are you so angry! Let's have some for mood?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_3"><text>Had enough of everything! Roll it out...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_41"><text>Alright! Spit on everything... Let's go!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_42"><text>I'd rather get lost...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_5"><text>Well come on... At least they haven't forgotten how to make vodka yet...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_6"><text>Yeah, pure as a komsomol's tear... What's bugging you?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_71"><text>Just bastards all around... You do good for people, and they smear you with shit. I found one stash, thought to get there with one bastard together, so there'd be someone to cover my back. So this infection slipped away quietly, even managed to gut my backpack... Ugh... People... Bastards! Maybe you can beat him there? Here's this stash...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_73"><text>Enough freaks starting with M, can't trust anyone... Always trying to pull some dirty trick...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_81"><text>I'll try, if I can, I'll try to restore your faith in people.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_82"><text>You're angry, I'm getting away from you...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, brother, haven't we met before?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_1"><text>Yeah, your face was flashing around, seems like, what's your name?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_2"><text>Call me Marked One, everyone calls me that...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_3"><text>Alright, Marked One so Marked One, well, let's drink to getting acquainted? Got some with you?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_31"><text>Well alright, Marked One. Would've had some for getting acquainted, but not feeling it right now...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_41"><text>You bet! Here! Strong as a monk's mother...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_42"><text>No, don't have any... Had to give away all my supply for ammo...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_5"><text>Ha! True! Strong! Well then, brother Marked One, now there's two more good people in the Zone...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_6"><text>They say you can find loot nearby, haven't heard?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_71"><text>Recently I wandered to Yantar, to see what the eggheads dug in there... Didn't go far, brain's not government-issued... Saw those poor souls there - zombified stalkers. They shoot like Voroshilov marksmen though! How do they manage? Brain doesn't work, does it? No? One of them was dying, I tried to search him - so, dear mother! Some nastiness sprayed out of him, almost kicked the bucket, got poisoned... Anyway, he had a map with a stash mark... But I won't risk going there, but I can share with you.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_73"><text>All the loot that was in easy places got cleaned out completely... Need to push toward the Zone center, they say it's a Klondike there...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_81"><text>Alright, I'll risk it!..</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_82"><text>A Klondike, you say? Well, well...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_0"><text>Why so cheerless, friend?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_1"><text>Just thinking, need to get out of the Zone... Each day gets worse and worse. Monsters get more dangerous and angrier, weather's shit, anomalies you can't tell where, and worst of all - people are turning into beasts...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_2"><text>Alright, forget it! Let's better have a drink...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_3"><text>Well come on, got something?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_41"><text>Wouldn't offer if I didn't have any...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_42"><text>Damn devil! There was another bottle! Someone stole it!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_5"><text>Eh-h-h, not Chardonnay, of course, but not bad either!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_6"><text>Why don't you go after loot?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_71"><text>It's a long story... You in a hurry? Seryoga Earless and I were friends, always went on deep raids together... Sometimes we'd get all the way to the "Brain Scorcher", saw those phantoms and more... \nPour a bit more... Yeah, Seryoga... His ear got shot off in Chechnya, that's where the nickname came from. How many times we covered each other's backs... On the last trip we ran into a pseudogiant, not particularly dangerous creature, if you don't rush at it like an idiot. But it happened that this beast slammed its paw on the ground, Seryoga got thrown, well, probably no more than half a meter, right into "Fruit Punch", with his whole body... Face, hands... everything. Meat flowed like jelly from his skull... And he was conscious... Pour some, my soul burns... I left him there. And left my soul there too. We had a stash, I won't take it, don't want to... If you find it, remember Seryoga...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_73"><text>I can't... The Zone broke me... Another day or two and I'll go try to get out...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_81"><text>I'll remember...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_82"><text>Right... Probably...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, little brother? How's it going?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_1"><text>Couldn't be better... Recently they brought us such good stuff, was in another world for 3 days... Shame it ran out...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_2">
<text>Well... Yeah... That's bad, of course. Maybe a shot glass each?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_3"><text>What kind of question is that?! Got some?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_41"><text>Always got some for such occasions!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_42"><text>That's the thing, don't have any.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_5"><text>Eh, it fell through, didn't notice...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_6"><text>You heard, some stalker came to Bar the other day... They say he cleaned out some big shot mercenary's stash. He was happy, told everyone how he picked up this mercenary's PDA somewhere here, at the Warehouses... Next day he disappeared somewhere, and nobody's seen him since, seems the mercenaries got him... That's how it is.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_71"><text>Yeah, that's all bullshit... We scare those mercenaries like cockroaches. We organized a raid on Duty's base, it was a terrible war, but we couldn't break through - an emission hit, a powerful one... brains just boiled over, I hid behind a Duty corpse, spotted a PDA, so I grabbed it... Had to escape to Wild Territory... Holed up in some garage, waited out the emission... Returned to base, I investigated this PDA and saw a mark on the map right here, didn't have time to check, so here, take it...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_73"><text>Damn him. Shouldn't have shown off, might have lived longer. I'm getting sleepy... Come again! We'll chat about this and that...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_81"><text>Yeah, I'll check it out sometime, thanks. See you soon...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_82"><text>I'll come by, of course, no question.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, friend! How's life?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_1"><text>Kind of weird, nobody wants to join our ranks... Maybe you'll sign up with us? Life will be more peaceful...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_2">
<text>Well, I'm just thinking about that... Maybe we'll skip a bottle for getting acquainted?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_3"><text>Eh, if only there were more generous people like you... I've got just the thing - half a kilo of sausage saved for such occasions. Bring out the elixir!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_41"><text>There, real Ukrainian... "Cossacks". Hold the shot glass!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_42"><text>I was ju-ust about to go to Screw, now, if he's got any left, I'll grab some...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_5"><text>Brrr... My liver won't be happy... That's an A+ for your personal file!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_6"><text>Well then, buddy? Hic... What's go-oing on with you guys generally?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_71"><text>Well, recently Lukash asked me to run to the Barrier... Said they had some trouble there... So I took these monkeys sitting by the fire, see? Well, and to the Barrier... And there - massive zombie attack! About 50 of them, probably... Only lost the sniper, though I thought we'd all die. Well, zombified ones are tough bastards, so like it or not, you gotta finish them off... I approach one, and he's mumbling some numbers, repeated them several times, so I "helped" the poor guy. When I returned, it dawned on me that these numbers are coordinates, but coordinates to what? Right here...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_73"><text>What can happen here? Recently they brought plan - awesome! If you want to get some, ask Bootlegger, he knows where to get it. Come again, we'll chat...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_81"><text>Yeah, these zombies constantly mumble something. Don't pay attention.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_82"><text>Well, see you! I gotta go.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_0"><text>Greetings, guys! Can I join you?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_1"><text>Hello there, Marked One! Come on, move over guys, make room for the VIP!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_2"><text>Thanks for the hospitality. Maybe a shot glass each?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_3"><text>Now that's what I understand! There's kebab cooking just for such occasions! So, where's "the stuff"?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_41"><text>"The stuff" is always with me! Here!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_42"><text>Where did I put it?.. Anyway, lost it somewhere. Now, I'll run to Bootlegger...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_5"><text>Brrr... Where'd you get this stuff? Tell me the spot - I'll always buy there!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_6"><text>Yeah... Don't say, the best I've ever drunk! I found it in a stash, not far from here...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_71"><text>Listen, maybe our Cook stashed it for a rainy day? Was drinking with him once, so he let slip that he unloads right there. He's our taster! Maybe you'll run there? There'll be a continuation of the banquet!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_73"><text>Shame, otherwise I'd buy it by the crate, excellent vodka! Well, if there's more - come by! I'm going to sleep.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_81"><text>Yeah... Cook's probably the Zone champion in liter-throwing... Well, see you...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_82"><text>Of course I'll come... well, good luck!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_0"><text>Hey there! Why are you moping? Why so upset?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_1"><text>Hey there, Marked One. What's not to mope about? No artifacts, no women, no vodka...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_2"><text>Can't argue with that... I had half a liter lying around somewhere...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_3"><text>Why were you keeping quiet then? Get over here, open your backpack. I've got a couple glasses here.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_41"><text>Where did I put it? Ah, here it is - at the very bottom! Let's drink to women and artifacts!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_42"><text>Where is... where did I put it? Wait here a couple minutes, I'll run to one address, there'll be something to fix our health with.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_5"><text>Not bad arsenal you got there... Better than ours... Small glasses. Well, let's drink to the beautiful sex!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_6"><text>Let's drink!... Ooh, that went down well! What's the word?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_71"><text>Well, recently they sent a group, me included, to Dark Valley, to scout a passage there directly from the Warehouses, you understand, we're like in a cage here - Duty on one side, Brain Scorcher on the other. It was in the evening. So anyway, we observed this picture: faster than a bullet runs a bandit... well, we're confused. Apparently he spotted us and changed vector toward us, our jaws dropped, thinking, what kind of Rambo? Then our eagle-eyed Roman says: "He's not running alone there", well he had a thermal scope. We looked closer, and indeed... behind him the air seemed distorted. He ran another 20 meters closer, then we realized things were bad - 4 bloodsuckers behind him! Had to put down everyone, including the thug. Seems like some lackey. Found a spot on the map in the PDA, right here, no comments. The poor bandit's jeans were all brown - he shit himself. Anyone would've crapped themselves with fear in his place.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_73"><text>Constantly hearing screams somewhere nearby. Real creepy. But essentially, I'm not really up to speed on what's happening here.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_81"><text>Yeah, unlucky guy. Well then, let's have one for the road, and I'm off.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_82"><text>Well then, one for the road, and off to sleep, I'm tired today...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, guys!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_1"><text>Don't yell like that, this is a creepy place... doesn't like disrespect. Don't loom there, sit down. What did you want?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_2"><text>Was thinking of having a drink with the guys...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_3"><text>Well, that's just what we need, we're freezing here. Bring out the dear one.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_41"><text>Here, take it.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_42"><text>Well, guys, I thought you'd treat me. Alright, I'll run to base, grab a bottle.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_5"><text>Respect, didn't let us die from cold... And we're sitting here waiting for the guys, waiting... they went to the village to clear out a bloodsucker den... seems we won't see them again. Shame about the boys... yeah.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_6"><text>Yeah, the hair on my ass is standing on end. Even vodka doesn't help. What else is happening here?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_71"><text>Ooh, you touched on a sacred topic. So many legends about this place. Before the 2006 emission this village was like the rookie village at Cordon, and my brother lived there. Everyone lived quietly, peacefully... Suddenly an emission hit with such force that far from everyone managed to survive... screams... waves of mutants poured from the Barrier side, one after another. The emission lasted about 10-15 minutes, but felt like 3 hours, many lost their friends then, next day they sent us to collect the corpses and bury them, but we would've done it without orders. I found my brother, you understand, my own brother, he was lying in the basement, painful to look at. I took his gun, see how it shines, and his PDA. In the PDA I found the only mark on the map, right here, and also a note addressed to me, but that's personal.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_73"><text>Lots happens here... Generally, come here less often - you got the whole Zone menagerie here. There's bloodsuckers, burers, controllers, dogs, even chimeras sometimes drop by...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_81"><text>Yeah, I sympathize, sorry. Well, let's have one for the road, I've got tons of things to do.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_82"><text>Thanks for the advice, but we'll see each other again somehow.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_0"><text>Hey there, guy. Got something to eat?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_1"><text>Got some, why?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_2"><text>Got something to drink?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_3"><text>What's not there, isn't there.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_41"><text>Well see? What would we do without each other? Already set up the spot... hold the glass! What shall we drink to?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_42"><text>Shame, I don't have any either.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_5"><text>Efficiently done. Let's drink to always having people like you, and that they always find people like me! Well, come on! Ooh, bitter, damn!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_6"><text>Don't say... It burns! Maybe you know something that I don't, eh?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_71"><text>Well, brother, you probably roamed the whole Zone yourself... No? Do you know anything about the Dead City? No? That's the main mercenary base. They captured me about half a year ago. Well, everything by the rules of the killer business - bag over the head, rifle butt to the skull and drove me in an unknown direction... They brought me, started squeezing out of me how to get to our base quietly... well I naturally didn't say a word to them. Left me for the night in a cage. Two more guys were across from me. One, by the way, looked a lot like you... we chatted about how to slip away from there. I noticed a Zone map there... some dots, could only remember one: seemed to be right here... then they dragged me out and hit me in the head with a rifle butt, came to already in the car, with a hood over my head. They dragged me out, put me on the edge of a cliff, said, like, last wish... and then, to my luck, an emission... Had to jump. Turned out to be some swamp, in the middle of the swamp - a trailer, waited out the emission in it. Turned out they brought me to Agroprom... barely made it home. Told everyone - they didn't believe me, because I was very drunk, you understand, surviving something like that...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_73"><text>Oh, where would I go? I've been here all day, they only put me here a week ago, so I haven't seen anything interesting. Come back later, maybe I'll find out something.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_81"><text>Interesting, it's a miracle you stayed alive. Well, bye.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_82"><text>Well alright, I'll drop by sometime. See you.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_0"><text>Why so pale?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_1"><text>It's so cold...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_2"><text>Why don't you warm up?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_3"><text>Would be nice to have something...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling it today...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_91"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_41"><text>I'll help you with that! Here! What are we drinking to?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_42"><text>And I'm freezing here... Thought someone would warm me up.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_5"><text>Let's drink so there's something to drink tomorrow! Ooh, strong. Here, chase it with sausage right away.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_6"><text>Yeah, thanks. Listen, where can you get rich with loot around here?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_71"><text>Well, everyone's got problems with that now. They say there's loot beyond the barrier, but going there is dangerous. Found out from my own experience - had no money, owed a lot to many people, so fate forced me to move beyond the Barrier. I'm walking... silence all around... I see something moving ahead, so I duck behind a rock. Stumbled, found myself face to face with an old acquaintance of mine, he'd been missing for a long time, but now he was half-decomposed, makes me want to puke when I remember. Well he was an authoritative stalker, managed to get rich with "Val". I took the backpack off him, why would he need it, I thought? Just lifted it up, I see monolith guys talking to moaning ones... Telling them like: "In the name of the Monolith...", ugh, so I quickly moved in the opposite direction... and literally half an hour later we were fighting off about fifty zombies. That's how it was. Found a couple stashes in the PDA, here and here. This one I cleaned out on the way, but too lazy to go to the other, plus I was loaded to the max, and I'd never been in those parts...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_73"><text>They say at Agroprom there used to be mountains of artifacts, now I don't know... Alright, Marked One, if anything, drop by.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_81"><text>You were lucky. I advise not doing that again. Alright, don't sleep - you'll freeze. See you.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_82"><text>Well alright, I'll drop by sometime.</text></string>
