<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="paper_box_name"><text>Cardboard Box</text></string>
<string id="paper_box_desc"><text>A cardboard box with supplies. Heavy and cumbersome.</text></string>
<string id="paper_box_green_name"><text>Cardboard Box for Petrenko</text></string>
<string id="paper_box_green_desc"><text>A cardboard box filled with sausage. Heavy and cumbersome.</text></string>
<string id="box_kulinar_name"><text>Cardboard Box</text></string>
<string id="box_kulinar_desc"><text>A cardboard box containing something unusual.</text></string>
<string id="zub_lampa_name"><text>Cardboard Box</text></string>
<string id="zub_lampa_desc"><text>A cardboard box with a part for a scanner.</text></string>
<string id="borzyi_to_borov_package_name"><text>Cardboard Box</text></string>
<string id="borzyi_to_borov_package_desc"><text>A package from Borzyi, intended for the Bandit leader Borov.</text></string>
<string id="box_conserv_name"><text>Crate of Canned Food</text></string>
<string id="box_conserv_desc"><text>A crate stuffed to the brim with canned goods. It would last one person a long time! But the others need to eat too...</text></string>
<string id="bochonok_vine_name"><text>Small Keg</text></string>
<string id="bochonok_vine_desc"><text>A small keg of good wine. It's small, but the wine is aged—made by special order!</text></string>
<string id="dollars1"><text>A little bit of money</text></string>
<string id="enc_dollars1"><text>A stack of small denomination bills.</text></string>
<string id="dollars3"><text>Thin wad of cash</text></string>
<string id="enc_dollars3"><text>A wad of cash, mostly small bills.</text></string>
<string id="dollars5"><text>Slender stack of cash</text></string>
<string id="enc_dollars5"><text>A stack of cash containing some medium denomination bills.</text></string>
<string id="dollars10"><text>Stack of cash</text></string>
<string id="enc_dollars10"><text>A stack of cash, mostly medium bills.</text></string>
<string id="dollars25"><text>Substantial stack of cash</text></string>
<string id="enc_dollars25"><text>A stack of cash, mostly large bills.</text></string>
<string id="dollars50"><text>Thick wad of cash</text></string>
<string id="enc_dollars50"><text>A thick wad of high-denomination bills.</text></string>
<string id="binocular"><text>Binoculars</text></string>

<string id="komp_flash_in"><text>Insert USB drive</text></string>
<string id="komp_flash_out"><text>Eject USB drive</text></string>
<string id="gun_tools_name"><text>Some sort of gadget, looks like a tool.</text></string>
<string id="gun_tools_desc"><text>Something heavy and mysterious. The Mercenaries were planning to use this thing to seize Monolith weaponry.</text></string>
<string id="ventil_rotate"><text>Open the shut-off valve</text></string>
<string id="gas_ventil_rotate"><text>Shut off the gas supply</text></string>
<string id="bun_switcher_press"><text>Main section power supply</text></string> 
<string id="radar_docs"><text>Documents found at Radar.</text></string> 
<string id="radar_docs_desc"><text>Documents found at Radar in the backpack of a dying scientist. Everything is soaked through; nothing can be made out clearly. Perhaps Sakharov will be interested.</text></string>
<string id="need_harddisc"><text>Retrieve the hard drive</text></string>
<string id="hard_disc"><text>Hard Drive</text></string>
<string id="hard_disc_desc"><text>A disk storage device, commonly known as a hard drive. It is the primary storage for computer information.</text></string>
<string id="foto_lisyi"><text>Photograph</text></string>
<string id="enc_foto_lisyi"><text>A photograph of a group of stalkers.</text></string>
<string id="skryaga_foto"><text>Photograph</text></string>
<string id="enc_skryaga_foto"><text>A photograph of Skinflint with some fat-faced guy. Rumor has it they're brothers.</text></string>
<string id="stalker_letter"><text>Note</text></string>
<string id="enc_stalker_letter"><text>A note from Barman's debtor. It lists the nicknames of some stalkers, likely couriers or intermediaries. There are many abbreviations with numbers next to them, probably referring to goods and prices. Dates and names of locations in the Zone appear throughout, all connected into a complex diagram with many arrows. An outsider has no hope of deciphering this. Better just deliver it to the recipient.</text></string>
<string id="scaintist_docs_name"><text>Documents</text></string>
<string id="scaintist_docs_desc"><text>Judging by the notes, the scientists were transporting a very unusual artifact.</text></string>
<string id="repair_itemoutfit_desc"><text>A prepared repair kit for field maintenance of body armor and other gear.</text></string>
<string id="repair_itemoutfit_feik_desc"><text>A set of consumables for field repair of body armor and other equipment.</text></string>
<string id="repair_itemoutfit_name"><text>RIA Repair Kit</text></string>
<string id="repair_item_weapon_desc"><text>A prepared repair kit for field maintenance of weapons.</text></string>
<string id="repair_item_weapon_feik_desc"><text>A set of consumables for field weapon repair.</text></string>
<string id="repair_item_weapon_name"><text>RIW Repair Kit</text></string>
<string id="repair_box_desc"><text>A box for storing repair kits.</text></string>
<string id="repair_box_name"><text>Toolbox</text></string>
<string id="device_pda1"><text>PDA</text></string>
<string id="enc_equipment_device_pda1"><text>A stalker's individual PDA. A storage for personal information and data essential for survival.</text></string>
<string id="exs_pda"><text>Experimental PDA</text></string>
<string id="enc_equipment_device_pda2"><text>A trial batch of PDAs for military personnel performing operations in underground laboratories.</text></string>
<string id="enc_equipment_device_pda_gg"><text>Marked One's PDA. It's not working.</text></string>
<string id="enc_equipment_device_pda_discharged_gg"><text>Marked One's PDA. Looks like the battery is completely dead.</text></string>
<string id="x18_door3_code"><text>Scientist's Note</text></string>
<string id="x18_door3_code_desc"><text>A note found on a scientist who died in the X-18 underground laboratory. One side contains various scientific gibberish, which nevertheless includes a description of an artifact modification method. On the other side, a code for some electronic lock is written: 26359.</text></string>
<string id="yan_pda_name"><text>PDA found at Yantar</text></string>
<string id="yan_pda_desc"><text>Judging by the accessible logs, the PDA belonged to a scientist... Perhaps Vasilyev?</text></string>
<string id="uncoder"><text>Code-breaking Device</text></string>
<string id="uncoder_desc"><text>A portable decoder that helps determine the cipher for code panels. Unfortunately, it's broken...</text></string>
<string id="personal_things"><text>Deceased's Personal Effects</text></string>
<string id="personal_things_text"><text>A few of a stalker's personal belongings. Trinkets, mostly: a couple of photos, a notebook, an old pocket knife, and other bits and pieces in the same vein...</text></string>
<string id="kulinar_voron_box"><text>Small Packet</text></string>
<string id="kulinar_voron_box_desc"><text>A small bag of herbs. It doesn't weigh much and has a faint smell. It might be good for your health, or it might not...</text></string>
<string id="boryan_kul"><text>Packet of Dried Herbs</text></string>
<string id="boryan_kul_desc"><text>A small bag of herbs. It doesn't weigh much and has a faint smell. It might be good for your health, or it might not...</text></string>
<string id="amk_ruksak"><text>Small Backpack</text></string>
<string id="amk_ruksak_s"><text>Small Backpack</text></string>
<string id="enc_amk_ruksak"><text>A small hiking backpack. Made of rubberized fabric, so it's waterproof. You can store valuable items in a secluded spot—it makes for an excellent stash.</text></string>
<string id="video_casset_name"><text>Video Cassette</text></string>
<string id="video_casset_desc"><text>A magnetic tape video cassette. Contains recordings of adult entertainment shows.</text></string>
<string id="scarman_pda_name"><text>PDA</text></string>
<string id="scarman_pda_desc"><text>The PDA of a stalker with a scar. Might have something valuable, but... it's just gibberish \n .njkmrjljwtyncltkftnnt,zcxfcnkbdsv/rfrnjnfr).</text></string>
<string id="fraer_pda_name"><text>PDA</text></string>
<string id="fraer_pda_desc"><text>Fraer's PDA. Might have something valuable, but...</text></string>
<string id="freedoms_pda_name"><text>PDA</text></string>
<string id="freedoms_pda_desc"><text>Skull handed over a Freedomer's trophy PDA. Might have something valuable, but...</text></string>
<string id="bes_pda_name"><text>PDA</text></string>
<string id="bes_pda_desc"><text>Bes gave this away while drunk. Might have something valuable, but...</text></string>
<string id="mil_kurjer_pda_name"><text>PDA</text></string>
<string id="mil_kurjer_pda_desc"><text>Found on a mauled stalker in the village near the Freedom base at the former Army Warehouses. It might contain some information, but at first glance, there's nothing special.</text></string>
<string id="solt_bag"><text>Sack of Salt</text></string>
<string id="solt_bag_desc"><text>Salt in a sack; looks like it's been sitting for a long time, it's turned to stone.</text></string>
<string id="redcatcher_albom"><text>Demob Album</text></string>
<string id="redcatcher_albom_desc"><text>A genuine demobilization album. Inside are photographs of soldiers, military hardware, pages with army poems, and other demob memorabilia. There are a couple of documents on high-quality letterheads from some research organization. And a scrap of a topographic map...</text></string>
<string id="agr_black_box"><text>Aviation "Black Box"</text></string>
<string id="agr_black_box_desc"><text>Every modern aircraft is equipped with technical means of objective control. Usually, this consists of a flight data recorder (FDR), which captures and saves flight info, and a cockpit voice recorder (CVR) that records crew conversations. It serves not to keep secrets, but specifically to reveal them.</text></string>
<string id="neum_drags"><text>Jar of Medicine</text></string>
<string id="neum_drags_desc"><text>The Doctor mixed up some kind of junk. The stench is awful; it's better not to open the jar.</text></string>
<string id="cherep_decoder_name"><text>Mysterious Device</text></string>
<string id="cherep_decoder_desc"><text>A Duty member nicknamed Skull took this device from a stalker. He didn't say what it's for or how it works...</text></string>
<string id="item_pda_lucky_name"><text>PDA, slightly dented</text></string>
<string id="item_pda_lucky_desc"><text>A PDA found in the jaws of a mutant. It's dented, and someone scratched "BOROV'S!" into the back of the casing.\nThe irony of the Zone: a "Borov" (Boar) PDA found on a boar...</text></string>
<string id="x18_order_code"><text>Order on Security Measures</text></string>
<string id="enc_x18_order_code"><text>A paper detailing an order for increased security measures and the access code for the X-18 lab control center. The entry code on the day the guard died was 13698.</text></string>
<string id="x18_botan_book"><text>Small Notebook</text></string>
<string id="enc_x18_botan_book"><text>A notebook in which one of the scientists in the X-18 underground laboratory described his impressions...</text></string>
<string id="x8_botan_book"><text>Paper with a Diagram</text></string>
<string id="enc_x8_botan_book"><text>A page torn from a notebook. Looks like an emergency exit diagram... It mentions a tunnel with an entrance code of 658956. The return access code is 84627...</text></string> 
<string id="mixture"><text>Mixture</text></string>
<string id="mixture_desc"><text>A bottle containing a mixture of unknown composition, found in the Sanatorium following a tip from Vergas. All labels on the bottle are in hieroglyphs.</text></string>
<string id="mil_rjaboi_letter"><text>Sort of a Repentance</text></string>
<string id="mil_rjaboi_letter_desc"><text>So this crap happened... The Zone sees everything. How you act is how it'll treat you.\nRyaby and I had been partners for a long time. Some guy tried to stick with us—we brushed him off. We believed you shouldn't tempt fate. Ryaby could sense anomalies from twenty meters away, and I could drop any mutant in a heartbeat. Had to happen like this. I thought, just a couple more raids and that's it, home. To Ryabinsk...\nThat time we managed to reach the City Center. Took a decent haul. It's just a shame we couldn't get the legendary Compass, even though the tip was solid... That art allows you to use tunnels to reach any place in the Zone. Traders would pay so much for it you could clear out across the border immediately... and then spend the rest of your life lounging on the Canaries. But what's the point now...\nWe were returning through the reserve, the Red Forest. To stay out of sight. And then, I see Ryaby looking at me... wrong. And I realized, he wants to grab it all for himself. Or maybe I just imagined it. We'd been "treating" ourselves heavily for radiation back then. Well, anyway... I drop any mutant in a heartbeat... What could he do against me... He didn't have time... I was first.\nOnly now. I've paid. Took one step back. And fell right in. A Springboard. Better if I'd died there... But I crawled out. How? I don't remember. That's all...\n\nLet all the evil that was pass away. Your life is ending and THERE you will be happy, for you realized what makes a human a human. Though the man never gave his name, it doesn't matter. THERE everyone is equal.\n\nAmen.</text></string>
<string id="im_chain"><text>Instruction Manual</text></string>
<string id="im_chain_desc"><text>A thin sheet of rice paper covered entirely in handwritten hieroglyphs. Found in the Sanatorium next to what is presumably an experimental Chinese mixture for treating memory loss. Most likely, it is the instruction manual for that very mixture.</text></string>
<string id="resiept_activ_anom"><text>Crumpled Paper</text></string>
<string id="resiept_activ_anom_desc"><text>This describes the method of transforming a Sparkler artifact into a Snowball artifact, and explains how the latter can be used to create an anomaly.\nBelow is a barely legible text, clearly written by a different hand:\nStrength is fading... hunger is overwhelming, but the thirst is gone... I'm trapped... I knew it, I felt something was wrong when I signed up for this job... Couldn't he go himself?! I fell for the loot... Had a strange feeling, like someone was trailing me the whole way to the adit... reached the spot, still amazed at how easy the path was... as if some unknown helpers had already cleared out all the mutants... And I found the promised reward quickly... a "Clear Sky" suit, there was a faction like that in the Zone once... Papers... collected everything and headed for the exit... Then I hear something starting to howl, like a draft... thought the wind picked up... If only... a "Whirligig" right at the entrance, dead center... So powerful there's no way to squeeze through... This isn't a coincidence... the Zone can't just toss something like this. Bad luck happens, but not like this... Someone was waiting for me... even found the artifact transformation recipe among the papers... it talks exactly about creating such an anomaly... I'd bet a hundred to one that the guy with the white eyes had something to do with it.</text></string>
<string id="bearer_cheque"><text>Cheque</text></string>
<string id="bearer_cheque_desc"><text>A bearer's bank cheque. Face value—one thousand dollars.</text></string>
<string id="scanner_anomaly"><text>Anomalous Activity Scanner</text></string>
<string id="scanner_anomaly_desc"><text>A device new to the Zone's conditions. Developed by Western intelligence agencies to detect and predict anomalous activity. Requires installation at specific locations to link into a unified information network. It is unknown whether it will function or to what extent it can identify anomalies.</text></string>
<string id="scanner_artefact"><text>Physical Process Recorder</text></string>
<string id="scanner_artefact_desc"><text>A recording device. It accumulates parameters in its memory that change under the influence of the spatial continuum during an emission.</text></string>
<string id="aver_monolith_scanner_name"><text>Psi-Field Recorder</text></string>
<string id="aver_monolith_scanner_desc"><text>This device captures and analyzes the psionic component of most types of background radiation in open areas. It can transmit the received data via satellite in real-time.</text></string>
<string id="memory_module"><text>EPROM Unit 12-X-14TO</text></string>
<string id="memory_module_desc"><text>An electronic component of the harmonizer-setter unit for wave variable processes. It is specially tuned depending on the required shape, frequency, and other radiation parameters. This component is marked 12-X-14TO.</text></string>
<string id="news_read"><text>Read</text></string>
<string id="enter_to"><text>Enter</text></string>
<string id="marsh_zapiska"><text>Documents from the CS Base</text></string>
<string id="banka"><text>Three-Liter Jar</text></string>
<string id="enc_banka"><text>A three-liter container made of special crystal. Used for storing the substance of the Fruit Punch anomaly.</text></string>
<string id="enc_kanistra"><text>An ordinary empty 20-liter canister for flammable substances.</text></string>
<string id="banka_full"><text>Jar of "Fruit Punch"</text></string>
<string id="enc_banka_full"><text>The substance of the "Fruit Punch" anomaly in a three-liter jar.</text></string>
<string id="upir_quest_banka_name_desc"><text>The substance of the Fruit Punch anomaly in a three-liter jar. A gold crown can be seen on top, all that remains of a stalker nicknamed Valerka Shkilet.</text></string>
<string id="acid_banka"><text>Jar of Acid</text></string>
<string id="enc_acid_banka"><text>Concentrated sulfuric acid in a three-liter jar.</text></string>
<string id="flesh_shkura"><text>Flesh Hide</text></string>
<string id="flesh_shkura_desc"><text>A hide from a Flesh, practically fresh. It stinks terribly.</text></string>
<string id="flesh_leather"><text>Cured Leather</text></string>
<string id="flesh_leather_desc"><text>Processed Flesh skin. Material used for making various items, primarily specialized clothing.</text></string>

<string id="doc_blood"><text>Folder with papers</text></string>
<string id="enc_doc_blood"><text>A falling-apart document folder. Smeared with dirt, blood, and something that smells unpleasant. It might be possible to read something, but... who needs it?</text></string>

<string id="docs_for_borov"><text>Lukash's Documents</text></string>
<string id="enc_docs_for_borov"><text>Lukash has drawn up some plans for actions against Duty. These documents are full of nothing but rows of numbers. It's completely incomprehensible.</text></string>
<string id="letter_for_borov"><text>Letter to Borov</text></string>
<string id="enc_letter_for_borov"><text>A note from a certain friend of Borov.</text></string>
<string id="drunk_dolg_letter"><text>Paper with scribbles</text></string>
<string id="drunk_dolg_letter_desc"><text>Among the scribbling, one can decipher a recipe for transforming a "Battery" artifact into "Electra's Tears."</text></string>
<string id="enc_drunk_dolg_letter"><text>It seems to describe an artifact transformation recipe.</text></string>
<string id="drunk_dolg_letter2"><text>Note to Vakhtang</text></string>
<string id="enc_drunk_dolg_letter2"><text>A former Duty member scratched some scribbles and asks to hand the paper to Vakhtang.</text></string>
<string id="red_shtreck_letter"><text>Note found in the adit, Red Forest</text></string>
<string id="red_shtreck_letter_desc"><text>I. We probably won't meet again, and I never got to thank you for the information. Thank you. That guy from the Warehouses really is one of them, but even he won't be able to help me. He doesn't have any shard. And I never could find the Black Mark; maybe you were right about me. There's no time left anyway, I'll try to break through as is. Farewell. S. \n ps Please, not a word to P. if you meet him.</text></string>
<string id="marsh_cs_sklad_letter"><text>Report on subject "Strelok"</text></string>
<string id="marsh_cs_sklad_letter_desc"><text>To the Head of the Clear Sky group, Colonel Lebedev. \nAs a result of planned measures to detect and localize the target subject, information has been obtained regarding periodic activity in the Red Forest sector. \nLocal sources have noted frequent appearances of subjects Fang and Ghost in the northern area of the Limansk Reserve basin. Presumably, the lair of the target group may be located in one of the underground formations of this district. I suggest utilizing one of the stalkers as a tool to achieve the operation's goals... Sergeant Major Predybaylo recommends establishing contact with the so-called "mercenary Scar." \nMonitoring Group Commander \nCaptain Dyba.</text></string>
<string id="aver_bandit_letter"><text>From a bandit in the Misty Forest</text></string>
<string id="aver_bandit_letter_desc"><text>Boss. Basically, we struck out here. We were tailing some chumps; according to a tip, they were dragging rich loot from the center. We wanted to whack 'em without a word. But there was some devil with them, they called him either Strelok or Sniper. He caught wind of our ambush and came from behind. He dropped Shnur and Khivrya instantly, they didn't even have time to squeak. Savoska caught a slug in the gut—died while we were leaving. Dead end, in short. Me and Pryanik will watch from a distance for now. Send some brothers for backup. The loot is a sure thing, I swear it.\nKarass</text></string>
<string id="rad_cart"><text>Electronic Map</text></string>
<string id="rad_cart_desc"><text>A memory card used for saving certain data.</text></string>
<string id="letter_for"><text>Note</text></string>
<string id="novice_letter"><text>Sheet with notes</text></string>
<string id="leshyi_letter"><text>Paper with a diagram</text></string>
<string id="leshyi_letter_desc"><text>...Had to ditch the container. \nMemorized the spot, before reaching the pig farm, to the right of the road, near a prominent stump.</text></string>
<string id="postmens_bag"><text>Tattered stack of paper</text></string>
<string id="soldier_letter"><text>Scrap of a Letter</text></string>
<string id="soldier_letter_1_desc"><text>...Father has completely fallen apart. He drinks every single day, took everything out of the house and sold it for booze... Tanyushka can't even go to school, her last pair of shoes fell to pieces. When he gets drunk, he starts looking for a fight. Son, please come back soon, you don't have much service time left. Maybe you can talk some sense into him. I just don't know how to deal with him anymore.</text></string>
<string id="soldier_letter_2_desc"><text>...And Svetka found herself someone else, I saw it myself! I told her that when you get back, you'll knock all that nonsense out of her head, but she says you won't come back at all... What a brat, huh? Mother is waiting for you, she reads a prayer every night, quietly, when she thinks I'm asleep. I wish you'd come back sooner so we could go fishing like we used to...\nWell, take care.\nYour brother, Vovchik.</text></string>
<string id="soldier_letter_3_desc"><text>...Sweetheart, it's so hard without you. All the girls are hanging out in nightclubs, sleeping with whoever, saying we only live once. But I'm waiting for you. I promised. My only consolation is that the day is coming soon when I can hug you, so very tight! And we'll never be apart again!\nUntil we meet, my dear.\nYours, and only yours, Lenochka...</text></string>
<string id="soldier_letter_4_desc"><text>...Mom, I'm doing fine! Even though they only moved me here two weeks ago and the place is supposedly dangerous—the Perimeter of the Exclusion Zone—I actually kind of like it here! Everything is quiet on our side, but inside the Zone you can hear shooting sometimes and strange sounds. But don't worry, Mom, we're safe here. The walls are thick, there are mines and plenty of other stuff. And the pay is good. Tell Svetka that as soon as I get back, we're getting married! Tell Father that...</text></string>
<string id="soldier_letter_5_desc"><text>...Sis, tell Mishka that if he puts even one scratch on my motorcycle, I'm going to rip his head off when I get home! You're the eldest, he has to listen to you. He's always been spoiled as the youngest in the family. But tell him I'm not joking about my steel horse! When you go to the hospital to see Father, tell him not to worry, I'm serving well, he won't have to blush for me! I've already got a whole stack of commendations from the command...</text></string>
<string id="soldier_letter_6_desc"><text>...my precious sunshine! I don't forget you for a single second, I'm constantly thinking about you! You're the most beautiful, the smartest, the absolute best to me! Even though it gets very tough here at times, I feel better immediately just thinking that you're waiting for me!...</text></string>
<string id="soldier_letter_7_desc"><text>...how much longer do you want to serve there? Bro, you can't earn all the money in the world, and that place is dangerous! It's all jokes to you: "Another six months, then another year," renewing the contract over and over, while Mother is drinking valerian by the bucketful every day. What will she care about your money if you don't come back yourself, huh? Use your head, quit sticking it under the radioactive rain!...</text></string>
<string id="soldier_letter_bandit_desc"><text>...and one more thing! Bro, if you squeeze any PDAs out of some chumps—don't throw 'em away, even if they're busted. Wiry is collecting them for some reason... Maybe he's a collector, maybe just a dummy, but he shells out some supplies for those tablets. \nThe boys were saying he pushes them to some foreigner, Kikabidze or someone... I don't remember. \nAnd don't forget our deal...</text></string>
<string id="docs_rad_psy"><text>Data Disc</text></string>
<string id="docs_rad_psy_desc"><text>A disc containing a calculation program and radiation data from the Brain Scorcher area.</text></string>
<string id="docs_2_rad_psy"><text>Printed Data</text></string>
<string id="docs_2_rad_psy_desc"><text>The resulting calculations, printed out and also saved on electronic media.</text></string>
<string id="quest_manycase_mil_kurjer_desc"><text>A case found in an abandoned village near the Army Warehouses. Contains documents inside. Partially encrypted...</text></string>
<string id="item test1"><text>This is a test string for the duffel bag</text></string>
<string id="item test2"><text>This is another test string for the duffel bag</text></string>
<string id="item_case_esc_desc"><text>A case with documents. Made of fireproof material.</text></string>
<string id="same_case_esc_desc"><text>A case with a combination lock. Made of fireproof material; the lock cannot be opened without specialized knowledge without damaging the contents.</text></string>
<string id="item_decoder_desc"><text>Something like a powerful electronic master key. It seems it was created to hack a very specific electronic lock. Curiously, the design is not universal, the decoder was made for one particular lock and is incapable of cracking any other codes.</text></string>
<string id="item_decoder_name"><text>Decoder</text></string>
<string id="rashpil_letter_name"><text>Rashpil's "Malyava"</text></string>
<string id="rashpil_letter_desc"><text>Rashpil scribbled a note for Ivantsov... The text is a bit hard to follow.</text></string>
<string id="borzyi_letter_name"><text>Borzyi's "Malyava"</text></string>
<string id="borzyi_letter_desc"><text>Borzyi scribbled a note for Zub... The text is completely incomprehensible.</text></string>
<string id="item_detector_yantar_desc"><text>A device for measuring psi-radiation.</text></string>
<string id="item_detector_yantar_name"><text>PP-4A Sensor</text></string>
<string id="item_doc_x16_desc"><text>A folder with some documents. It's hard to understand much without a degree in biology.</text></string>
<string id="item_doc_x16_name"><text>Documents from Lab X-16</text></string>
<string id="item_doc_x18_desc"><text>A thick stack of scientific papers. Nothing but terms, formulas, and diagrams.</text></string>
<string id="item_doc_x18p2_name"><text>Documents from Lab X-18, Part 2</text></string>
<string id="item_doc_x18p3_name"><text>Documents from Lab X-18, Part 3</text></string>
<string id="item_doc_x18p4_name"><text>Documents from Lab X-18, Part 4</text></string>
<string id="item_doc_x18p5_name"><text>Documents from Lab X-18, Part 5</text></string>
<string id="item_doc_x10p1_name"><text>X-10 Duty Roster</text></string>
<string id="item_doc_x10p2_name"><text>Project "Rainbow" Documentation</text></string>
<string id="item_doc_x10p1_desc"><text>Orders for organizing duty shifts, guard post records, and lists with equipment inventory numbers.</text></string>
<string id="item_doc_x10p2_desc"><text>Highly specialized information regarding the operation of the primary systems of the so-called "Brain Scorcher." Among other things, it contains schematic plans and a description of the electrical supply network for the lab complex.</text></string>
<string id="item_dynamite_esc_desc"><text>A heavy wooden crate with "Explosive" labels in several languages.</text></string>
<string id="item_dynamite_esc_name"><text>Dynamite Crate</text></string>
<string id="item_flash_eco_rost_desc"><text>Looks like a standard PDA. Won't turn on. It's unclear whether it's functional or not.</text></string>
<string id="item_flash_eco_rost_name"><text>Professor Kruglov's PDA</text></string>
<string id="item_flash_esc_desc"><text>A flash card—a convenient device for transferring information.</text></string>
<string id="item_flash_esc_name"><text>Prisoner's USB Drive</text></string>
<string id="item_flash_gslinger_agro_desc"><text>A flash card—a convenient device for transferring information.</text></string>
<string id="item_flash_gslinger_agro_name"><text>USB Drive with files</text></string>
<string id="psy_scan_data_flash_name"><text>USB Drive with data</text></string>
<string id="psy_scan_data_flash_desc"><text>Contains the results of the psycho-matrix consciousness scan of the stalker known as Marked One.</text></string>
<string id="x12_secret_flash_name"><text>Sakharov's USB Drive</text></string>
<string id="x12_secret_flash_desc"><text>Contains a clever program that, when connected to a computer, should automatically download a specific set of files.</text></string>
<string id="tex_escape_lager_volk_document"><text>\nI need to find a lost document in the underpass beneath the railway at Cordon. They're promising an assault rifle for it.</text></string>
<string id="item_quest_case_02_desc"><text>Briefcase with documents. Inside is a whole pile of papers, maps, and diagrams...</text></string>
<string id="item_quest_case_02_name"><text>Briefcase</text></string>
<string id="item_quest_case_06_desc"><text>A case containing military documents, taken by a deserter when escaping the Agroprom base.</text></string>
<string id="item_quest_case_06_name"><text>Documents from the Military Base</text></string>
<string id="item_quest_sak_plan_name"><text>Bag of "Grass"</text></string>
<string id="item_quest_sak_plan_desc"><text>High-quality "Cannabis Afgani" packed in a waterproof bag.</text></string>
<string id="val_escort_captive_name"><text>Max Luber</text></string>
<string id="sak_resiver_name"><text>Military Radio Station</text></string>
<string id="sak_resiver_desc"><text>A standard military VHF radio, but in the active conditions of the Zone, its outdated vacuum tube design has proven to be the most resistant to various types of radiation.</text></string>
<string id="sak_resiver_yantar_name"><text>Monitoring Unit</text></string>
<string id="sak_resiver_yantar_desc"><text>A device built into a standard military VHF radio. It is a modern system for monitoring the active manifestations of the Zone's disturbances. This design allows for remote monitoring and, in some cases, provides more accurate tuning for the teleportation process.</text></string>
<string id="sak_document_desc"><text>Near the Brain Scorcher, I found several bodies in scientific suits. One of them had what looks like scientific data, notes, hints. Diagrams... Formulas. Scraps of correspondence, photographs. It describes an artifact transformation recipe. There's a bit of everything here... Stalker nicknames pop up, among them, "Ghost reported that he knows how to reach the center while avoiding surface dangers..."</text></string>
<string id="war_document_desc"><text>Scattered documents, orders, notes. There might be something useful in all these papers...</text></string>
<string id="x18_document_desc"><text>Some papers found in X-18.</text></string>
<string id="war_document_name"><text>Papers and Documents</text></string>
<string id="sak_document_name"><text>Papers and Documents</text></string>
<string id="item_rad_document6_desc"><text>Scattered documents, orders, notes. There might be something useful in all these papers...</text></string>
<string id="item_rad_document6_name"><text>Document Folder</text></string>
<string id="item_rad_document7_desc"><text>An order to conduct a special operation in the underground facilities beneath the Agroprom Research Institute.</text></string>
<string id="item_rad_document7_name"><text>Military Order</text></string>
<string id="sak_document2_desc"><text>The descriptive part of the document contains information about an existing method of artifact transformation.</text></string>
<string id="sak_document2_name"><text>Documents and Unreadable Disc</text></string>
<string id="garbage_pda_desc"><text>A PDA found at the Garbage. Among various useless information, there is a description of a relatively safe path from the Garbage to the Forgotten Settlement.</text></string>
<string id="garbage_pda_name"><text>PDA with Information</text></string>
<string id="esc_bandit_letter_desc"><text>Hey, boss... Basically, it's a handy spot here; rookies keep coming through. The loot isn't super rich, but it's constant. I think we'll stay for another week until they catch on. Rusty took the first cut to the common fund yesterday, I'll gather the rest plus a bit more and bring it myself... Also, something happened—a truck full of corpses drove past here, we almost crapped ourselves! But it didn't stop, thank god... We need to get out of this ZONE!</text></string>
<string id="esc_bandit_letter_name"><text>Some piece of paper</text></string>
<string id="gar_bandit_letter_desc"><text>We squeezed some chump here... He doesn't have much gear, just a couple of cheap arts—but he says there's a way to cook a Droplet from a Wrenched. He's probably lying. I'd check it, but I'm a bit chicken—what if it blows up? Anyway, your call...\nKaban</text></string>
<string id="gar_bandit_letter_name"><text>Note with Information</text></string>
<string id="inventory_sakbox_01_name"><text>Ammo Crate</text></string>
<string id="inventory_sakbox_01_desc"><text>A heavy wooden crate. Contains sealed tins of ammunition.</text></string>
<string id="inventory_sakbox_02_name"><text>Metal Box</text></string>
<string id="inventory_sakbox_02_desc"><text>A metal box containing a set of tools.</text></string>
<string id="inventory_sakbox_03_name"><text>Safe</text></string>
<string id="inventory_sakbox_03_desc"><text>A fireproof, armored safe. Locked with a magnetic combination lock. Can only be opened with a blowtorch. No one knows what's inside...</text></string>
<string id="inventory_sakbox_04_name"><text>Steel Case</text></string>
<string id="inventory_sakbox_04_desc"><text>A fireproof steel case with a combination lock. Usually used for transporting important documents or cash.</text></string>
<string id="inventory_sakbox_05_name"><text>High-Security Container</text></string>
<string id="inventory_sakbox_05_desc"><text>A steel laboratory container. Designed for storing and transporting dangerous or fragile substances and items. In the Zone, it's used for transporting artifacts with unknown properties.</text></string>
<string id="inventory_sakbox_06_name"><text>Military Equipment Crate</text></string>
<string id="inventory_sakbox_06_desc"><text>A heavy military crate containing weapons, ammunition, and other gear.</text></string>
<string id="mines_box_desc"><text>Contains MON-50 anti-personnel mines and detonators. Carry with extreme caution!</text></string>
<string id="shadow_inv"><text>Backpack</text></string>
<string id="sak_book1_name"><text>Book</text></string>
<string id="sak_book1_desc"><text>A scientific treatise, incomprehensible to mere mortals...</text></string>
<string id="sak_book3_name"><text>Book</text></string>
<string id="sak_book3_desc"><text>At first glance, an ordinary textbook on correlation calculus.</text></string>
<string id="scaintist_pda_name"><text>Scientist's PDA</text></string>
<string id="scaintist_pda_desc"><text>The electronic organizer of a scientist who died in Pripyat. It likely contains information that would interest the Barman.</text></string>
<string id="item_notebook_desc"><text>A laptop found in the X-18 laboratory. Surprisingly, it is in working condition... It contains data from a seismological survey of the Army Warehouses territory.</text></string>
<string id="item_notebook_name"><text>Laptop with Data</text></string>
<string id="item_notebook_labx6_desc"><text>A laptop found in the "Tesla" bunker. It appears to be in working condition.</text></string>
<string id="item_notebook_labx6_name"><text>Laptop</text></string>
<string id="item_decoder1_name"><text>Eggheads' device from the bunker</text></string>
<string id="item_decoder1_desc"><text>A complex electronic measuring converter.</text></string>
<string id="agroprom_pda_name"><text>Mole's PDA</text></string>
<string id="agroprom_pda_desc"><text>A pocket computer belonging to the stalker known as Mole.</text></string>
<string id="und_pda_name"><text>Max Luber's PDA</text></string>
<string id="und_pda_desc"><text>Judging by the login data, it belonged to Luber. Max Luber, a friend of Pulya, claims that many Duty secrets are hidden within this device.</text></string>
<string id="volkodav_pda_name"><text>Volkodav's PDA</text></string>
<string id="volkodav_pda_desc"><text>Most sections are encrypted. Among the curiosities in public access is a method for obtaining the Fireball artifact.</text></string>
<string id="item_case_esc_name"><text>Documents from the Checkpoint</text></string>
<string id="same_case_esc_name"><text>Special Case</text></string>
<string id="zub_flash_name"><text>USB Drive with Data</text></string>
<string id="zub_flash_desc"><text>Zub, a shady dealer in the Bar, scanned documents he received from bandits who robbed a scientist. Formulas, formulas, formulas, and a few notes in a foreign language. Now what?</text></string>
<string id="x16_flash_name"><text>USB Drive with X-16 Documents</text></string>
<string id="x16_flash_desc"><text>The Barman provided a flash drive containing scans of documents discovered in the X-16 laboratory, along with his own notes and comments. It needs to be taken to Sakharov at Yantar; perhaps this data holds the key to disabling the "Brain Scorcher" at Radar.</text></string>
<string id="strelok_sheets"><text>Strelok's Notes</text></string>
<string id="enc_strelok_sheets"><text>Fragmentary records. Strelok handed them to Ivar; for some reason, it was important to him that Ivar knew this.</text></string>
<string id="strelok_book1_desc"><text>Scribbled pages that look like hastily torn sheets from lecture notes or calculations. They feature notes made by another hand and highlighted in a different color. Is there anything useful here? It's all so high-brow... \n The main point in all of this is the highlighted summary: "Here it is! All that's needed is to connect these anomalous formations with a total weight of 16 kg, plus or minus one hundred grams. If we stay within these limits, it should work!"</text></string>
<string id="strelok_book1_name"><text>Fragmentary Records</text></string>
<string id="strelok_book2_desc"><text>A notebook with records... Strelok's? It's unclear who wrote to whom and regarding what.</text></string>
<string id="strelok_book2_name"><text>Notebook</text></string>
<string id="petruha_letter"><text>Some Scribble</text></string>
<string id="petruha_letter_desc"><text>Incomprehensible letters, numbers, and abbreviations. It looks like an inventory, but it's unclear of what: 1BO, 2NZ, 2KK, 1M... At the end, there is a note: "Don't forget! I need to replace the strap for my shotgun; it rubs my shoulder so much I can't stand carrying it anymore. I've stashed it for now in a house—I'll pick it up the next time I have to trudge through the Darkscape."</text></string>
<string id="vil_volk_letter"><text>Wolf's Note</text></string>
<string id="vil_volk_letter_desc"><text>So you decided to go for it after all. Didn't mind getting your hands dirty in the filth. Well then, listen up for the sake of learning: My mother was a teacher—strict but fair. She was so strict that in the school bathroom (where we usually shared one cigarette between three people), they recognized her by the clicking of her heels; after she bought silent shoes, they were genuinely terrified. But that's not the point. Late 70s, I'm sitting in the back row, drawing (the kindergarten was closed for quarantine, no one to leave me with). Mom is teaching a "problem" class. They loved giving her the ones with the lowest grades and the worst family situations. The lesson ends, Mom goes to take me to the cafeteria and discovers—her boots are gone! Those very ones, new winter boots that she'd saved up for for a long time. Tears and silent despair. The last "most problematic student" leaving noticed this. After clarifying the situation, he left. My mother and I just sat there—her in her indoor shoes, me clutching my coloring book. The bell rings for the next class—that same "problem" student walks in with a triumphant look and hands my mom a bag... with her boots. As it turned out, because of his "problematic" nature, the boy quickly figured out who, where, to whom, and why. He ran off, took them back, and gave them a beating while the trail was hot. Why did he return them? He said, "you can't rip off your favorite teacher." That's how they are, the loyal "problem" ones. Satisfied with the "treasure" you found, pup? Maybe you want to keep looking? There are plenty of latrines in the Zone. You should have used your head first: would I really hide anything valuable in a place like this... \nActually, if I catch you, I'll strangle you.</text></string>
<string id="vil_volk_letter2"><text>Note from Wolf's Stash</text></string>
<string id="vil_volk_letter2_desc"><text>Petruha, I always knew you were a stubborn guy, especially if someone makes you mad. That's why I decided to leave a few messages for you in my "stashes." Look, I said some things in the heat of the moment back then—don't hold a grudge. And that first note I wrote... I wasn't myself, basically. Don't go running straight to Sidor to sell my artifacts. Better find me at the Warehouses; we'll sit down with a bottle or two and talk like human beings. And bring that container with you, alright? I'll definitely share the loot with you; you've helped me so much. I'll be waiting for you at the fork where the road to the Barrier starts.\nWolf</text></string>
<string id="svoboda_letter"><text>Scrap of a Freedomer's Note</text></string>
<string id="svoboda_letter_desc"><text>Radar killed almost everyone... there is no place for the living here. Drop everything and run... If I don't make it by evening, there will be one more walking corpse.</text></string>
<string id="gluzov_letter_name"><text>Letter from Gluzov</text></string>
<string id="gluzov_letter_desc"><text>Greetings, Marked One!\nFinally, an opportunity arose to drop you a few lines. I don't know how long my letter will take to reach you, but I hope you receive it.\n
First, I want to thank you once again for everything you've done for me. My presentation at the conference was well-received, and I've already received several very tempting offers from the largest research institutes in Europe.\n
Second, remembering my promise, I tried to make inquiries about an institution outside the Zone where they could help you recover your memory. I learned about it from a colleague who worked with Professor Sakharov at Yantar.
It's called the "Center for Advanced Zone Research" and is unofficially overseen by the Professor personally. Their main profile is anomalous formations—artifacts—but in reality, they are "jacks of all trades" out of boredom.
My colleague mentioned that among other things, they deal with the rehabilitation of field expedition staff injured in the Zone, but with the right connections—backed by a tidy sum of money—they might take an outsider for treatment.\n
Anyway, I wanted to try to get you in there, but after talking to people in the know, I changed my mind. I won't bore you with unnecessary details, I'll just say that things with this Center are not as pleasant as they seem at first glance.
According to the information I received, several stalkers have been taken there, supposedly for treatment. However, in all that time, not a single one of them has ever been discharged. What happened to them is unknown, but rumors... varied rumors are circulating.\n
On the other hand, for money and with a recommendation from respected people, they could register you not as an ordinary stalker, but, say, as a freelance employee, but... is it worth the risk? I believe it is not.\n
Whatever the case, I will continue to look for alternative options. I'm sure there are plenty of private clinics ready, for an extra fee, to admit a patient in... semi-legal status. As I understand it, you don't have any documents at all, do you?\n
Regardless, everything is solvable as long as there's money. I'll contact you when I find something suitable, but for now... I know you aren't sitting idly by yourself and are trying various ways to regain your memory, so I'll ask Ivan Sergeyevich to provide you with any possible scientific assistance, should you need it.\n
On the back of the sheet, I'll leave a small message for him. Give this letter to I.S. after reading it, and he will help you. This is the least I can do for you right now.\n
Best regards, S. Gluzov.
</text></string>
<string id="mar_theory_desc"><text>Instructions on the use of a "laboratory specimen." Written in shaky, hurried handwriting. Aside from the instructions, it contains theories on energetics that only a specialist would understand. It also inexplicably mentions the "Battery" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="mar_theory_name"><text>Swamp Scientist's Instructions</text></string>
<string id="sak_document4_desc"><text>Found a note inside the tank hatch in the Red Forest. Among other things, it contains a recipe for artifact transformation.</text></string>
<string id="sak_document4_name"><text>Note from a stash in the Red Forest.</text></string>
<string id="war_ecolog_pda_desc"><text>A PDA found in the laboratory beneath the Brain Scorcher.</text></string>
<string id="war_ecolog_pda_name"><text>Scientist's PDA</text></string>
<string id="borov_kurjer_pda_desc"><text>A PDA found by stalkers on a bandit at the Garbage. Non-functional, shot through in two places.</text></string>
<string id="borov_kurjer_pda_name"><text>Borov's Courier's PDA</text></string>
<string id="alko_banka"><text>Jar of Moonshine</text></string>
<string id="enc_alko_banka"><text>Moonshine is moonshine, no matter where you are. As for what it's distilled from... better not to ask. People drink it and even sing its praises.</text></string>
<string id="yantar_docs_name"><text>Documents</text></string>
<string id="yantar_docs_desc"><text>Hidden among the unintelligible scientific gibberish is a method for obtaining a Dummy class artifact.</text></string>
<string id="labx10_ecolog_papers_desc"><text>Hidden among the unintelligible scientific gibberish is a method for artifact modification.</text></string>
<string id="arts_notebook_name"><text>Old Notebook</text></string>
<string id="arts_notebook_desc"><text>A notebook containing notes on various types of artifacts in the Zone. Author unknown.</text></string>
<string id="item_quest_case_03_desc"><text>Inside the briefcase are accounting records and other interesting papers belonging to Borov, the bandit authority from the Dark Valley.</text></string>
<string id="item_quest_case_03_name"><text>Bandit Briefcase</text></string>
<string id="playboy_desc"><text>"Playboy" — a men's magazine. It's unknown how they find their way into the Zone, but they are highly valued.</text></string>
<string id="playboy_name"><text>"Playboy"</text></string>
<string id="playboy_kruglov_desc"><text>"Playboy" — a men's magazine. The egghead at Yantar manages to source new issues from somewhere every now and then...</text></string>
<string id="playboy_kruglov_name"><text>2006 Playboy Magazine Collection.</text></string>
<string id="outfit_soldiersak_desc"><text>Body armor modified using the antigravitational Pellicle artifact. It allows for carrying a significantly higher load, though it is very heavy when inactive. Unfortunately, the modification has resulted in a decreased resistance to damage...</text></string>
<string id="outfit_soldiersak_name"><text>Unique Gravisuit</text></string>
<string id="ara_pda_name"><text>Mercenary PDA</text></string>
<string id="ara_pda_desc"><text>The mercenary Vakhtang kept many of his faction's secrets on this PDA, including a description of a secret path between the Army Warehouses and the Tesla zone.</text></string>
<string id="rad_pda_name"><text>Encrypted PDA</text></string>
<string id="rad_pda_desc"><text>A PDA found near the Brain Scorcher... It's best to have this decrypted. Doesn't look like it belonged to an ordinary stalker.</text></string>
<string id="quest_manycase_01_desc"><text>A fireproof steel case with a combination lock; there's money inside...</text></string>
<string id="quest_manycase_01_name"><text>Steel Case</text></string>
<string id="mask_repair_kit_name"><text>Mask Lens Replacement Kit</text></string>
<string id="mask_repair_kit_desc"><text>A universal kit for replacing mask lenses in field conditions. Rumor has it these are assembled by none other than the junk dealer Lyokha, who set up shop in the Sanatorium. It contains one replacement lens for each of the most commonly used suits, coveralls, and scientific rigs in the Zone.\nRequires a toolbox to use.</text></string>
<string id="mil_crazy_key_name"><text>Key</text></string>
<string id="mil_crazy_key_desc"><text>Looks like a perfectly ordinary key. Obtained from a crazy fellow living in a shack in the middle of a swamp near the Freedom faction base. Apparently, it can be used to unlock a certain lock in the Red Forest.</text></string>
<string id="povar_lost_key_desc"><text>According to a stalker nicknamed Dobryak, this key can unlock the stash of Cook, the Freedom faction's chef.</text></string>
<string id="dog_tag_name"><text>Military Dog Tag</text></string>
<string id="dog_tag_desc"><text>Contains a soldier's individual identification number.</text></string>
<string id="pda_chip_name"><text>PDA Expansion Module</text></string>
<string id="pda_chip_rad_desc"><text>This module allows the PDA to exchange information with other devices supporting long-range data transmission. Specifically, it makes the handheld compatible with Geiger counters and other detectors.</text></string>
<string id="pda_chip_spot_desc"><text>This module updates the "Map" application, allowing the user to create custom markers with text descriptions in the corresponding PDA section.</text></string>
<string id="pda_chip_cook_desc"><text>This module connects the PDA to autonomous ground monitoring stations and scientific data processing centers, allowing for real-time tracking of artifact transmutation results—or, in stalker slang, "cooking."</text></string>
<string id="pda_chip_hack_desc"><text>Dosent's "know-how." This module enables the PDA to be used as a brute-force tool to gain access to data on other PDAs protected by weak passwords. To use it, simply press "Enter" on the device's start screen without typing any characters. If desired, one can still attempt to guess the password manually.</text></string>
</string_table>