<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<string id="General"><text>General Information</text></string>
<string id="Mutants"><text>Animals and Mutants</text></string>

<string id="Chimera"><text>Chimera</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_chimera_general"><text>The result of genetic experiments under the UZAZ program (Universal Army Protection Animal project). It possesses excellent tissue regeneration; furthermore, it has a duplicated system of internal organs, which allows it to withstand trauma better. It usually attacks unexpectedly from behind; if detected, it may retreat, but not for long. Powerful paws allow the chimera to cover vast distances in a single leap, attacking the victim from above. It can emit a piercing shriek that temporarily paralyzes the central nervous system, leaving the victim no chance to even flee. They usually live in small groups.</text></string>

<string id="Fracture"><text>Fracture</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_fracture_general"><text>Whether it's the result of experiments or the Zone's effect on the people who remained, or perhaps just the result of a fevered imagination and the shattered psyche of certain stalkers... \nIt is believed that these mutants, who look very much like thin and hunched humans, possess a hypertrophied limb, and their brain and nervous system have not undergone such destructive changes as those of zombies. They are cunning and try to lure stalkers in with conversation or requests. They say that by sharing food, you can learn interesting information about the Zone... \nThough many veteran stalkers say they've never encountered a Fracture in the Zone; who knows, maybe everyone who saw one learned something so vital about the Zone that they decided to depart from this world...</text></string>



<string id="Burer"><text>Burer</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_burer_general"><text>The result of genetic experiments conducted by secret services on criminals under a program to develop telekinetic abilities in humans. Their temperament is extremely vile; a nervous malice drives them to commit wild and unexpected acts. They are practically unable to control the sounds they emit, which is why they almost constantly mumble or shriek piercingly. They move quite fast but clumsily, stomping loudly. Their intuition and telekinetic abilities are highly developed. Foresight helps them sense an enemy and guess their location without visual contact, while telekinesis allows them to manipulate fairly large objects from a distance, hurl them at the enemy, or deliver powerful telekinetic strikes at medium range. Furthermore, despite their short arms, they can deliver powerful blows in hand-to-hand combat. They usually live alone, or less frequently, in small groups of two or three individuals.</text></string>

<string id="Cat"><text>Cat</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_cat_general"><text>An ordinary domestic animal that has changed significantly under the influence of the Zone. A thyroid gland swollen from radiation is clearly visible on the neck. It possesses a greenish coloration, allowing it to blend better with the natural environment. It scents its prey from afar, moving toward it swiftly and silently. This nickname was given due to its ability to induce strong drowsiness in its victim. Despite the adrenaline during a fight, the victim may simply collapse and fall into a "dead sleep," making them easy prey. They usually live in small prides of three or four individuals.</text></string>

<string id="Blind"><text>Blind Dog</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_blind_general"><text>Since the time of the first disaster, several generations of canines have passed, and in each of them, the influence of the Zone became more apparent. Mutations and evolutionary adaptation led to the strengthening of previously weak canine abilities, often at the expense of conventional ones. The main physiological changes affected their vision — it proved almost useless after the rapid sharpening of their other senses: for example, blind puppies survived in the Zone just as well as, if not better than, their sighted siblings. As a result, ordinary dogs soon died out here completely, giving way to a new species — the Blind Dog. These animals perfectly recognize and bypass anomalies, radiation, and other invisible dangers that infest the Zone. Almost all individuals possess unique psi-abilities: under hypnotic influence, a stalker can easily drop their weapon. In some individuals, these abilities are more developed, in others weaker. Like their ancestors, Blind Dogs hunt in packs; meeting a large group of these creatures means serious danger even for a well-armed stalker. They live in large packs, sometimes numbering several dozen individuals.</text></string>

<string id="Bloodsucker"><text>Bloodsucker</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_bloodsucker_general"><text>A semi-legendary monster. A hunter of hunters. A tall, hunched humanoid with many tentacles in place of a mouth. Apparently, the creature feeds using these tentacles. The most amazing thing about the bloodsucker is its ability to become invisible. It is very fast, ferocious, and extremely dangerous. It attacks the victim with a powerful strike of a clawed paw, becoming visible only immediately before the strike, then, if the victim survives, it distances itself, becoming invisible again, only to circle back on a sharp arc and strike again. They can emit sound waves unbearable to humans, stunning them and opening old wounds, causing profuse bleeding. They live both alone and in small packs.</text></string>

<string id="Boar"><text>Boar</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_boar_general"><text>A large beast, reaching a meter and a half at the withers. In its resilience and aggressiveness, this animal surpasses its relatives outside the Zone and is not inferior to most mutants. Mutagenic processes caused by radiation and anomalies have significantly affected the appearance of these mammals: in some places they have gone bald, while in others, conversely, they have grown very long, stiff fur, especially on the belly, which, for reasons still unknown, is capable of accumulating ionizing radiation. The animals' hooves have changed shape and become sharper, acquiring some resemblance to claws; the pupils have lost color, and pigment spots and deep wrinkles have appeared on the balding head. Usually, these animals attack at a run, trying to rip open the victim's belly with their tusks or knock them off their feet. They live in small to large packs.</text></string>

<string id="Crow"><text>Crow</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_crow_general"><text>Only one bird species survived in the Zone — crows. Other feathered creatures could not endure the radiation and did not learn to avoid anomalies. To avoid dying in the labyrinth of gravitational disturbances, military pilots use complex detectors, but the secret of the crows will soon drive ornithologists and biologists crazy. There are many theories explaining this phenomenon; however, they all agree that the reason for this miracle is the highly developed brain of crows, which has managed to develop complex reflexes.</text></string>

<string id="Flesh"><text>Flesh</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_flesh_general"><text>Domestic pigs that ended up in the Zone, like many other living organisms, underwent severe mutation. Since the genes controlling metabolic processes were affected, the animal's phenotype changed drastically. The mutated pig, which stalkers call "Flesh," is one of the most vivid examples of the Zone's violation of nature. These creatures have developed a scaly-bony protective shell that perfectly protects them from almost all mechanical impacts, and their nervous system has become more complex. They rarely attack alone, however, like a regular pig, the flesh is omnivorous, so if hungry, it may well attack a stalker. They live in small and large packs.</text></string>

<string id="Poltergeist"><text>Poltergeist</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_poltergeist_general"><text>Truly supernatural invisible creatures found only deep within the Zone; they usually live inside semi-ruined buildings. Nothing is reliably known about their origin; a legend exists that these are the spirits of stalkers caught in a massive blowout. The way these invisibles manifest indeed matches the legends of the poltergeist (hence the name) and varies: from periodic howling and laughter to dangerous fireballs appearing out of nowhere. Unfortunately, all information about this phenomenon is drawn from vague and rather contradictory stories whose truthfulness is doubtful.</text></string>

<string id="Controller"><text>Controller</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_controller_general"><text>A rare mutant, usually found close to the center of the Zone. Externally, it resembles a humanoid with a disproportionately enlarged head. It possesses advanced perception as well as the ability to control the behavior of less developed living beings. Mature individuals are capable of taking control even of humans. In the immediate vicinity of a controller, the victim begins to experience various auditory and visual hallucinations, gradually driving them mad. They usually live alone.</text></string>

<string id="Pseudodog"><text>Pseudodog</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_pseudodog_general"><text>Despite the name, pseudodogs originated not from dogs, but from wolves. Wild animals living in the Zone's forests at the time of the disaster became the ancestors of one of the most dangerous mutant species. Pseudodogs are as different from mutated dogs as wild wolves are from mutts. These creatures lead a territorial lifestyle and fiercely attack anyone who invades their domain. Lightning-fast reactions, incredible mobility, and sharp teeth make the pseudodog a very serious opponent, difficult to resist even for a large mutant or a well-armed stalker. With direct visual contact, they can cause minor convulsions in the victim, preventing aimed fire. They live in small and large packs.</text></string>

<string id="Pseudogiant"><text>Pseudogiant</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_pseudogiant_general"><text>The Pseudogiant is a massive bulk consisting of a drop-shaped torso and a pair of hypertrophied limbs. The "arm-legs" are used by this creature for movement and grasping prey. An adult individual reaches a weight of two tons with a height of about two meters. The external clumsiness is very deceptive — pseudogiants are swift in their movements, their muscles possess simply amazing power, and their bones are as strong as metal. The brain is protected by a very thick — about 100 millimeters (!) — skull; furthermore, many complex functions are performed by the spinal cord. Also striking is the pseudogiants' ability to form local shockwaves on the ground's surface, striking everything living within a limited radius. They live alone or in small packs.</text></string>

<string id="Snork"><text>Snork</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_snork_general"><text>These creatures, apparently, were once humans, though it is difficult to imagine what conditions could bring a person to such a state. Snorks are crazed creatures leading a completely animalistic lifestyle, essentially little different from the predatory monsters of the Zone. They move on four limbs, hopping above the ground and constantly sniffing it to catch the scent of prey. They hunt cautiously and calculatively, lying in wait for stalkers like predatory animals. Lightning reflexes and hypertrophied muscles allow snorks to make long, precise jumps and tear a victim to shreds in seconds. On some individuals, parts of army uniforms or individual pieces of equipment have been preserved, suggesting they were once missing-in-action military stalkers. They live in small and medium groups.</text></string>

<string id="Tushkano"><text>Tushkano</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_tushkano"><text>In fact, these animals are not related to the well-known jerboas, although they look quite similar to them. It is not yet possible to pinpoint the species from which the Zone's tushkanos descended; one can only state that their ancestors were pack animals, most likely rodents. Reaching up to 40 centimeters at the withers, they are significantly more mobile, aggressive, and voracious than the desert animal. They live everywhere, eating everything they find — from plants to distracted stalkers. Sometimes even large animals and mutants fall victim to tushkanos: attacking in a large pack, they will easily tear apart any creature that hasn't managed to escape. They are quite cowardly, but they exist in a kind of symbiosis with most mutants: animals from all around flock to their shrieking, which can create many problems. They usually live in large packs.</text></string>

<string id="Zombie"><text>Zombie</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_zombie_general"><text>The impact of the Brain Scorcher completely destroys the personality structure, leaving only the physical shell. After wandering through the Zone for a while, the mindless bodies begin to turn into actual zombies. Only the most primitive reflexes remain, and weapons and clothing soon fall into disrepair. As a result, zombies are nothing more than slow-moving semi-corpses, for whom only two effective stimuli exist: food and sleep. Zombies are completely indiscriminate in their choice of food and drink, so their bodies are literally saturated with radiation and toxins. As a rule, these creatures wander aimlessly through the Zone or, like corpses, lie inside abandoned buildings. However, as soon as a zombie senses the close presence of a living person, it immediately tries to attack. Experienced stalkers try to bypass these clumsy, hollowed-out shells.</text></string>

<string id="Zombieg"><text>Electro-tushkano</text></string>
<string id="enc_mutant_zombieg_general"><text>A small rat-like creature moving on two legs. One of the stupidest mistakes one can make in life is to underestimate these animals because of their small size. Tushkanos are insanely fast and nimble and always move in large packs. In appearance, it's a regular tushkano, however, due to prolonged exposure to high anomalous radiation, this particular species has acquired the property of accumulating and carrying a huge amount of static electricity, making them even more dangerous opponents from whom any trick can be expected.</text></string>

<string id="mutant_face_tushkano"><text>Tushkano head</text></string>
<string id="mutant_face_tushkano_description"><text>Tushkanos have highly developed intelligence, and scientists are trying to figure out how such a tiny brain holds a large amount of information and everything else. From a substance obtained from the tushkano brain, scientists are trying to create new drugs that will allow humans to use their own thinking capabilities much more fully. Unfortunately, when the heart stops for a few seconds, the pressure in the cranium rises sharply and the thin walls of the skull, for the most part, cannot withstand it and literally burst, while the brain turns into jelly. Finding a tushkano corpse with a preserved brain does not happen often.</text></string>

<string id="mutant_hand_kontroler"><text>Controller hand</text></string>
<string id="mutant_hand_kontroler_description"><text>The controller possesses psi-abilities. At a distance, it can only intimidate and create various hallucinations, but when you get closer, it inflicts damage. Scientists believe that the controller's power is concentrated in its hand, but this has not been fully investigated. For research, a special hand is needed that does not lose its properties after the death of the host. If you hold it close to your head, you can feel a slight malaise. It is highly discouraged to carry such limbs with you for long.</text></string>

<string id="mutant_poltergeist_glas"><text>Poltergeist eye</text></string>
<string id="mutant_poltergeist_glas_description"><text>No one knows what a poltergeist eye is needed for, but they pay well for it. When an individual is destroyed, the physical shell of the poltergeist usually breaks down, turning into an incomprehensible substance with a sharp, disgusting smell. Therefore, obtaining an intact eye happens extremely rarely.</text></string>

<string id="mutant_psevdogigant_hand"><text>Pseudogiant chunk</text></string>
<string id="mutant_psevdogigant_hand_description"><text>Researchers who really want to study the nature of this mutation try to get a piece of pseudogiant flesh. And they can sometimes pay well for it. The outer shell of the carcass is so strong that separating this very piece works, at best, once out of five times.</text></string>

<string id="mutant_tail_cat"><text>Cat tail</text></string>
<string id="mutant_tail_cat_description"><text>The resistance of the skin of mutated cats to chemical and electrical effects has long attracted the attention of scientists. Due to the absence of fat deposits, undamaged tails of young cats are best suited for laboratory research. They are smaller in size and significantly more resilient than the rest. Externally, this manifests as a faint phosphorescence.</text></string>

<string id="mutant_chimera_kogot"><text>Chimera claw</text></string>
<string id="mutant_chimera_kogot_description"><text>Some individual chimeras have claws with strength comparable to diamond. Whether this is a mutational feature or a coincidence of some external factors is unknown, but all scientific circles show interest in such anomalous claws outside the Zone perimeter. Determining if a claw is anomalously hard is quite simple: it is impossible to even scratch it.</text></string>

<string id="mutant_e_chimera_kidney"><text>Electro-chimera kidney</text></string>
<string id="mutant_e_chimera_kidney_description"><text>According to scientific research, it is in the kidneys of the electro-chimera that the electromagnetic discharges are generated, which make it so deadly.</text></string>

<string id="mutant_boar_leg"><text>Boar hoof</text></string>
<string id="mutant_boar_leg_description"><text>A rare specimen of a boar hoof. It differs from ordinary hooves in that it constantly radiates heat and does not emit radiation at all. Most likely the result of a mutation.</text></string>

<string id="mutant_dog_tail"><text>Dog tail</text></string>
<string id="mutant_dog_tail_description"><text>The resistance of the skin of some mutated dogs to chemical and electrical effects has long attracted the attention of scientists. Due to the absence of fat deposits, the tails of these dogs are most suitable for laboratory research. They differ from ordinary tails by a characteristic matte color.</text></string>

<string id="mutant_flesh_eye"><text>Flesh eye</text></string>
<string id="mutant_flesh_eye_description"><text>After mutation, the enlarged eye of some flesh specimens acquired a number of properties, the most useful of which is the ability to regenerate the lens. The details of this mechanism are not exactly known, but this discovery promises a revolution in medicine. Such an eye can be distinguished from ordinary ones by its characteristic iris if you point a light source at it — be it sunlight or light from a flashlight.</text></string>

<string id="mutant_zombie_hand"><text>Zombie hand</text></string>
<string id="mutant_zombie_hand_description"><text>The manner of movement with the hand extended forward leads to the fact that practically all individuals have severely damaged hands. But rare specimens are found in which this part of the body is almost not subjected to the effects of the aggressive environment. Such limbs are of great interest in the development of protection against the anomalous effects of the Zone. They can be distinguished from useless ones by the sensation of intense cold that emanates from this part of the body.</text></string>

<string id="mutant_burer_hand"><text>Burer hand</text></string>
<string id="mutant_burer_hand_description"><text>The hands of rare burer specimens have acquired a number of properties, the most useful of which is high resistance to radiation. The details of this mechanism are not exactly known. Such hands differ from ordinary ones by a characteristic ossification.</text></string>

<string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw"><text>Bloodsucker tentacles</text></string>
<string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw_description"><text>Bloodsucker tentacles contain a special gland: it secretes an enzyme that dissolves the victim's skin and simultaneously prevents blood clotting. If scientists manage to determine the structure of the enzyme, it will help achieve a breakthrough in medicine. Unfortunately, cutting off the tentacles without damaging the gland is extremely rare, and without it, such tentacles are practically useless.</text></string>

<string id="strange_bs_jaw_name"><text>Unusual bloodsucker tentacles</text></string>
<string id="strange_bs_jaw_name_desc"><text>Found in the Ivankiv regional center at the site of the disappearance of a strange creature resembling a bloodsucker. This specimen will surely interest the research group from the Swamps.</text></string>

<string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail"><text>Pseudodog tail</text></string>
<string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail_description"><text>An undamaged tail is a rare bit of luck. Usually, from the impact of the anomalous environment, pseudodog tails look depressing. But there are also specimens where even the fur is in perfect condition. Scientists are very interested in specifically such tails.</text></string>

<string id="mutant_snork_leg"><text>Snork boot</text></string>
<string id="mutant_snork_leg_description"><text>Once an ordinary army boot. Now very strongly modified. What caused these changes is unknown, but the removed boot appears to be an integral part of its owner. In its internal cavity, blood vessels connecting the piece of clothing with the mutant's foot are clearly visible in several places. The entire outer part of the boot is dotted with hairs or bristles, both minute and larger ones. Another striking feature of this object is the ability to independently close cuts and other damage under the influence of radiation. Overall, it leaves the impression of a "living" boot, as far as that's possible.</text></string>

<string id="fracture_spleen_name"><text>Fracture spleen</text></string>
<string id="fracture_spleen_desc"><text>The internal organs of fractures represent almost no value due to the rapid necrosis of tissues after the host's death. But there is one exception. Dr. Perelman hypothesized that the active growth of the strike arm in fractures is associated with the secretion of special hormones by the spleen of these mutants. Beyond the perimeter, there are a small number of collectors obsessed with the Zone who are ready to give a lot of money for such a "trophy" in a jar of formalin.</text></string>
</string_table>