<!-- ;Vergas  © NLC 7 ============================ -->

#include "text\eng\string_table_pda_stalker.xml"
#include "text\eng\string_table_pda_bandit.xml"
#include "text\eng\string_table_pda_dolg.xml"
#include "text\eng\string_table_pda_freedom.xml"
#include "text\eng\string_table_pda_killer.xml"
#include "text\eng\string_table_pda_ecolog.xml"
#include "text\eng\string_table_pda_treasure.xml"

<string id="razgruzka_name"><text>Army Load-Bearing Vest</text></string>
<string id="razgruzka_new_name"><text>Load-Bearing Vest</text></string>
<string id="razgruzka"><text>A load-bearing vest designed for carrying essential ammunition and personal emergency medical supplies.</text></string>
<string id="podsumok"><text>A belt pouch for carrying various small items.</text></string>
<string id="klava_name"><text>Electronic Notebook</text></string>
<string id="klava"><text>A reworked old smartphone turned into an electronic notebook by the technician Vergas.</text></string>
<string id="st_sleeping_bag"><text>Sleeping Bag</text></string>
<string id="st_sleeping_bag_descr"><text>A lightweight sleeping bag. Waterproof. This model combines the comfort of a blanket-style bag with the high thermal insulation of a mummy cocoon.</text></string>
<string id="st_notebook_of_artist"><text>Artistís Sketchbook</text></string>
<string id="st_notebook_of_artist_descr"><text>A sketchbook of a deceased artist, filled with drawings and travel notes.</text></string>
<string id="flask_army"><text>Army Flask</text></string>
<string id="flask_army_descr"><text>A flask with a screw cap on a chain. Made of food-grade aluminum. Comes with a protective cover. Designed for convenient carrying of liquids.</text></string>
<string id="self-made_decoder"><text>Decoder</text></string>
<string id="self-made_decoder_descr"><text>A homemade device for breaking into electronic door lock systems and extracting the keypad code matrix.</text></string>
<string id="bag_on_belt"><text>Belt Bag</text></string>
<string id="bag_on_belt_descr"><text>A handy bag for storing a small number of minor items. Commonly used by stalkers as a reserve emergency stash.</text></string>
<string id="krujka_1"><text>Glass in a Holder</text></string>
<string id="krujka_1_descr"><text>A glass found in the Sanatorium. Clearly old-fashioned.</text></string>
<string id="krujka"><text>Mug</text></string>
<string id="krujka_descr"><text>A mug found in the Sanatorium.</text></string>
<string id="chashka"><text>Cup</text></string>
<string id="chashka_descr"><text>A cup found in the Sanatorium.</text></string>
<string id="graal"><text>Grail</text></string>
<string id="graal_descr"><text>A goblet found in the Sanatorium. Looks like tea was brewed in it more than once...</text></string>
<string id="anomaly_krujka"><text>Weight with a Mug</text></string>
<string id="anomaly_krujka_descr"><text>A weight found in the Sanatorium. A full pood. How did a mug get embedded into it like that? Damn Zone!</text></string>
<string id="pivnaya_krujka"><text>Beer Mug</text></string>
<string id="pivnaya_krujka_descr"><text>A beer mug found in the Sanatorium. Clearly been through an anomaly.</text></string>
<string id="skiing"><text>Skis</text></string>
<string id="skiing_descr"><text>Old wooden skis with soft felt-boot bindings and bamboo poles. Donít glide at all.</text></string>

<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_0"><text>Oh right, I found some kind of mug. Crawled all over the entire sanatorium...</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_1"><text>Well Iíll be... Nice! Letís see it.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_2"><text>You take this mug. Iím sick of hauling it around.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_3"><text>And you werenít too lazy to lug all that weight, Marked One. The mug isnít mine, and I donít know the weight either... But you know, you moved me, Marked One. You didnít spare the time or effort, crawling through some ruins just to please an old man you barely know. Hand the thing over. Iíll keep it as a reminder of your good deed.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_4"><text>Thanks for the trouble, Marked One, but no hard feelings. Itís not mine... But you know, you moved me, Marked One. You didnít spare the time or effort, crawling through some ruins just to please an old man you barely know. Hand the thing over. Iíll keep it as a reminder of your good deed.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_5"><text>A fine little thing, but not mine. Use it yourself... But you know, you moved me, Marked One. You didnít spare the time or effort, crawling through some ruins just to please an old man you barely know. Hand the thing over. Iíll keep it as a reminder of your good deed.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_6"><text>Sorry, but thatís not what you were supposed to find. Maybe youíll get lucky next time... But you know, you moved me, Marked One. You didnít spare the time or effort, crawling through some ruins just to please an old man you barely know. Hand the thing over. Iíll keep it as a reminder of your good deed.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_7"><text>Donít recognize it. Someone elseís thing... But you know, you moved me, Marked One. You didnít spare the time or effort, crawling through some ruins just to please an old man you barely know. Hand the thing over. Iíll keep it as a reminder of your good deed.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_8"><text>Some kind of grail. You didnít find it in a church, did you? Head still aching? Clearly not mine... But you know, you moved me, Marked One. You didnít spare the time or effort, crawling through some ruins just to please an old man you barely know. Hand the thing over. Iíll keep it as a reminder of your good deed.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_10"><text>Here, take a look. Mustíve been one hell of a quake at the sanatorium if it got embedded into a weight like that...</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_11"><text>Here. A beer mug. Clearly been through an anomaly. You can barely even see it...</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_12"><text>Thatís not a cup, itís a glass. But itís got a holder.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_13"><text>Here, a mug like any other. Clearly someone drank tea from it.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_14"><text>Here it is, a little cup. Careful ó porcelain. Fine work.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_15"><text>Not quite a cup, but they clearly had tea with it.</text></string>

<string id="dialog_krujka_V_100"><text>Oh! Thatís mine! Hand it over, weíll carve it out of the weight.\nAnd special thanks for not selling it to anyone.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_101"><text>Mine, my favorite! Holds as much as a samovar.\nAnd special thanks for not selling it to anyone.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_102"><text>My little glass! I remember nicking it on a train once... Accidentally.\nAnd special thanks for not selling it to anyone.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_103"><text>Thatís the one, dear to my heart. You did me a real favor, Marked One.\nAnd special thanks for not selling it to anyone.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_104"><text>A collectorís item. Thatís what I used to drink tea from at the sanatorium.\nAnd special thanks for not selling it to anyone.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_105"><text>There it is, my imperial goblet!\nAnd special thanks for not selling it to anyone.</text></string>

<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_108"><text>Well then, take it and enjoy!</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_109"><text>Iíll give this to you, VergasÖ a bit later, I willÖ</text></string>

<string id="dialog_krujka_V_150"><text>Thank you, Marked One. At least Iíll have some kind of keepsake. Of my past life, or of your good deed ó all that matters is that it warms the soul.\nAnd this is for you. Been saving it, so to speak, for old age, but for you ó no regrets.</text></string>

<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_202"><text>Well damnÖ And what do I need skis for? Itís May.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_203"><text>Nope, I donít need a gun like that. Keep it.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_204"><text>Donít need a sleeping bag ó extra weight.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_205"><text>Thanks, I already have one. Donít need a second pair of binoculars.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_206"><text>A batteryís a good thing, but Iíve got nowhere to put it right now. Sorry.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_207"><text>Iíll manage without that belt.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_208"><text>Iíd take the container, but itís too heavy. Keep it.</text></string>

<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_210"><text>I donít use that kind of ammo. No thanks.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_211"><text>Keep the repair kits. You need them yourself.</text></string>

<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_213"><text>These medkits are too weak. Got any army or scientific ones?</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_214"><text>Donít need matches right now. A lighter would be better.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_215"><text>Nice armor, but mineís better. Iíll pass.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_216"><text>Donít need this. Field rations give me heartburn.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_217"><text>Vodkaís a good thing, but not right now.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_218"><text>Grenades are kinda weak. Got any anti-tank ones?</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_219"><text>Donít need antirads. Iíll treat myself with vodka instead.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_220"><text>Donít need those ìcatís eyesî. Heard they make your kidneys fail.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_221"><text>How do people even drink this? Wonít even go down. Vodkaís better.</text></string>

<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_223"><text>Canned food again... No, thanks.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_224"><text>Hunting? No need.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_225"><text>The best sausage is a sock full of money. Wanna trade for that?</text></string>

<string id="dialog_krujka_V_303"><text>You shouldnít have passed on that. Itís a good piece.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_304"><text>A sleeping bagís a solid thing. Youíll regret it later, when itís too late.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_305"><text>EhÖ that optics is German, you know.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_306"><text>A batteryÖ That batteryís worth its weight in gold.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_307"><text>Just so you know, belts like that donít lie around on the roadside.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_308"><text>Couldíve dropped it off in Stasís stash, saved it for better times.</text></string>

<string id="dialog_krujka_V_310"><text>Youíre a strange one, Marked One. You could trade that for anything you want at the Bar.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_311"><text>True enough. Youíll come crawling back for repairs anyway.</text></string>

<string id="dialog_krujka_V_313"><text>Medkits like these are a real rarity around here.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_314"><text>Look at what youíre asking for. Gasolineís in short supply these days.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_315"><text>Wouldnít say so myself, but suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_316"><text>Agreed. This is nowhere near a NATO field rationÖ</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_317"><text>Up to you. Drink vodka then ó surprise your liver.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_318"><text>Maybe youíd rather I hook you up with a gun?</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_319"><text>A decent option, but antiradís more reliable. In my opinion.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_320"><text>Your loss. Thatís good chemistry. And everyoneís liverís still intact so far.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_321"><text>Right on the mark. But sometimes a can like that saves your life.</text></string>

<string id="dialog_krujka_V_323"><text>As you say. Canned food tastes like crap, but at least it doesnít spoil.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_324"><text>Thatís where youíre wrong. Tasty, and it wonít go bad either.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_325"><text>Youíll earn it yourself. All I can offer is a sock.</text></string>

<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_700"><text>Thanks. Hope this comes in handy.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_701"><text>Youíre welcome.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_702"><text>Alright, Iím off.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_703"><text>Hey now, my friend, only the Zone knows how long youíll be walking her paths. Youíll probably ring in the New Year somewhere around here.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_704"><text>Donít jinx it, Vergas. But fine ó Iíll take it.</text></string>
<string id="dialog_krujka_V_705"><text>There we go.</text></string>

<string id="dialog_krujka_GG_11001"><text>Got it. Iím not an idiot.</text></string>

<string id="krujka_not_found_0"><text>Vergas, I canít get your story out of my headÖ the one about you lying paralyzed in that local Sanatorium, then the emission putting you back on your feet. You also asked me to look for your cup, remember? Itís all strange. What if there are sometimes special, ìhealingî emissions?</text></string>
<string id="krujka_not_found_1"><text>ìHealing,î yeah right. It only worked like that on me ó for the others lying there, it was hell. And why it happened to me that way, who knows. And the cupÖ you know, Iím starting to think maybe there was no ìspecialî cup at all. Just an ordinary hospital one. Or maybe I made it up entirely, just so life wouldnít feel so scary. Just to have at least some proof of my past life.</text></string>
<string id="krujka_not_found_2"><text>Yeah, I get it. Iíd dig with my bare hands just to learn anything at all about my own past. By the way, about your cup ó Iíve been to that Sanatorium more than once, but I never came across any dishes. Except maybe three-liter jars.</text></string>
<string id="krujka_not_found_3"><text>Really? Thatís a shame. Youíre the one who took care of the burer that settled there, right? The youngsters have been talkingÖ Youíre a good man, Marked One. You didnít forget my request, and you even did a good deed that helped everyone. Ah, to hell with it! Iíd been saving something for a rainy day, but you need it more. Here, take this ó a gift from me.</text></string>
<string id="krujka_not_found_4"><text>Well, old manÖ I donít even know what to say. I didnít expect this. Thank you.</text></string>