<!--ŔĚĘ -->
<string id="trans_finished_title_upgr"><text>Artifact transmutation result - </text></string>
<string id="trans_finished_title"><text>Artifact transmutation complete</text></string>
<string id="af_dummy_buliz"><text>"Cobblestone"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_buliz"><text>An artifact that has lost all its properties as a result of an energy collapse is called a "Cobblestone". These artifacts remain valuable to science, as they emit light and anti-gravitational energy. Some stalkers use the latter property to lighten their carried load. Scientists pay well for them. May cause a feeling of hunger.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_buliz"><text>Artifact, the result of an energy collapse.</text></string>
<string id="af_spirit_1"><text>"Soul Drop"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_spirit_1"><text>The modificate improves health and reduces the dose of absorbed radiation. Slightly increases human fatigue, sensitive to electricity.</text></string> 
<string id="artifact_spirit_1"><text>Modificate of the "Symbiont" artifact.</text></string> 
<string id="af_spirit_2"><text>"Fire Soul"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_spirit_2"><text>This mesomodificate retains the "Soul Drop" property of improving health, but is one and a half times more effective at reducing the dose of absorbed radiation. At the same time, it negatively affects human endurance, sensitive to electricity.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_spirit_2"><text>Mesomodificate of the "Soul Drop" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_spirit_3"><text>"Crystal Soul"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_spirit_3"><text>This hypermodificate retains the properties of improving health and increasing bodily fatigue, sensitive to electricity. It has a very high rate of removing radionuclides from the human body.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_spirit_3"><text>Hypermodificate of the "Fire Soul" artifact</text></string>
<string id="af_spirit_4"><text>"Bengal's Crystal Soul"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_spirit_4"><text>This absolute perfectly removes radiation from the human body, removes psi-emissions, and improves health. Highly valued on the market both inside and outside the Zone.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_spirit_4"><text>Absolute of the "Symbiont"-"Soul Drop"-"Fire Soul"-"Crystal Soul" artifact line.</text></string>
<string id="af_cry_1"><text>"Tears of Electra"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_cry_1"><text>The modificate increases endurance, provides protection from electricity and fire, and also negatively affects resistance to impact and rupture. May cause a feeling of hunger.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_cry_1"><text>Modificate of the "Battery" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_cry_2"><text>"Tears of Fire"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_cry_2"><text>"Tears of Fire" fairly well increases the endurance of the person wearing this mesomodificate on their belt, protects well against fire and electricity. Increases vulnerability to impact and rupture. May cause a feeling of hunger.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_cry_2"><text>Mesomodificate of the "Tears of Electra" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_cry_3"><text>"Tears of Chimera"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_cry_3"><text>This hypermodificate, besides very well increasing endurance, is also useful in that it protects against fire and electricity. Increases vulnerability to impact and rupture. May cause a feeling of hunger.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_cry_3"><text>Hypermodificate of the "Tears of Fire" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_cry_4"><text>"Giant's Tear"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_cry_4"><text>This absolute magnificently increases human endurance, and is also useful in that it perfectly protects against fire and electricity. May cause a feeling of hunger.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_cry_4"><text>Absolute of the "Battery"-"Tears of Electra"-"Tears of Fire"-"Tears of Chimera" artifact line.</text></string>
<string id="af_babka_1"><text>"Grandmother's Beads"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_babka_1"><text>The resulting modificate generates a temporal field that significantly slows down the speed of bullets entering it, thereby protecting the person from critical wounds. Improves telepathy susceptibility, protects well against psi-cramps. You can carry more additional weight. Slightly radioactive.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_babka_1"><text>%c[default]%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Psi-cramp protection  %c[255,1,255,1]+55%\n%c[default]Modificate of the "Mama's Beads" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_babka_2"><text>"Great-grandmother's Beads"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_babka_2"><text>"Great-grandmother's Beads" have a somewhat better bullet wound resistance rate relative to "Grandmother's Beads" due to the increased temporal field. Improves telepathy susceptibility, protects very well against psi-cramps. You can carry significantly more additional weight. At the same time, do not forget that "Great-grandmother's Beads" are slightly radioactive.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_babka_2"><text>%c[default]%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Psi-cramp protection  %c[255,1,255,1]+65%\n%c[default]Mesomodificate of the "Grandmother's Beads" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_babka_3"><text>"Burer's Grandmother's Beads"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_babka_3"><text>A unique hypermodificate, more akin to an absolute in its properties. Its temporal field is strong and has a large radius, so a person wearing "Burer's Grandmother's Beads" on their belt has a high chance of surviving even a hit from an SVD. Improves telepathy susceptibility, perfectly protects against psi-cramps. At the same time, the hypermodificate allows you to carry additional weight.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_babka_3"><text>%c[default]%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Psi-cramp protection  %c[255,1,255,1]+75%\n%c[default]Hypermodificate of the "Grandmother's Beads" artifact</text></string>
<string id="af_babka_4"><text>"Burer's Great-grandmother's Beads"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_babka_4"><text>A unique absolute, improves telepathy susceptibility, magnificently protects against psi-cramps. Carry a lot, don't get tired.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_babka_4"><text>%c[default]%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Psi-cramp protection  %c[255,1,255,1]+90%\n%c[default]Absolute of the "Mama's Beads"-"Grandmother's Beads"-"Great-grandmother's Beads"-"Burer's Grandmother's Beads" artifact line</text></string>
<string id="af_pudd_1"><text>"Fire Dummy"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_pudd_1"><text>In addition to neutralizing high temperatures, this modificate grants the wearer resistance to electricity when carried on the belt, but in turn makes the body more susceptible to bullet and shrapnel wounds. Increases movement speed.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_pudd_1"><text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Movement Speed  %c[255,1,255,1]+5%\n%c[default]Modificate of the "Dummy" artifact</text></string>
<string id="af_pudd_2"><text>"Bright Dummy"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_pudd_2"><text>This mesmodificate shares the same properties as its "parent" artifact. The positive qualities (resistance to thermal and electrical effects, as well as increased movement speed) are more pronounced, while the negatives (reduced resistance to bullet and shrapnel wounds) are less severe.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_pudd_2"><text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Movement Speed  %c[255,1,255,1]+10%\n%c[default]Mesmodificate of the "Fire Dummy" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_pudd_3"><text>"Lunar Dummy"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_pudd_3"><text>This hypermodificate shares the same properties as its "parent" artifact. The positive qualities (resistance to thermal and electrical effects, as well as increased movement speed) are more pronounced, while the negatives (reduced resistance to bullet and shrapnel wounds) are less severe.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_pudd_3"><text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Movement Speed  %c[255,1,255,1]+15%\n%c[default]Hypermodificate of the "Bright Dummy" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_pudd_4"><text>"Pudding"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_pudd_4"><text>This absolute provides strong protection against extreme heat and electric shock. Noticeably increases movement speed. No negative properties detected.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_pudd_4"><text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Movement Speed  %c[255,1,255,1]+20%\n%c[default]Absolute of the "Dummy"-"Fire Dummy"-"Bright Dummy"-"Lunar Dummy" artifact line.</text></string>

<string id="af_dik_1"><text>"Porcupine"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_dik_1"><text>Despite the fact that this modificate is very simple, the "Porcupine" has a high radiation blocking rate, increases jumping! The modificate slightly reduces endurance and increases bleeding, which is a fairly modest price for the ability to roam irradiated lands without fear of receiving a lethal dose of radiation.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_dik_1"><text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Jump increase  %c[255,1,255,1]+7\n%c[default]Modificate of the "Spring" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_dik_2"><text>"Electric Porcupine"</text></string> 
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_dik_2"><text>The mesomodificate has a blocking rate for radiation and electricity, but unfortunately, it increases sensitivity to fatigue and bleeding.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_dik_2"><text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Jump increase  %c[255,1,255,1]+8\n%c[default]Mesomodificate of the "Porcupine" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_dik_3"><text>"Snotty Porcupine"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_dik_3"><text>This hypermodificate has a radiation blocking rate - a person receives only 35 percent of the amount of roentgens they would have received without wearing this hypermodificate on their belt. Besides this, it is very effective against chemical burns. The unpleasant side of the "Snotty Porcupine" is that it increases a person's sensitivity to fatigue, and it is inconvenient to wear due to an incomprehensible slime constantly oozing from it. The substance is harmless, but terribly unpleasant. Despite its unpresentable appearance, the hypermodificate is highly valued in the Zone.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_dik_3"><text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Jump increase  %c[255,1,255,1]+9\n%c[default]Hypermodificate of the "Electric Porcupine" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_dik_4"><text>"Stone Porcupine"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_dik_4"><text>This absolute reduces the dose of radiation received by a person by exactly a quarter. In addition to this rarest quality, the "Stone Porcupine" reduces a person's sensitivity to explosions and effectively reduces bleeding. It is highly valued not only by scientists, but also by stalkers.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_dik_4"><text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Jump increase  %c[255,1,255,1]+10\n%c[default]Absolute of the "Spring"-"Porcupine"-"Electric Porcupine"-"Snotty Porcupine" artifact line.</text></string>
<string id="af_kol_1"><text>"Steel Kolobok"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_kol_1"><text>"Steel Kolobok" reduces the skin's sensitivity to rupture and impact. Unfortunately, it is radioactive and sensitive to telepathy.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_kol_1"><text>Modificate of the "Kolobok" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_kol_2"><text>"Titanium Kolobok"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_kol_2"><text>"Titanium Kolobok" reduces the skin's sensitivity to rupture and impact. Unfortunately, it is radioactive and sensitive to telepathy.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_kol_2"><text>Mesomodificate of the "Steel Kolobok" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_kol_3"><text>"Diamond Kolobok"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_kol_3"><text>The hypermodificate gives the skin of the person wearing it resistance to rupture, reduces the effect of impact. The downside of this rather useful hypermodificate is that it emits radiation.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_kol_3"><text>Hypermodificate of the "Titanium Kolobok" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_kol_4"><text>"Giant's Younger Brother"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_kol_4"><text>This absolute reduces the skin's sensitivity to rupture, impact, and radiation accumulation for the person wearing it.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_kol_4"><text>Absolute of the "Kolobok"-"Steel Kolobok"-"Titanium Kolobok"-"Diamond Kolobok" artifact line.</text></string>

<string id="af_armor_1"><text>"Hide"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_armor_1"><text>The modificate reduces susceptibility to the effects of any chemically aggressive environment, slightly improves resistance to telepathy, and perfectly removes psi-emissions. It is radioactive, bleeding is increased.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_armor_1"><text>Modificate of the "Pellicle" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_armor_2"><text>"Scale"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_armor_2"><text>The "Scale" mesomodificate reduces the impact of chemically aggressive environments on a person, improves telepathy susceptibility, and removes psi-emissions. At the same time, "Scale" is radioactive and increases bleeding in the person wearing it.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_armor_2"><text>Mesomodificate of the "Hide" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_armor_3"><text>"Carapace"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_armor_3"><text>"Carapace" increases telepathy susceptibility, removes psi-emissions, and neutralizes most chemically aggressive environments upon contact with human skin. The only negative quality is a slight radiation background.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_armor_3"><text>Hypermodificate of the "Scale" artifact.</text></string>
<string id="af_armor_4"><text>"Controller's Scalp"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_armor_4"><text>This absolute perfectly reduces damage from aggressive chemical environments, very well shields and removes psi-emissions.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_armor_4"><text>Absolute of the "Pellicle"-"Hide"-"Scale"-"Carapace" artifact line.</text></string>
<string id="af_dummy_simbion"><text>"Symbiont"</text></string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_simbion"><text>The unique dummy "Symbiont" is obtained by the simultaneous transmutation in a "Fruit Punch" anomaly of four artifacts at once: "Jellyfish" - completely negative, "Stone Blood" - completely positive, "Droplet" - completely positive, and "Thorn" - completely negative, which, converted into a single whole, give the person wearing it on their belt tangible protection from psi-emissions. At the same time, the "Symbiont" also increases the rate of psi-health recovery.</text></string>
<string id="artifact_simbion"><text>Dummy of the "Jellyfish", "Droplet", "Stone Blood", and "Thorn" artifacts.</text></string>
<string id="enc_amk_recipt_simbion_name"><text>[4] Symbiont from Fruit Punch</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_stone_dikoobraz_1_text"><text>Log 1: "... and we saw the whole process from start to finish, even though the Monolith members surrounded the "Springboard" in a tight ring, trying to cover the transmutation process and the artifact itself from possible observation. But Artyom was in a fairly advantageous position and managed to examine the artifact thrown into the anomaly through his binoculars. It turned out to be a "Snotty Porcupine" (a strange name, but it's original, given by the stalker-creator, we verified this data). An hour and a half later, already in the evening, the artifact was thrown back out by the anomaly. Now we have to take it from the Monolith members. Artyom suggested doing this during their next prayer to the Monolith. It will begin in 40 minutes. After we return, I want to put in a good word for this capable guy. Vladislav Leonidovich, I think you will support it..." \n \nLog 2: "... I will dump the data in fragments onto a flash drive, I will duplicate it. We dealt with the Monolith members fairly quickly - while they were performing some strange ritual around a black rectangle brought by one of them instead of a backpack (at first I thought it was a knapsack, but it turned out to be a portable altar(!); Vladislav Leonidovich, I think this fact will be of interest to both Russian and foreign colleagues). Artyom opened fire from his "Vintorez", and I added a couple of grenades from the underbarrel launcher. To our joy, our main fears did not come true - the altered artifact remained intact. After two days of our trek, I noted the following qualities of the "Stone Porcupine" (we gave it the name considering its properties and origin from the "Snotty Porcupine"): this artifact, which I would classify as an absolute, reduces the dose of radiation received by a person by 50 micro-roentgens per hour! In addition to this rarest quality, the "Stone Porcupine" reduces a person's sensitivity to explosions, effectively reduces bleeding, and adds jumpiness..." \n \nLog 3: "... they're chasing us. Monolith members, about fifteen people. We tried to break away - didn't work. They are gradually closing the ring. I will leave the flash drive with the duplicate information to Artyom Inkin, and I will try to hold off the pursuers myself..."</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_stone_dikoobraz_2_text"><text>Log 1: "... they took me at the exit from the village... I managed to get five of them... we didn't even manage to send out a ping, the quick response group is still sitting there waiting... They shot off Andrey Semyonovich's leg right in front of my eyes, just below the knee, the bitches! They led us for a long time, I carried the wounded Andrey Semyonovich. I didn't even know they had an underground stash here. Those scumbags said we would answer for killing their brothers... They threw Andrey Semyonovich into the next cage, he was already unconscious by then... they untied my hands and didn't even take my PDA and backpack, only my weapons and ammo..." \n \nLog 2: "... I don't know what it is... I don't know... it's not a bloodsucker, it's not a chimera... it's not... It crawled out of the pit to their singing! They opened the door of Andrey Semyonovich's cage... it didn't touch them, it immediately moved to the cage... it crawled in there... and... AND STARTED DEVOURING HIM! AND HE WAS STILL ALIVE AND SCREAMING!!! IT WAS GNAWING HIS FACE OFF, AND HE WAS WHEEZING AND TRYING TO USE HIS HANDS..." \n \nLog 3: "... it will come... the Monolith members left, and it's sitting there in the ground... I hear its thoughts. They left and opened the door to my cage... and it went down and is talking to me from down there and... and Andrey Semyonovich is speaking... in my head. I will leave... I'll just take Andrey Semyonovich's arm... he says that even just the arm, that's already good... it... is important, very important... and it... won't come out... it's glowing down there... in the pit... like a rainbow... and tells me not to go anywhere... but I will leave... they didn't even close the door... said it wouldn't let me crawl out... but it went to its place after it gnawed Andrey Semyonovich clean... only left an arm... Andrey Semyonovich says I should leave now... while it's thinking down below... And I took the arm... because it's important to him..." \n \nLog 4: "I tricked it... it's stupid... I took Andrey Semyonovich's arm and my backpack... and left. It started roaring and crawling out... but suddenly stopped - I told it I really needed to go out. It believed me and didn't follow me further! Just roared for a long time and glowed in the dark... I TRICKED IT! I tricked it..."</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_steel_kolobok_text"><text>Log 1: "Found a dead stalker. Or rather, what was left of him next to a "Springboard". He had a "Kolobok" in his backpack, and a weird one at that - it glows, the infection. I racked my brains, decided to throw my "Kolobok" into the "Springboard" and see what happens. It's a shame, of course, I could've gotten a lot of booze for it, but... screw it, I'll try." \n \nLog 2: "Sitting, waiting. Waxed a lone zombie. I shouldn't have fed the "Kolobok" to this anomaly, oh I shouldn't have!" \n \nLog 3: "Yes! Flew out, my baby, like a cork. Glowing. Gotta drink to this!" \n \nLog 4: "Phew! Got lucky! I'm definitely gonna be walking around the Zone drunk now. If I was sober - I'd be dead for sure! Ran into a thug. He blasted at me with a PM, but his barrel jammed right after the shot. So that scum pulled out a knife and slashed me. I put that bitch down with my shotgun!" \n \nLog 5: "It ain't all that simple. Doesn't really add up. Like, for example, I clearly remember him slicing my leather jacket open easily with his knife, I remember the blade hitting, but on my stomach - just a scratch. Maybe my "Koloboks" helped me? "Steel Koloboks"... And they do radiate, those round bastards. Yeah, "Steel Balls" would've been cooler..."</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_titan_kolobok_text"><text>Saracen dragged in some caught rookie. Says he didn't off him right away 'cause this rookie was lookin' around all funny, like he was carryin' somethin' real valuable. Stubborn punk! We felt up his backpack and found an interestin' "Kolobok". Well, "Kolobok"... looks like it, but then again, it don't. Asked him what kind of beast he had in his bag, he kept quiet like a partisan. Gotta respect that! He's a skinny twerp, too! Swede broke a couple of his fingers before he told us what's what. Says it's a "Steel Kolobok" changed in a "Whirligig". Like, it lays there a bit and becomes somethin' else. Says it saves you from impacts real good, and ain't bad against ruptures, but damn it, it's radioactive and you better not step into a "Matrix" with it. Came up with a funny name for it - "Titanium Kolobok"! We gotta check if this faker was tellin' the truth. Now if only we could find a "Steel Kolobok"..."</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_almaz_kolobok_text"><text>This hypermodificate, obtained by the transmutation method in a "Fruit Punch" anomaly of the "Titanium Kolobok" mesomodificate, gives the skin of the person wearing it resistance to rupture and impact. The downside of this hypermodificate is that it emits radiation.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_controller_skalp_text"><text>May He abide in Eternity, may He change the World! \n \nMentor Victor has heralded another success from his naturalists! The Mentor, like all of us, is certain that He has once again presented us, His followers, with a gift to strengthen our faith! After a skirmish with a military squad that was guarding scientists, Phalanx Leader Ostakh brought back a "Carapace" along with bodies and trophies. Along with the bodies of the lost, it was sacrificed to His Flame, but the Watchers, Brother Akim and Brother Lekho, found the "Carapace" that fell out of the "Burner" an hour and a half later. It glowed unusually, which confirmed the Watchers in His sign. This altered "Carapace" went through two skirmishes together with the naturalist Brother Roman. On the way back, his phalanx encountered and fought four burers in the catacombs. Brother Roman claims that this altered "Carapace" worked miracles - Brother Roman hardly felt the burers' psi-attacks! He also noticed that for the entire time he wore this artifact, he didn't want to eat. Truly, He gifts us fragments of Eternity even now! Further natural tests showed that this artifact, given the name "Controller's Scalp" by the Quality, improves well-being, stops bleeding, and saves from chemical burns. Our faith grows and strengthens day by day! For He remembers us! May He abide in Eternity! May He change the World!</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_souls_text"><text>... so, here's how it was. On the night of July seventh, half a month ago, basically, a "Tramp" popped up in building #3 - a wanderin' "Burner" anomaly, shit. I was left alone in that building, Max and Yurka Sevastopol left, though how - I still don't get... we were drinkin' heavy. Just as I was gettin' ready to make a bed in the corner - whoa, fire from the wall! I'm drunk, at first I thought Timur Marinade fixed that infantry flamethrower he found and was messin' around. Then I thought a gas pipe burst in the walls - there used to be a kitchen behind it. Then I remembered the gas in the pipes ran out like fifteen years ago, got a little confused, started pourin' water on it. But when I saw the flame movin' along the wall, I finally got it, but it was too late - managed to grab my G36 off the nail, but not the bag with the "Soul" I found two days ago. Got real bummed out, had a drink. And a bit later, my "Soul" falls out of the fire! Only it's glowin' real cool, like a lamp. So I snatch it up and put it in a container. Woke up the next mornin', look: the boys are roastin' a piglet on the "Burner". That's when I remembered the "Soul". Warned Max and dragged myself to the eggheads. Had a fun trip gettin' there, but that's another story. Got there, gave this "Soul" for measurements. Sugar scratched his bald head for a long time after. "Besides improvin' human health," he says, "the artifact has gained the ability to reduce the dose of radiation." Also this art (I named it "Soul Drop", sounds cool) adds to fatigue. Sugar tried to talk me into sellin' it for a long time, but I didn't bite. By then I already had a plan - throw this art into the "Burner" again and see what happens, and then bring it to Sugar for measurements again. He scratched his skull for a long time again, but agreed. I took my "Soul Drop" and moved to the tunnel. There's a shit ton of those "Burners" there. Threw it in, waitin'. Less than an hour passed, it started showin' up, but wouldn't jump out of the anomaly. Barely got it out, got singed, almost went as bald as Sugar. Brought it for measurement and turned out to be right! This art (I called it "Fire Soul") started protectin' against radiation twice as good! Nah, I guess it's a good thing I didn't go to college. Who knows, could've been a professor, an academic... Anyway, I went to the "Burner" for the third time, like the Old Man to the blue sea, damn it. Dropped a couple of zombies on the way, one turned out to be former Mikha Cameroon, I had a drink for him to rest in peace later. What a fate, huh, 'cause a month ago I was drinkin' with him, and today a bullet in the head... may he rest in... Threw the "Fire Soul" into the "Burner" and started waitin' again. This time it happened even faster. The art jumped out, glowin' so happily. I picked it up and moved to the eggheads. There's already a whole crew waitin' there, pourin' me coffee with cognac, messin' with the artifact themselves. While in a high-society mood with the coffee and Hennessy, I came up with a name for it - "Crystal Soul". The eggheads are gaspin', amazed, sayin' this hyp... hyperdiff... anyway, the "Crystal Soul" improves health and got some unprecedented radiation protection stat. Next mornin' I made it to the "Burner" without any trouble again, threw my precious "Crystal Soul" into the anomaly. Waited a long time. Look - the art jumped out. I didn't get it - the glow didn't change for shit. Well, I think, to hell with you, if you don't want to - don't. Walked back, look - a wanderin' "Electra" is pushin' through the passage. No way to get past. Sat there and sat there, then I think: "Let's throw my art into the 'Electra'!" Happened just like in the "Burner" - it disappeared in there and jumped back out soon. The light comin' off it is completely different! I waited for the "Electra" to migrate further and went on my way. Brought the "Crystal Soul" to Yantar, gave it to Sugar. He was gone for a long time, comes out of the lab - his eyes are glowin' behind his glasses, fo' real like a psycho. Says it's some kind of absolute. If the trans... transm... anyway, the changed "Soul" used to decrease human endurance, this art, besides improvin' health and protectin' from radiation, increases endurance instead of decreasin' it. I made a good chunk of cash off the eggheads for studyin' my "Soul" back then...</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_tears_electra_text"><text>The "Battery" artifact is placed into an "Electra" anomaly. The resulting "Tears of Electra" modificate increases the wearer's endurance. A negative impact on the human body is dealt through impacts and ruptures.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_tears_fire_text"><text>The "Tears of Electra" modificate is placed into a "Burner" anomaly. The resulting "Tears of Fire" mesomodificate fairly well increases endurance, has good protection against fire. Vulnerability to impacts, ruptures.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_tears_chimaera_text"><text>The "Tears of Fire" mesomodificate is placed into a "Fruit Punch" anomaly. This hypermodificate increases endurance well and is also useful in that it increases protection against fire and electricity.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_tears_gigant_text"><text>The "Tears of Chimera" hypermodificate is placed into an "Electra" anomaly. The resulting absolute very well increases endurance, and is also useful in that it blocks almost half the damage from fire and electricity.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>For mandatory familiarization. \n \nSoldiers! Our comrades, the scientists, have provided information about the possibility of altering the "Mama's Beads" artifact and subsequently granting it new characteristics. This artifact is subject to alteration only in the "Electra" anomaly, into which the artifact must be placed. After this, it, with a high degree of probability, receives new characteristics. I quote from the scientists' document: "The resulting modificate generates a temporal field that fairly significantly slows down the speed of bullets entering it, thereby protecting a person from critical wounds, when worn on a belt, it is possible to carry more weight. Slightly radioactive." \n \nI recommend copying the file to your PDAs and, when meeting with quads on a raid, transferring the information directly to the leader of the encountered group...</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_pra_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>... Found Vanka Four Fingers in the village. I hid in there from a pack of dogs. I'm sitting there, from the open cellar I can hear the crackling of a Geiger counter. I immediately grabbed my weapon: who knows, maybe some bandit or merc hid in there. Looked, and he's lying there face down in a "Fruit Punch". I only recognized him by his moronic bandana - red with hammer-and-sickle crests. And it had only been four hours since we parted ways; he went ahead, and I was waiting for Vadik Rosy to pass him a package. It's a shame, damn... Well, anyway, I put on my gas mask and went down to pull him out. Couldn't figure out how he fell in there for a long time, since he'd been stomping around the Zone for four years already, until I saw that someone snapped his neck. Obviously, I changed my mind about burying him in the ground right away. Who knows what kind of hostess prepared some canned food out of an experienced stalker for herself, and whether this very hostess was grazing somewhere nearby. Quickly looted him, trying not to touch his clothes, took off his backpack, the arts from his belt. Didn't take his favorite TOZ - the "Fruit Punch" chewed up the shotgun pretty good. And I got out of there as fast as I could. Vanka only had three arts. A "Droplet", a "Sea Urchin" and those "Grandmother's Beads" of his. The "Droplet" and "Sea Urchin" were hanging on the back of his belt, but the "Grandmother's Beads" fell into the "Fruit Punch". Thought the artifact was a goner, but it turned out - the art was perfectly intact, only glowing weirdly. Well, I tested it out while I was making my way to the Freedom guys. It became different. I called it "Great-grandmother's Beads" in my head. Saved me from bullets decently when I ran into a military zombie. And the backpack felt like it got lighter. And it started radiating less than the "Grandmother's Beads". I'll probably sell it to the scientists and get myself some new gear.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_burer_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>Log: "I got some info for you. You know, I served as a clerk over there at our base: sat at a computer, messed with documents and reports. And then, when our guys started getting your fellow stalkers killed every day, I couldn't take it! Disgusting... Well, whatever, not about that right now. I accidentally read one file there... Well, sort of accidentally... Anyway, had to mess with the code for a bit to hack it... Didn't copy it, but memorized it tight. There was an egghead report there about changing artifacts in anomalies! Can you imagine! So this file said that if you take some me... meso something or other... called "Great-grandmother's Beads" - moronic name, remembered it right away, just don't ask what it is, I have no idea - and put it in a "Whirligig", then in less than an hour a different artifact comes out! Well, kind of different... The exact same one, only its properties change. It radiates some kind of field, significantly slows down everything flying fast that gets into it. I thought: "That means bullets!" Also, like, you can carry additional weight. There you go. I hope this information helps you more than it helped me."</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_burer_pra_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>The "Burer's Grandmother's Beads" hypermodificate is placed into a "Burner" anomaly. This absolute, besides very well increasing endurance, is also useful in that it blocks a portion of telepathy and allows carrying additional weight.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_dikoobraz_text"><text>... to achieve the required transmutation, the "Spring" artifact is placed into a "Burner" anomaly. If the transmutation is successful, the transformed artifact receives a very good radiation protection stat. Its negative characteristics are that it increases fatigue and prevents wounds from closing. Our subsequent experiments showed the impossibility of further transmutation of the resulting "Porcupine" modificate in this anomaly...</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_electra_dikoobraz_text"><text>Not for distribution! Only for "Freedom" members! Top secret, shit! \n \nVitek Rosy managed to create a new art! You need a "Porcupine" for the source, gotta throw it into an "Electra", and this artifact hatches out of it. Rosy called it an "Electric Porcupine", but basically, I couldn't care less. Main thing is the art holds back radiation pretty damn well and helps against "Electra". Kvely, I can already see your concerned question about girls - go straight to the forum for that. Don't PM me - I'll kill ya! Oh, right - achtung! It sucks, if you put on this "Electric Porcupine", your endurance drops real fast, and you gotta be more careful when shavin', god forbid you cut yourself. So be careful out there! \n \nStepan Mediacenter, infoservice, fuckin' hell.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_sopl_dikoobraz_text"><text>Gentlemen! Mr. Alexey Astronomer's group provided an invaluable service to our laboratory. The fact is, the territory near our mobile laboratory was flooded with boars and fleshes. This is their second migration wave after the last emission, we already had casualties among our personnel. Mr. Alexey Astronomer's group, who responded to our call for help, completely destroyed the mutants! We believe that monetary compensation does not fully reflect the depth of our gratitude, and in order to support our further cooperation, we are sending you information about the generation of the "Snotty Porcupine" hypermodificate. We apologize for the somewhat vulgar name, but it, invented by the creator of this hypermodificate, best describes the essence of this artifact. I hope the "Duty" soldiers possess a proper sense of humor and will adequately react to this artifact and its name! To obtain a "Snotty Porcupine", it is necessary to place an "Electric Porcupine" artifact into a "Fruit Punch" anomaly. I would like to note that this hypermodificate has a radiation blocking rate - a person receives only 35 percent of the amount of roentgens they would have received without wearing this hypermodificate on their belt. Besides this, it also very effectively stops bleeding and blocks chemical burns. The unpleasant side of the "Snotty Porcupine" is that it increases a person's sensitivity to physical exertion, and it is inconvenient to wear due to an incomprehensible slime constantly oozing from it. The substance is harmless, but terribly unpleasant. Overall, our team believes that such a small inconvenience as slime will not discourage your soldiers from using this hypermodificate!\n \nRespectfully, Member of the Russian Academy of Sciences, Academician Sakharov</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_giant_small_brother_text"><text>Log 1: "Barely got out of the Dark Valley. Lost Yurka Brawler - guy got torn apart by a vortex, didn't notice in the firefight how a burer shoved him in there with psi-strikes... may he rest in peace... Bad. The group is incomplete without him - fewer chances to carry this interesting piece of paper to the Bar. Looks like the burers dragged some poor scientist into the catacombs for lunch. He wrote in his PDA that he discovered a way to change artifacts into new... modificates, or whatever... that's what's written, I think... Anyway, the result is some absolute class artifact he named "Giant's Younger Brother", and it's made in a "Burner" from a "Diamond Kolobok". The scientist wrote that this absolute not only reduces the skin's sensitivity to impact and rupture for the person wearing it, but also "deflects" a fairly sensible percentage of bullets entering the generated field away from the person. Pleasant bonuses of the "Giant's Younger Brother" are the following properties: decent removal of radiation from the body and a decrease in a person's need for food by feeding them with its own energy. Overall, interesting information, we should take it to Sakharov and his team, just with more guards just in case, two groups minimum." \n \nLog 2: "Ran into those blockheads from "Freedom"! The three of us dropped five of them. Just started rejoicing over the trophies - they got some fine barrels, when Sanka Cooler's head got blown off by a shot from an SVD. We hit the sound with our underbarrel launchers, but it's unclear if we offed that sniper or not. Rinat says I should leave, he'll cover me. The information is way too important... The sniper, asshole, isn't giving his position away at all, he's an old bird. Alright, gotta go..."</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_shkura_text"><text>Hello, Vovan. You're such a blockhead! Why do you keep repeating: "How's it in the Zone, how's it in the Zone?". It's nothing special! Boring as hell. If we weren't catching these half-wits pushing in there for artifacts, it'd be completely depressing. No, well, it gets creepy sometimes, why should I show off to you... When some animal or who knows what howls near the checkpoint - I don't shit my pants, but my hair stands on end. Even on my ass... And that's considering I, like everyone else here, don't let go of my assault rifle. Recently, though, there was some entertainment - we caught a guy. Was walking back from the Zone. Well, we took him. He was dragging some little rock with him, glowing - like the underbelly of your tuned up Lada 99 in the dark! Well, we interrogated him with some pressure, he told us that this rock isn't just an artifact, but some new crap - it, like, has the ability to reduce chemical burns, or something, and you can, like, not give a damn about psi. Well, not entirely, of course. Also said blood clots poorly. We checked this rock with a dosimeter - it crackles, the infection! And this caught guy tells us that he's, like, carrying this thing to the scientists, like, for the benefit of the people. Opened up his heart, says you take some "Pellicle", throw it into a "Springboard" and bam! And less than an hour passes, and this crap is ready. He said a lot of other things, looking scruffy himself, covered in scars. A ghoul, basically. Anyway, we put him in a transport and sent him to the third checkpoint, they'll deal with him there. Alright, Vovan, take care, I gotta go to formation soon. Hey, tell Yulka I love her there, remember her and all that. Anyway, be safe!</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_cheshya_text"><text>Gentlemen, I am glad to inform you that we have discovered a new transmutation sample! The "Hide" modificate is exposed to the "Whirligig" anomaly for approximately 20 to 40 minutes (the reasons for such fluctuations in time have not yet been established). The resulting mesomodificate, with the working title "Scale", possesses the following characteristics: it reduces the impact of chemically aggressive environments on a person, reduces the impact of psi. Attention, this is important! "Scale" is radioactive and increases bleeding in the person wearing it! We hope that this information will help you in your noble cause, and also that this small present will further strengthen our friendship and partnership! \n \nRespectfully, Member of the Russian Academy of Sciences, Academician Sakharov</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_pancir_text"><text>Comrade Major, a report has arrived from the Center regarding the "Carapace" hypermodificate provided by us for study. Judging by the data received, the "Carapace" (the "Scale" mesomodificate reborn in a "Fruit Punch" anomaly) reduces bleeding for the person wearing it, neutralizes most chemically aggressive environments upon contact with human skin, and the impact of psi is insignificant. The transmutation time is short - only about 40 minutes on average, give or take 10 minutes. The Center has expressed a desire to obtain as many objects for study as possible and new data on all possible modificates, authorizing us for fifth-degree interrogations. In connection with this, I request your permission to conduct interrogations of this degree on captured stalkers. \n \nCaptain M. Lubyankin</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_simbion_text"><text>I hasten to inform you, Nikolai Valentinovich, that Department "B" has provided us with an unexpected result from their research! They discovered that if four different types of artifacts are placed in a "Fruit Punch" anomaly: a "Jellyfish", a "Droplet", a "Stone Blood", and a "Thorn", then as a result of transmutation, a completely new artifact is generated with amazing qualities! This dummy, assigned the working name "Symbiont", blocks 50% of psi-emissions in a small radius around its wearer, and also helps to recover faster from the consequences of psi-field exposure on the human body! The experiments were conducted on prisoners who were subjected to a mental attack by our captive Archibald. Making allowances for the fact that this controller has been in our captivity for a long time, and without the nourishment of residual emission energy it has somewhat weakened, I still believe that the psi-blocking rate is excellent! The report for the Center has been compiled, I am waiting for your comments and permission to send the data. \n \nHead of Department "B", Professor Snegirev</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_dummy_text"><text>Report #14/7 on project "Deceiver"\nTo the Director of the "K-32" Research Department\nProfessor Sazonov Nikolai Dmitrievich\n \nDear Nikolai Dmitrievich, we have completed a series of experiments on the "Lunar Dummy" hypermodificate. During the experiments, 7 (seven) "Lunar Dummy" hypermodificates were subjected to destruction, 5 (five) "Lunar Dummy" hypermodificates were subjected to degradation, 1 (one) "Lunar Dummy" hypermodificate showed a positive result in a series of transmutations. \n \nWhen the "Lunar Dummy" hypermodificate was placed into a "Fruit Punch" anomaly, the artifact was not rejected, as it was in the "Burner" and "Vortex" anomalies. The altered artifact received absolute class properties, namely: it increases resistance to fire, slightly increases endurance, and significantly increases resistance to electroshock and radiation. The working name of the absolute is "Pudding". \n \nFurther placement of the resulting absolute into a "Fruit Punch" anomaly led to nothing - the anomaly rejects the artifact. \n \nI believe that our group has reached a brilliant result in our research on the transmutation of the "Dummy" artifact. Thus, I consider project "Deceiver" successfully completed. Full observation records have been transferred to the server. \n \nHead of Research Group "7", V. A. Avakyan</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_fake_text"><text>To obtain the "Sunlight" modificate, it is necessary to place the "Moonlight" artifact into a "Burner" anomaly. After approximately four hours, the "Sunlight" modificate is formed, possessing the following properties: a strong increase in endurance, a decrease in susceptibility to high temperatures, a slight decrease in susceptibility to electroshock. A side effect is that the resulting modificate emits radiation. Information not verified.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_tears_gigant_text"><text>I see everything, I feel everything, I understand everything... I can't change anything. I know it's going to hurt soon...\n \nA controller doesn't kill right away. And it doesn't extinguish consciousness right away, and even your will and desire remain with you for a long time... long enough to regret it. But a human is a strange creature: wants to live, even when they understand it would be better to die. \nI will whisper. While it's not looking, while there's still a chance to move my lips of my own volition. \n \nThe strange artifact is still glowing there, in the dark, next to the anomaly that devoured both my partners... although a few days have already passed, and a couple of previous Emissions have changed the rest of the anomalous terrain beyond recognition. This is the third \n \nIt doesn't like Emissions. There is a burrow, safe, no anomalies. It hides in there when the sky pours with crimson, "plugs" the entrance with the carcass of a controlled pseudogiant... The giant roars, scrapes with its paws, trying to break inside, to get further away from the scorching fire advancing from the North. Not a chance! The entrance is narrow, the giant can't fit. It squeals and writhes, breaking into an absolutely unbearable ultrasound... blue-green transparent drops swell and roll down the corners of its huge, saucer-like eyes. The giant is in pain. It is crying. Wow... and I cannot. \n \nMotya was "extinguished" by the contra right away. Just looked in his direction, and he – exactly like a mannequin, a spineless doll! – stepped right into the nearest anomaly himself. Just as he was – with all his gear, his backpack, his weapons... Did that weapon really help him! And it didn't help us, paralyzed, either. We just stood and watched as this scum pulled what was left of a human out of the sparking "Electra", laid it out on the rusty, withered grass... and licked its lips, the bastard, and even seemed to smirk! \n \nAnd Motya had an art for telepathy protection in his container - how many times did he demonstrate his precious "Tears of Chimera" to us... The intact backpack didn't interest the contra. And the fact that a white flash extinguished the world for a moment didn't excite or scare it either. Or maybe it didn't notice?.. We noticed, just as we noticed the new light appearing a little later next to the flickering anomaly - one of Motya's artifacts had reborn there. But we didn't care anymore. \n \nFilin was second. Right after the second Emission. Also by himself. Also without screaming. One moment there was Filin and a "Springboard" - and then instantly a pile of bloody shreds and the indifferent, expressionless eyes of the contra. It wanted to eat and it got food... Now it's my turn. \n \nI know – the Controller is hungry again. And a "Springboard" was just born nearby. But first I need to go and take what has been glowing near the non-disappearing anomaly for a few days now... It said to go. I will go. I'll finish whispering and go. It said so, after all. And the artifact – is green. Green, like those tears. Tears of a giant during an Emission. Here, I see it as if up close. No, not green. Aquamarine... strange word... where is it from? I don't remember. Need to take it. It says to take it... \n \nI am going...</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_burer_pra_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>... Sergey Romanovich, I ask you to pay special attention to Appendix 12 to Kratov's group's latest monthly report, namely - to the results of the study of "Sample 112-12-3". According to preliminary data, the mass production of absolutes with such properties seems to be of paramount importance both in order to achieve maximum protection for our expeditions and to continue receiving grants under the "Apostle" program. As far as we have been able to establish, obtaining such artifacts "artificially" is indeed possible, despite all the calculations of Professor Saraev, who asserted the complete insolvency of our assumptions. After reading the full report, you yourself will be convinced of the rightness of my words. For now, suffice it to say that placing the hypermodificate codenamed "Burer's Grandmother's Beads" (please forgive this stalker slang, but we are almost used to it here) into a third-type singularity anomaly ("Burner"), in the area of subcritical voltage of torsion and alpha fields, leads to the appearance of a new artifact, provisionally named by us for now as "Burer's Great-grandmother's Beads". The time required for the transformation is up to 1 hour. Possessing only positive properties, from our point of view, this artmodificate is not subject to the destructive influence of emissions, and can rightfully be called an absolute of this modification line. By the way, the history of obtaining our experimental sample is as unusual as it is, I am not afraid of this word, tragic... But it is better to talk about such things over fish soup and strong drinks, and therefore, since I have a vacation coming up very soon, I hope to tell it to you personally, somewhere on a night fishing trip by the fire. Stalkers are desperate guys, and in their reckless experiments with "cooking" (Imagine, that's what they call the processes of supermatter transformation in the points of singular regions!) they are somewhat akin to the mystical Monolith members. \n \nYes, and say hello to your wife, Irina Semyonovna - a lovely woman, and she helped us a lot with supplies last month. Without her patronage for the new mass spectrometers, we wouldn't have achieved this for another year...</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_dikoobraz_text"><text>\n \nThe "Porcupine" radiation resistance modificate is obtained from\nthe "Spring" artifact\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 10 to 30 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_electra_dikoobraz_text"><text>\n \nThe "Electric Porcupine" radiation and electricity resistance mesomodificate is obtained from\nthe "Porcupine" modificate\nby transmutation in an %c[UI_orange]"Electra" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 20 to 40 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_sopl_dikoobraz_text"><text>\n \nThe "Snotty Porcupine" radiation, chemical burn, and bleeding resistance hypermodificate is obtained from\nthe "Electric Porcupine" mesomodificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Fruit Punch" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 30 to 50 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_stone_dikoobraz_text"><text>\n \nThe "Stone Porcupine" bleeding, radiation resistance, and explosion absolute is obtained from\nthe "Snotty Porcupine" hypermodificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Springboard" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 40 minutes to 1 Zone hour.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_steel_kolobok_text"><text>\n \nThe "Steel Kolobok" impact and rupture resistance modificate is obtained from\nthe "Kolobok" artifact\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Springboard" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 10 to 30 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_titan_kolobok_text"><text>\n \nThe "Titanium Kolobok" impact and rupture resistance mesomodificate is obtained from\nthe "Steel Kolobok" modificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Whirligig" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 20 to 40 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_almaz_kolobok_text"><text>\n \nThe "Diamond Kolobok" rupture and impact resistance hypermodificate is obtained from\nthe "Titanium Kolobok" mesomodificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Fruit Punch" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 30 to 50 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_souls_bengal_text"><text>\n \nThe "Bengal's Crystal Soul" health, radiation resistance absolute is obtained from\nthe "Crystal Soul" hypermodificate\nby transmutation in an %c[UI_orange]"Electra" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 40 minutes to 1 Zone hour.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_souls_drops_text"><text>\n \nThe "Soul Drop" health and radiation resistance modificate is obtained from\nthe "Symbiont" artifact\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 10 to 30 Zone minutes.</text></string>
    
<string id="enc_amk_recipt_souls_fire_text"><text>\n \nThe "Fire Soul" health and fire resistance mesomodificate is obtained from\nthe "Soul Drop" modificate\nby transmutation in an %c[UI_orange]"Electra" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 20 to 40 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_souls_cristal_text"><text>\n \nThe "Crystal Soul" health and radiation resistance hypermodificate is obtained from\nthe "Fire Soul" mesomodificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 30 to 50 Zone minutes.</text></string>
    
<string id="enc_amk_recipt_tears_electra_text"><text>\n \nThe "Tears of Electra" endurance modificate is obtained from\nthe "Battery" artifact\nby transmutation in an %c[UI_orange]"Electra" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 10 to 30 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_tears_fire_text"><text>\n \nThe "Tears of Fire" endurance mesomodificate is obtained from\nthe "Tears of Electra" modificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 20 to 40 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_tears_chimaera_text"><text>\n \nThe "Tears of Chimera" endurance hypermodificate is obtained from\nthe "Tears of Fire" mesomodificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Fruit Punch" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 30 to 50 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_tears_gigant_text"><text>\n \nThe "Giant's Tear" endurance absolute is obtained from\nthe "Tears of Chimera" hypermodificate\nby transmutation in an %c[UI_orange]"Electra" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 40 minutes to 1 Zone hour.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>\n \nThe "Grandmother's Beads" bullet resistance and carrying capacity modificate is obtained from\nthe "Mama's Beads" artifact\nby transmutation in an %c[UI_orange]"Electra" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 10 to 30 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_pra_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>\n \nThe "Great-grandmother's Beads" bullet resistance and carrying capacity mesomodificate is obtained from\nthe "Grandmother's Beads" modificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Fruit Punch" anomaly.\n \n %c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 20 to 40 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_burer_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>\n \nThe "Burer's Grandmother's Beads" bullet resistance and carrying capacity hypermodificate is obtained from\nthe "Great-grandmother's Beads" mesomodificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Whirligig" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 30 to 50 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_burer_pra_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>\n \nThe "Burer's Great-grandmother's Beads" carrying capacity and psi-protection absolute is obtained from\nthe "Burer's Grandmother's Beads" hypermodificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 40 minutes to 1 Zone hour.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_giant_small_brother_text"><text>\n \nThe "Giant's Younger Brother" rupture, impact, and radiation resistance absolute is obtained from\nthe "Diamond Kolobok" hypermodificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 40 minutes to 1 Zone hour.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_shkura_text"><text>\n \nThe "Hide" telepathy, chemical burn resistance, and psi-health recovery modificate is obtained from\nthe "Pellicle" artifact\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Springboard" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 10 to 30 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_cheshya_text"><text>\n \nThe "Scale" telepathy, chemical burn resistance, and psi-health recovery mesomodificate is obtained from\nthe "Hide" modificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Whirligig" anomaly.\n \n %c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 20 to 40 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_pancir_text"><text>\n \nThe "Carapace" telepathy, bleeding, chemical burn resistance, and psi-health recovery hypermodificate is obtained from\nthe "Scale" mesomodificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Fruit Punch" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 30 to 50 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_simbion_text"><text>\n \nThe unique "Symbiont" psi-protection dummy is obtained simultaneously from four artifacts:\n \n• "Jellyfish" %c[red]completely negative\n%c[default]• "Thorn" %c[red]completely negative\n%c[default]• "Stone Blood" %c[green]completely positive\n%c[default]• "Droplet" %c[green]completely positive\n \n%c[default]by joint transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Fruit Punch" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]7-12 minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_dummy_puding_text"><text>\n \nThe "Pudding" endurance, burn, and electroshock resistance absolute is obtained from\nthe "Lunar Dummy" hypermodificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Fruit Punch" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 40 minutes to 1 Zone hour.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_dummy_fire_text"><text>\n \nThe "Fire Dummy" endurance and burn resistance modificate is obtained from\nthe "Dummy" artifact\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 10 to 30 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_dummy_bright_text"><text>\n \nThe "Bright Dummy" endurance and burn resistance mesomodificate is obtained from\nthe "Fire Dummy" modificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Fruit Punch" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 20 to 40 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_dummy_moon_text"><text>\n \nThe "Lunar Dummy" endurance and electricity resistance hypermodificate is obtained from\nthe "Bright Dummy" mesomodificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 30 to 50 Zone minutes.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_controller_skalp_text"><text>\n \nThe "Controller's Scalp" psi-protection, chemical burn, and bleeding resistance absolute is obtained from\nthe "Carapace" hypermodificate\nby transmutation in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner" anomaly.\n \n%c[default]Transmutation time is %c[green]from 40 minutes to 1 Zone hour.</text></string>
