<string id="rem_characters_0"><text>Childhood</text></string>
<string id="rem_characters_1"><text>Parents</text></string>
<string id="rem_characters_2"><text>School Years</text></string>
<string id="rem_characters_3"><text>After School</text></string>
<string id="rem_characters_4"><text>Army Service</text></string>
<string id="rem_characters_5"><text>After the Army</text></string>
<string id="rem_characters_6"><text>Family</text></string>
<string id="rem_characters_7"><text>Work Life</text></string>
<string id="rem_characters_8"><text>Life Stories</text></string>
<string id="rem_characters_9"><text>Arrival in the Zone</text></string>

<string id="character_vrach_0"><text>Maybe being alone in the Zone is worse than being in a group. And there are plenty of factions here. Surviving alone is hard. But for now I'm nobody here — what group would even need me? Nobody gives a damn about me. Well, let them… \nFrom early childhood. We were swimming somewhere in a shallow spot on a river, and suddenly everything went dark before my eyes, my ears filled with some dull gurgling sound, my nose and throat started burning. I didn't even have time to understand what had happened. Next thing I know, I'm standing waist-deep in the water, coughing and spitting. Mucus and tears all over my face… I was terrified back then, and nobody noticed a thing. It hurt so much! Everyone kept swimming like nothing had happened. Some women were sunbathing on the shore, and there I was, standing and crying. How could they not notice that I almost drowned? It was me, not someone else — I was drowning… And they just went on! The fear passed instantly, only resentment remained. What the hell — so I was nobody to them, nobody cared about me, nobody paid attention, they just didn't give a damn! That's where the tears came from…</text></string>

<string id="character_vrach_1"><text>You should never let your health fall, as they say, “below the baseboard.” In the Zone this is especially obvious… If you don't recover in time, if you don't maintain your health properly at all, even the bite of some miserable tushkano can be deadly… \nProbably all parents want their child to grow up strong, smart, rich, healthy. Everyone has their own priorities; my parents' priority was health. “Health is what matters most, everything else will follow… take care of your health while you're young… you can't buy health…” and so on. I think they were unlucky. As long as I can remember, we had a paralyzed grandmother at home — my father's mother. A living reminder that health can't be bought. Parents were always at work, no time. My father was some kind of boss — meetings, conferences… my mother worked shifts at a factory. So it was up to me to bring my grandma water, fix her pillow, do this, do that. My parents probably suffered with her themselves, which is why they kept repeating: health comes first. Maybe they were afraid for me, that I'd end up like that, or afraid for themselves, that the same fate might await them and I'd have to suffer with them later… And I even liked playing “doctor.” “What a good boy. Such a good boy.”…</text></string>

<string id="character_vrach_2"><text>The tongue, as they say, will get you all the way to Kyiv. Talkers aren't liked in the Zone, of course, but sometimes it doesn't hurt to get someone talking — maybe they'll point out a path or blurt something out about a stash. The main thing is to ask the right question, so you actually get an answer instead of being told to piss off… \nSomething from my school years: the schoolyard and some young reporter from a factory. Very businesslike, with a microphone and a tape recorder, preparing a radio program for February 23, asking us questions as future defenders of the motherland, recording our answers… “What would you like to be when you grow up, boy?” — that was me. And what did I answer? That I wanted to be a fighter pilot, but my parents said it would be better to be a doctor. So if that's the case, I'd like to be a doctor too, to help people stay healthy. The woman smiled nicely in response. Later, when my parents heard my answer on the radio, they were proud of me for choosing two such good professions… And I was so proud of myself for answering that silly question so nicely!</text></string>

<string id="character_vrach_3"><text>Is heroism necessary in the Zone? A rhetorical question. For what, for whom? It's not Stalingrad behind you. Just because you can't do otherwise? But here, like everywhere else, pointless heroism often looks like stupidity, and more often it's better to lie low and not show off your bravery… \nMy first shift in the ward, right after graduating from the institute. Lots of patients, including critical ones, and I'm alone… everyone else had vanished somewhere. A call to a room — an elderly woman, a frail old lady, started crashing. I run in — shallow breathing, thready pulse, check the blood pressure — zero. I shout to the nurse to call resuscitation, urgently! I turn back to the old woman — her eyes roll back, no pulse, silence in the carotid arteries. Damn it, my first trial by fire! Clear the room, tilt the head back, mask on the face, two breaths mouth-to-mouth… compress, compress, compress… breath… compress, compress, compress… Then, through some haze, I realize the resuscitation team has arrived, adrenaline administered, they wheel her out on a gurney, there's a pulse, they say she'll make it. I didn't want to stand out, of course, I was just doing my job, I wasn't thinking about how it looked from the outside. Only later did I imagine how I must have looked like a hero in other people's eyes. I strutted around like a peacock for a while, proud of myself — first time, and straight into heroics. And if I hadn't done anything, nobody would've blamed me — first shift, what could they expect — and nobody would've even noticed, plenty of fresh graduates wandering around…</text></string>

<string id="character_vrach_4"><text>So many fools with guns here, like it's some kind of hot zone! And not all of them even served in the army, many never held a weapon before. Not only can they accidentally kill someone, but they'll maim themselves out of inexperience… \nI never served in the army myself. But after my internship I worked for a while at a military hospital near a garrison town. Mostly conscripts, career soldiers, contract servicemen, military pensioners, and various others through connections. Routine work, but one case stuck with me. We were called out to a shooting range. Some soldier with a gunshot wound — looked like a self-inflicted one. We arrived quickly — about ten kilometers from the range to the hospital — but it was clear right away we had to rush him. We took off with sirens, and as luck would have it, rain started pouring down, the road was dark and slick. I'm monitoring his condition inside the ambulance and shouting to the driver through the window: “Step on it, Kolya, step on it, we won't make it otherwise!” The driver did great, squeezed everything he could out of that van. But then, at a turn, right before the checkpoint, a truck flies into the intersection… I catch sight of it out of the corner of my eye, and of our second vehicle coming up behind us, and I realize we won't stop in time. Then the impact — and darkness… Later they told me the driver died on the spot, I was thrown through the windshield and lost consciousness. I was lucky, as I often was in life. Somehow special. Everyone later kept clicking their tongues around me — lucky bastard… And our self-shooter was strapped to the gurney with safety belts, which saved him that day. The second crew picked him up and rushed him straight to intensive care, while they scraped us off the asphalt… They said he survived in the end, though I don't know if he was happy about it…</text></string>

<string id="character_vrach_5"><text>What's better in the Zone — being quiet and unnoticed, or decisive and brazen? Everyone decides for themselves. On one hand, staying unnoticed gives you an advantage when you need to bypass an enemy or save ammo… But decisiveness sometimes lets you prevail even when you're low on ammunition. Sometimes you have to push straight through, brazenly, or you won't make it in time… \nOne of my operating days while on duty. I was first assistant in surgery, standing closest to the screen around the operating field. A difficult case. As they say, “the patient is more dead than alive,” and nobody would have blamed us if things went wrong… They administer anesthesia, breathing mask, the whole thing, and suddenly I see our lead surgeon going pale. Why? It's obvious he's getting faint, his hands weakening. Overexposed himself near the anesthesiologist, maybe. They're usually used to it, but why him? Things happen, sure. Every surgeon has their own cemetery grown from failed operations — it's inevitable. But I didn't want to be part of that. Why the hell should I be death's assistant? I had to take matters into my own hands… Everything worked out, thank God. Our doctor came to, they brought him hot tea with sugar. And me? Even though I proved myself, I still spent half the day walking on shaking legs… But it taught me not to leave the line of attack. It showed me that I could do something despite everything, that decisiveness matters, that even death backs down before it… If I had stayed passive back then, we wouldn't have saved him…</text></string>

<string id="character_vrach_6"><text>Everyone in the Zone waits for luck. Everyone believes that sooner or later it will smile on them. You walk for months, searching and searching — nothing, and then suddenly! There it is, the coveted artifact! And right next to it — a bust, radioactive, can't carry it… \nWe waited a long time for a child. Wanted one, prepared ourselves, dreamed, got ready… And nothing. Examinations showed everything was fine, but for some reason God wouldn't grant us one. And finally it happened! Joy and… no, not grief, but some kind of shock, disappointment, confusion — why, why us? Our son was born with a congenital defect. We were told not to expect much time. But I told myself, and then convinced my wife: “Everything will be fine, we'll pull him through, I have connections… and I can finally do something myself. Me — and I won't manage?!” I've helped so many, pulled so many back — what, I won't raise my own son? I'd do anything for him. And it worked, at least he lived far longer than the time we were given. There was pride in myself for managing it, pride in him for being stronger than circumstances, and great hope that luck would keep following us… But luck never comes alone. Luck and a bust — a sweet couple, always together, beyond the perimeter and here in the Zone…</text></string>

<string id="character_vrach_7"><text>How many drugs does a person need in the Zone not to croak? You have to swallow pills by the handful here. Your liver will give out faster from them than from vodka… \nMy neighbor had a two-year-old son. I remember he was constantly being admitted to the hospital and discharged again — breathing problems. She talked to me about him, and I even offered my help, but for some reason she refused. Something bothered her about it. One day she had to call an ambulance, and later I called to check how things were. Her son was in critical condition, and instead of treating him, the doctors told her to brace herself… And what did I do then? Oh right! She needed some medication… What was it called, damn it, I remembered the name back then. I worked at a hospital at the time, just a different one… And I got the medication after all, not entirely legally, nearly got a case opened. But that's not the point — the point is her son started recovering. It was almost my own case… Her husband later did everything for me: fixed my car, got spare parts, even whitewashed my ceiling for free once. Her parents told me every time we met: “We tell everyone what a wonderful doctor you are.” And I told them: “Oh come on, it's nothing,” as if I'd treated him myself… Silly, but it felt good — something rose in my chest, like I really was a good person. And confidence that my own son would be fine too…</text></string>

<string id="character_vrach_8"><text>What are artifacts really worth? Here they're all described and priced, used like a handful of coins or a piece of metal. But they're a miracle of nature! How can you put a price on an artifact that can make a sick person healthy? How do you measure a return to a healthy life in money?.. \nA very recent event: someone close to me had a hard time after surgery, even though top doctors from Moscow promised a quick recovery. And there he lay in intensive care in our small town, covered in electrodes, catheters, and all sorts of medical gear keeping life going somehow. Our only hope was the ICU doctors — that all he needed was support, and then he'd pull through on his own. Every day I brought him fresh homemade broth for tube feeding. And one day, coming in with a thermos, I joked with the on-duty doctors about how tasty the broth was. And I realized they had nothing to say — they looked at me, and their eyes said only one thing: sorry, we did all we could. “No!” I shouted and ran into the room. My son lay there, his hand was cold, and his eyes would never look at me again… I would have given anything then to find that magical artifact that brings the dead back to life, if such a thing existed. Maybe I'll still find it…</text></string>

<string id="character_vrach_9"><text>People don't come to the Zone just to wander around out of boredom. They come here deliberately, for something very specific — only everyone for their own reasons… \nWhat brought me to the Zone? My son, the memory of him… Of course. This thought won't leave me alone, it gnaws at me. Why?! But I'll do anything, no matter the cost, I'll overcome death… With doctors this often happens: this feeling that you're above death, stronger than it, and the desire to prove that these hands and this mind can save and turn death away — not some clerk or moneybag… It doesn't matter who you are — a powerful banker or a “trembling creature,” before death everyone is equal. Everyone but me! I can do it! I remember my last conversation with my wife. “Don't blame yourself, what can you do? You won't bring him back, don't indulge in illusions, we knew from the beginning…” I didn't listen to her. What was the point? I was already thinking about the man waiting for me near the perimeter, ready to guide me into the Zone for a certain price. The sum was unbearable for me at the time, I had to sell many things, my wife was deeply disappointed in me — but what does that matter? For me it was a one-way ticket. Either I make it and everything happens the way I want, or… or we meet again there… “Are you listening to me? Get all these fairy tales out of your head. What are you going to do? You can't overcome death…” She had accepted it. I hadn't… And I'm leaving — it's time, he won't wait long… I'll make it, I'll find it, I can do it…</text></string>

<string id="character_botan_0"><text>The Zone doesn't like chatterboxes and teaches you not to talk more than you have to. If you know something, keep quiet, or even pretend you don't know, or can't say — it'll cost you less... \nAs a kid I kind of stuttered, or maybe just spoke badly — something like that. Until about six years old, I think. They teased me because I was tongue-tied, and I just shut down and ran off somewhere away from the yard — I couldn't answer properly or stand up for myself. I'd sulk alone for a while there, talking to myself. Oh, I could say a lot to myself, or to an imaginary companion! That helped me cool off, not hold onto resentment for too long. And then I'd come back... But not for long. It happened again and again... Where was that? Somewhere in the central part of the country, in our city. Maybe even back then I liked writing things down more than speaking...</text></string>

<string id="character_botan_1"><text>Why is the Zone full of all kinds of scum? What draws them here? And even more outright idiots and fools with peashooters — an absurd concentration per square meter... \nPeople like to blame negative personality traits on childhood trauma. They say it's all the parents' fault. Didn't love enough, didn't understand enough, didn't raise you right. So they're to blame... Nonsense. If you're a bastard or an idiot in life, don't dump it on your parents. And yet I had parents too. My mother worked at a school, my father was some kind of specialist at a classified facility. And it feels like they did understand me, raise me, love me. We lived in a nice little house on the outskirts of town. Or maybe it was all the opposite, and I just wanted to believe it was like that... I can't remember their faces at all — it's all a blur...</text></string>

<string id="character_botan_2"><text>Here in the Zone you're always waiting for something. You wait for dawn, you wait for a call from someone, you wait for an emission... Always waiting, waiting for something... \nA school memory: September, me sitting on a bench in front of the school. The sign “School No. 2” still slightly crooked. Behind the fence a blue dress flashes by, like a bright summer flower among withered grass. It's her. The guys told me I was wasting my time waiting — she wouldn't talk to me, why would she need a kid who can't even string two words together. I could write beautifully, though — in letters at least. Oh, how I could write, I was a smart, well-read boy. But talking scared me. Maybe she would've spoken first, but I was afraid to even approach — I didn't know what to say or how. And yet I waited every day, hoping she'd notice and start the conversation herself... Damn, it was so long ago, I don't even remember her name anymore. Then some loudmouth who never read a book just walked up, babbled his nonsense, grabbed her, and took her away. Just like that. It hurt. But he acted — he didn't wait like I did... And I've been waiting my whole life, just like now...</text></string>

<string id="character_botan_3"><text>What do you need to survive in the Zone — intelligence, diligence, courage, strength?.. Nothing of the sort. From what I see, you need cunning, flexibility, a lack of principles... And why is it so unfair? The smart and honest one fails, the sly and shameless one thrives... \nI was applying to university. The competition was fierce — the department was run by very prominent scholars. Getting in was difficult, a serious institution. But if you worked hard, you could get into research quickly, with good supervisors and real academic growth. Vasily applied with me — I even remember his name. Thick as a plank. I lived over textbooks, crammed theory... I passed the competition, hooray. And then I see him in my year. How? “You gotta know how, old man.” Later I practically lived in libraries, gnawed through the granite of science, earned my topic, nurtured it like a child. And he spent his time at discos and bars — you never saw him around. Then I meet him again: “Still sweating over your topic? I've already started my candidate thesis... Similar topic, almost like yours.” What? Why? My topic. “Fast times, old man. You gotta hustle. Nothing personal. First come, first served.” How does he slither everywhere like an eel? I'll never believe he earned it himself. He's nothing. I still don't understand this injustice. Just like I don't understand it now...</text></string>

<string id="character_botan_4"><text>There are strange underground laboratories in the Zone. What were they doing there? And what did they achieve? The Zone's mystery... \nThe laboratory where I started worked on developing supposedly harmless pesticides and herbicides. That's what it was called. Maybe that was the official focus. What I do know is that our department, under that cover, was engaged in military research. I had doubts at first — after all, we were creating death with our own hands. Not the death of one or two people, but on a far greater scale. Even then I understood what that substance could do if released, accidentally or deliberately. But I convinced myself. I was ready to justify anything. I'm a scientist, I deal in pure science — how can I control everyone who wants to use advanced research for selfish purposes? Should we stop developing aviation because military aircraft exist? Stop developing energy because bombs exist? Nonsense. And most importantly — I had a promising topic, unexplored territory, and I began. Yes, Herr M?ller and Mr. Smith had already achieved results. But I would prove we were worth something too. Even without their money, their backing, their laboratories, their plush offices and equipment. I would achieve no worse results. And I would have it all too...</text></string>

<string id="character_botan_5"><text>The Zone constantly puts you under stress. Even when everything seems fine, there's still this persistent anxiety, like you're late for something... \nThe contract deadline was approaching, and I still needed my project supervisor's approval before submitting the paperwork. I waited in the office, but he was late. Time kept slipping away, so I went to find him for the signature. I remember clearly — some hotel, in Moscow. Everything there is hotels now, all Western-style. We were attending a scientific conference and at the same time trying to push our ideas into production. A friend arranged a consultancy position for me at a solid firm and dragged me along to a “forum.” In reality — a free trip, blowing generous allowances on bars and women. Some people know how to settle in. Makes you envious. I don't remember much of that time, but I remember the feeling — the same as now. I was nervous, afraid of being late, afraid of losing such a lucrative position over a stupid mistake. Just like now — always afraid of not making it somewhere important...</text></string>

<string id="character_botan_6"><text>There are no women in the Zone. And that's how it should be. Imagine a stalker heading into danger with his girlfriend nearby — impossible. She wouldn't let him go, and he wouldn't dare leave her alone. Here, nothing distracts you, nothing ties you down. You can focus on your work... \nI never had much time for women. Serious science leaves no room for courtship, movies, restaurants — eventually not even for family. For a long time I noticed no one. Somehow I still got married. Not out of love — it was just necessary. Everything happened quickly. A modest wedding, small circle, no pomp. Then a semblance of family life. But I was always busy — lab, institute, production facilities. And then it happened. Someone had to take my place eventually. I could've forgiven a lot, but that it was him... Him. That talentless office rat with nothing to do with science. How could she choose him? Because of connections? A fancy apartment? Trips south on someone else's money? I couldn't forgive it. I left. Threw myself into work. And nothing tied me down anymore...</text></string>

<string id="character_botan_7"><text>I've learned that much knowledge is useless in the Zone. Here, you need to know how to survive — everything else is excess. Ironically, you know plenty, just not what matters... \nFor a while I worked at a publishing house. Once I reviewed an important scientific article — plenty of data from reputable sources, but missing what truly mattered. I tore into the whole department — accuracy is everything. I had authority back then, ran a department. It wasn't some magazine, but a serious scientific journal. I even stepped away from research for a time — just to prove I could succeed like others. Funny now, but back then I was respected and well-off. Tell that here and they'll ask: how does that help you survive in the Zone? Maybe I should've worked in travel magazines or military journals instead...</text></string>

<string id="character_botan_8"><text>The Zone is full of windbags and chatterers. Ask them anything and they'll talk endlessly — except about what you need. Stupid stories, pointless jokes. Nothing useful... \nI worked in many offices. Some were comfortable, quiet. I left them all. No scientific prospects. If you chase money instead of results, you live comfortably — but not me. Comfort softens the mind. Get used to it and you stop striving. That's death for a scientist. When I left my last job, some tried to stop me, others pitied me. Most just thought I was crazy. “Aiming for a Nobel... Lone mad professor...” They don't understand. They staffed whole departments with idlers, half with bought degrees or connections. One shallow article a month — and they act like giants of science. A real scientist achieves results through continuous work, not talk. Same in the Zone — you can brag about artifacts without owning a single one, and still earn a reputation...</text></string>

<string id="character_botan_9"><text>How do people come to the Zone? And why? And how did I?.. \nNikolai Antonovich arranged everything at my insistence. He resisted, but I convinced him. “There are more prospects here. What will you do there? Results reach us anyway. Why this pointless heroism?” He didn't understand that we only receive crumbs from the Zone, while the best is taken by those quicker. He was old school. I used to think theory alone would bring success. It doesn't. Others seize the opportunity. And I needed to prove that I mattered too — that success isn't only connections and stolen degrees. Only the Zone could prove it. He signed reluctantly. Inspections, paperwork, signatures — and suddenly I was a field researcher in the exclusion zone, full of hope... Fool. Antonych was right — heroism and hardship lead nowhere...</text></string>

<string id="character_oper_0"><text>You never know where or when you'll find an artifact in the Zone. Sometimes you go for days without a single one, and then suddenly there's a whole bunch at once, like apples fallen from a tree... \nWhen I was a kid, we lived in a settlement somewhere in the south. The whole settlement was surrounded by apple orchards. In autumn, after the harvest, there were still plenty of apples left on the trees. Then the orchards were opened to anyone who wanted to come in. Everyone gathered apples — all kinds. My brother, my parents, and I too. All winter long the house smelled of fragrant apples. Once I found a box that had been kept for some reason. Inside, every apple was wrapped in paper, yet the smell was incredible. The box was full — take even a couple and it would be noticed. So I took a bite out of each one and wrapped them back up. The illusion of wholeness. Funny... My brother probably still lives there, still picking apples. And here I am, gathering my own harvest...</text></string>

<string id="character_oper_1"><text>Sometimes you need to get from one end of the Zone to the other. Ammo's low, and there's nowhere to buy more along the way. The road itself isn't what wears you down — it's the poverty, constantly counting rounds one by one... \nI trained at a sports school and even traveled to competitions all over Russia. Once there were either competitions or training camps at the other end of the country — almost in Vladivostok. Then a telegram arrived. My father had fallen ill, they said, be ready to come. I really didn't want to, but I started preparing anyway. Then suddenly, a week later — or maybe longer — I got a letter from my father. He was feeling better. I brightened up instantly. But to be honest, I wasn't happy about his recovery — I was happy I didn't have to go anywhere. I didn't have a penny for such a trip, or rather I did, but it was set aside for something else, and the ticket price was outrageous. And going off to the middle of nowhere just to say something, offer sympathy... what was the point? Or maybe it was the other way around — maybe I lived there and they were somewhere in the west... Doesn't matter. Now I'd rush anywhere, just to know that at least someone is waiting for me.</text></string>

<string id="character_oper_2"><text>In the Zone everyone hides something. For a rainy day, for later, for the future, just in case of “nuclear war.” There's probably no one who doesn't stash something. And if you find someone else's stash, consider yourself lucky — rehide it and count it as yours. That's standard Zone practice. Means it was poorly hidden to begin with... \nBack in school we played “cops and robbers.” I was always a cop — I didn't like being a robber. Everyone chipped in with whatever they could, two candies from home, a chocolate bar, something like that. We organized a “bank.” Then, as usual, the “gang” robbed it and hid the loot again. The cops had to find it using notes and clues... I found it first, because I ignored their stupid hints like “go here, go there.” I knew the gang leader, Vovka, knew his habits, and figured out where they'd hide it. Then came the arguments — why I didn't search with everyone, why I knew everything in advance, accusations of cheating... And so on. But the main question was — why was there so little left in the bank? Well, I found it first, so I get the prize. Or at least I “confiscate” half — I'm a cop, I have the right. What do the others have to do with it? The “robbers” could've taken their share and left half behind. Since they didn't, that means I took it. Winner takes the prize. I found it myself, fair and square — so it's mine.</text></string>

<string id="character_oper_3"><text>Life is a strange thing. You never know what's waiting the next minute. You think everything's planned out, but fate has completely different ideas. Just like here in the Zone. You never know which side it'll turn next... \nI wanted to become a programmer, applied to... what was it... LETI — that's it. I had the score, there were openings, everything seemed to line up — but no. Not fate. Or rather, I wasn't from St. Petersburg, I was an outsider. They made it clear right away — don't even try. I bounced around a few places and ended up in a technical college. Became a technician... refrigeration systems, I think. Compressors maybe. Doesn't matter now — it wasn't meant to be. In the end it never came in handy anyway, and I chose something completely different later, after the army. If I'd known how things would turn out, I'd have become a lawyer, a banker, a dentist — or better yet some deputy on a financial committee. Bought a house in London... or lived by the sea in a villa, maybe even on my own yacht. Ah, my poverty...</text></string>

<string id="character_oper_4"><text>Vodka is bad — everyone says that. Or rather, drinking is bad, but vodka itself is a necessary thing in the Zone... \nWhere did it all start for me... In the army. Somewhere in the northwest. Only six months left — complete relaxation, golden army days. We liked to drink on the sly. Drivers went to Pskov and managed to stash a couple of bottles in the fuel tank. Brought them back without a problem. Then came the partying... Vodka was good currency in the army too, just like here. I joined later than most — at twenty. By then I was already twenty-two and a senior sergeant. That meant I got more — they poured for me, brought it to me by rank. And I was happy to take more, fool that I was. Better not to remember — it took me two years back in civilian life to kick the habit. But thank God it worked out — I didn't drink myself to ruin... I think. I hope that's not why I ended up here without memories...</text></string>

<string id="character_oper_5"><text>There are generators at Zone bases — useful machines, but they need fuel. And where do you get it? You can siphon leftovers from old gas stations and haul it in jerrycans, if you're not lazy, and even get rewarded for it... \nAfter the army I went to police school and ended up serving in criminal investigation in a very small, quiet Siberian town. All local crime boiled down to cattle theft and drunken village brawls. Life was calm. Then suddenly — an incident. A villager's vehicle was stolen: an IZH motorcycle with a sidecar. Our “informant,” a homeless guy named Vasya, pointed to a local kid. The bike was hidden at an apiary. We arrived — it was in a shed, no one around. So what do we do? Set up an ambush. A village ambush is something special: padded jackets, vodka, lard, all the tourist delights. They took me along “for practice.” The guys waited, drank, snacked, offered me some. “No, I'm off it.” Out of boredom I checked the shed and found four full jerrycans of gasoline. I kept quiet — figured I'd confiscate them later without fuss. One day passed, then another. Supplies ran out twice. No one to relieve us — five people in the department, two of them bosses. So I had to run to the store. And I carried those jerrycans twice — five kilometers, one in each hand. Nearly tore my arms off. They caught the kid later, boxed his ears — he confessed. I kept quiet about the gas. He didn't complain either...</text></string>

<string id="character_oper_6"><text>Why is it always raining in this Zone? You never get decent weather, like it doesn't exist at all. And the worst is when it's raining and dark... \nOnce I had to go somewhere urgently at night. The weather was awful — October in the north always is. Somewhere near St. Petersburg. We were about to go on vacation to Karelia with the whole crew. Pooled our money, but the trip fell through and I had to take my share back. The guys were upset — everything planned and bought already, stop counting pennies. “I paid in, now I need it back urgently.” They took offense. Whatever. I got in the car and drove. Fog, cold, drizzle, darkness. On a turn the car skidded. I hit the brakes, but it kept sliding. Stopped about fifty meters later. And there he was — a man right by the car, pale as a sheet. He cursed me out. I was shaking myself — arms, legs. But I still made it to the station. Right — I was meeting my wife. Valya. Or maybe not my wife yet... Or was it Lyuska? No — Valya already. For sure.</text></string>

<string id="character_oper_7"><text>Dogs, dogs everywhere... Damn them. Not a Zone, a kennel. Should shoot all those bitches so they don't multiply like that... \nOnce we entered a private house for a search. I tore my jacket climbing the fence — tall, brand new, nails not bent down. Ripped the sleeve clean. The jacket was brand new too. Inside, a dog rushed us, my hand went for the weapon on reflex. I barely had time to rack the slide when the owner threw herself in front of the dog. I lost it — either from anger at the dog or frustration over the jacket and pointless expenses. Fired a warning shot and yelled, not sure at whom: “Freeze! I'll shoot!” She froze, stared, then sat down on the ground. Must've looked impressive. Later I couldn't explain my anger to the guys. What was I supposed to say — that I felt that bad about a jacket? They'd say I was stingy. But I'm not greedy. I've just always been careful with money...</text></string>

<string id="character_oper_8"><text>In the Zone almost everyone has a PDA. People think a simple password makes it a safe. So they store stash coordinates, hideouts, negotiation records. Idiots. Life teaches them nothing — keep that on a PDA and you'll get burned fast, lose everything you earned... \nI pull up to headquarters, park as usual. Quietly walk along, peek into the first-floor windows of the narcotics unit. Suddenly — a screech of metal. A window flies open and an operative named Shurik jumps out, folder in one hand, something like a hard drive in the other. Inside it's chaos. I've seen SOBR units, but seeing these guys tear through our own offices was something else. Our people stand along the wall, eyes down. Men in gray suits rummage through offices, sealed computers everywhere. And the deputy chief's look burns into my skull: “Get the hell out and hide, idiot.” I didn't argue. Locked myself in, swept all the “extra” into a trash bag — cognac, boxes, envelopes, notes. Dumped the important files to a flash drive, set the disk to format — something broke, not my fault. Threw the bag out the window and followed Shurik's trail. That day the narcotics unit was smashed. A few heads rolled, the rest got off easy — two severe reprimands. All thanks to Shurik clearing the evidence from under the all-seeing eye. I played it safe — and learned not to trust machines.</text></string>

<string id="character_oper_9"><text>Most people come to the Zone for quick money. What pulled me in? Probably the same thing... \nI learned about the Zone from a wheeler-dealer we once worked over. He called himself a stalker. During a search we found strange trinkets — that's when he told us. By then I'd already left regional HQ. Didn't get along with certain people — or rather, I was pushed out for not sharing. Transferred to a district department. My wife kept warning me: stop taking bribes, they'll set you up next. And she was right. Someone high up stole big and got caught. They pulled the thread — the whole system unraveled. Inspections everywhere. I was clean, but something surfaced anyway. They needed scapegoats. I was one of them. Not only did the bosses walk away with a scare, they turned out to be vindictive too. Remembered I hadn't shared once. I was pushed out of the system. But life goes on — loans, expenses. I told my wife it was a break, a vacation, a reset. And in the back of my mind: six months is enough. Money's lying on the ground, just don't be lazy. Main thing is carrying the loot out. That's a stalker word I learned. Met the stalker, planned the trip. He owed me anyway. That's how I ended up in the Zone. Dreams... “Carry the loot out.” How stupid. I should just be able to carry myself out of here...</text></string>

<string id="character_bandit_0"><text>Boldness is a second kind of luck. That rule works everywhere, and here in the Zone too. Only here you also need a sense of proportion, so you don't overdo it — otherwise, in response to excessive boldness you might get a very small but very heavy olive flying your way... \nFrom childhood: I was the smallest kid in the yard, but also the boldest. I could charge at some big lout like a little mutt at an elephant. The older guys used that — for them it was free entertainment. “Hey, Tushkanchik, go sell that runt a cigarette butt… And if anything, hit him straight in the face — we're nearby… heh-heh-heh.” And I'd sell it, and slap him in the face with my palm, hopping up comically because otherwise I couldn't reach. And behind me laughter and approving pats on the shoulder: “Good job, Tushkanchik, small but gutsy — that's how it should be,” and a candy or some gum as a reward… Then we moved away, those guys weren't around anymore, and I sort of “settled down.” But that idea — that you can achieve something with sheer boldness — stuck in my head. You don't need to be strong or smart, you need to be brave and cheeky. Just like here in the Zone…</text></string>

<string id="character_bandit_1"><text>In the Zone it's nothing but thieves everywhere. You have to count every penny — and if only pennies, every single round has to be counted too. You save and save, but one day some mug can just take everything you earned with blood and sweat, without even asking… \nWe lived poorly. I couldn't afford jeans or sneakers, I didn't have a player. I had serious complexes because of that, bugged my parents, kept asking: “Why do others have all this and we don't?” They tried to do something — well, my mother did. My father was useless, a drunk who dragged everything out of the house. My mother locked all the cupboards. She didn't give me pocket money, of course, but she bought me some clothes. Only decent clothes cost decent money, and that was exactly what we lacked, so it didn't work out well. My father was a simple plumber, always drunk or hungover, and my mother was either a painter or a plasterer… In short, money was always tight, so we had to tremble over every penny — just like now…</text></string>

<string id="character_bandit_2"><text>In the Zone the main thing is not to gape and not to think too long — grab it and run, that's the principle, and we'll sort it out later… \nEither during school or on vacation, me and the guys used to sneak through a hole in the fence into a factory near our house. We'd steal all kinds of junk from the crates on the grounds. You run from the guard, and all you hear are his stones whistling past your ears like bullets… And at the same time you feel fear and some kind of excitement. It was like a test — if you hadn't climbed the fence and stolen something right in front of the guard, then you weren't a real guy. And the factory itself was nothing special — a toy factory, they made wooden rocking horses or ones on wheels. Or no… that was in another city. In this one there was some garage complex or a mechanical column… Yeah — Communications Mechanical Column No. 4. I even wondered back then what kind of “fur column” that was — something with fur, maybe… That's when I started stealing.</text></string>

<string id="character_bandit_3"><text>How do people live here? If you look closely, artifacts aren't even the top priority for many. You can live in the Zone without them, doing something else. Some hunt, some steal, some sell information, some trade second-hand clothes… \nThe beginning of my “working” life was right after school. Adult life started, but studying was beyond me, and working was too much effort. I suddenly realized you could make money through simple speculation. Somehow it dawned on me that it wasn't necessary to bust your back from bell to bell. I started trading clothes, slipping into some semi-criminal world. I even came up with an ideological platform for myself, a slogan to justify it: “Living on one salary is for suckers!” It seemed like those who worked at factories were just idiots and losers. Yeah, back then my buddy and I decided we needed to leave for free Europe, or even better, America. Sanyok kept buzzing in my ears — that's where freedom of choice is, freedom of business, freedom of doing nothing! And I wasn't against getting out of that crappy little town myself, if only I had the means… That's how it goes — you dream of one thing and get another, what you deserve. The Zone, for example…</text></string>

<string id="character_bandit_4"><text>I don't understand what soldiers are doing in the Zone. It's not service, it's killing time. What will they remember later? How they scammed passing stalkers for vodka? They'll forget it all as soon as they get out of here… If they're lucky enough to get out… \nAfter school I got drafted into the army too. I had no desire whatsoever, I dodged as best I could, but… At the nearby communications mechanical column we were constantly pulling cables, got familiar faces there, sometimes they even grabbed us by the hand, but somehow we managed to snatch things. We burned it, sold the copper — made pocket money somehow. Once we dragged off a whole coil, managed to tear it apart quickly, otherwise we'd have been caught — turned out a massive phone network expansion was planned. Then suddenly some inspection hit, they started digging into who was stealing copper and cable. There were plenty of their own thieves there, but they needed someone to dump all the losses on… A guy came to me, worked as a driver there. He treated me well. We talked. Basically he made it clear: “If you don't get lost somewhere, they'll pin everything on your gang. You're already eighteen, can't hide behind being minors anymore — think about it…” And right then another draft notice arrived: “With belongings and documents…” In short, the choice was simple — either run off to the army, and without a convenient scapegoat they'd find someone else, or get arrested and charged with theft. I didn't want to, of course, but I chose the first. That's how I ended up in the construction battalion… You couldn't really call it real service. But I somehow got through it and forgot it forever.</text></string>

<string id="character_bandit_5"><text>In general, life in the Zone isn't so bad, you can live if you've got a head on your shoulders and don't stick your nose into every hole. One problem though — women are in short supply… \nAfter the army I didn't have any job or any desire to get one. But I got lucky. Old connections helped. They put me to keep an eye on the girls. Walk them to clients, negotiate, smooth things over if someone started acting tough or offended our “swans.” I didn't stand on ceremony with women myself — took anyone who stirred something in me. I slept around left and right, just not with our own girls. The boss ordered not to damage the merchandise, otherwise you couldn't “put her back on the machine.” But one time I bent hard and he allowed it: pick any one of your own. I'd had my eye on one brunette for a while, waiting for a chance to get my hands on her… And I had a good time then. After that it became routine — in the end I touched them all. Kids? What kids would they have? And from others — no idea. I never planned to hang anyone around my neck and never thought about such nonsense…</text></string>

<string id="character_bandit_6"><text>There are places in the Zone so remote you'd better not go there alone. Maybe not monsters — but you twist your ankle and then what? Yell for help? Useless… To be heard you'd need a cast-iron throat. And even if they hear you, there's no guarantee anyone will come… \nI lived with one slut… She was nothing special, but at the time the main thing was having a roof over my head and somewhere to crash, I wasn't that interested in her. If I wanted, I could sleep with anyone. But she put up with me and I didn't completely ignore her. Sometimes I'd pull her close — after a couple of glasses… But her voice — holy hell. A real trumpet of Jericho! Once I was asleep when the cops showed up, and she was just going out into the yard. Quick thinker — she let the dog loose and started screaming: “Thieves! Thieves! Where are you going, you bastards!” Blocked the way, a real battle-axe. “May you rot, you monsters!..” And off she went… She did it on purpose so I'd hear — with a voice like a ship's horn, how could you not hear… I jumped up nearly to the ceiling from that beluga-like roar, looked into the yard, quickly figured things out, grabbed my stuff and dove out the back window. From there through the shed and across the gardens, through the gardens. I thought I was clean at the time, but who knows why they came — better safe than sorry… And I was right — someone had ratted me out. If she hadn't screamed, who knows where I'd have ended up…</text></string>

<string id="character_bandit_7"><text>Sometimes in the Zone you can find all kinds of papers, notes, little journals, albums… Seems like trash — wipe your ass and throw it away, but who knows what it is? Maybe someone really needs those papers and will pay well for them. Anything can happen… \nOnce we hit an apartment. I usually avoided outright criminal jobs. I preferred Bender's “honest” methods. But that time I got involved — really needed to. They took me into the team. We did everything clean — went in during the day, like it was our own place. Set up lookout signs around the address and worked calmly inside. Collected everything valuable and were about to leave. That's when I noticed a bookcase stuffed full of albums. Took a look — postage stamps. To me they were just bits of paper, some nonsense. I grabbed an album on impulse. The next day we split the take, I got my share, and went our separate ways… About a month later I was sitting with a fence, unloading some junk, and remembered the album. He got interested in it. Took it, flipped a couple of pages, nervously stood up and ran to the hallway for his glasses. Put them on and started greedily examining the stamps. Then he asked me: “W-where did you get THIS?!” I shrugged: “Picked it up at a flea market.” The fence got nervous: “Stop bullshitting! Who sells THIS at a flea market? Do you even know how much THIS is worth?!” He named a sum — probably lowballed it three times over. I sat there not showing a thing, but inside I was rolling dice in my head, remembering that bookcase full of the same albums, cursing myself for stupidity… But it was too late. Should've grabbed those papers right away…</text></string>

<string id="character_bandit_8"><text>It's a pity there are no cars in the Zone. Maybe you could get a ZIL running, but where would you go in it? You'd drive straight into some anomaly — sometimes you can't even walk along the road… \nAt one point I got into car theft. Nothing big-time, small stuff. I didn't mess with fancy Toyotas or Mercedes. Didn't touch cars belonging to well-known people either — mostly small fry. Serious cars weren't my niche. I took plain, unremarkable Zhigulis or some old Opels. Yeah, the payoff wasn't huge — they were only taken for parts. But I wasn't aiming for a big score, it was enough for me. And it was safer, less chance of exposure. Who's going to look for some pensioner's Zhiguli or a bread factory accountant's car? Nobody needs them. No one's going to bother with cases like that. And that's exactly what I wanted. Once I almost got burned. An old man left his Zhiguli in the yard and usually didn't lock it when going inside. He probably never even heard of alarms. I waited, counted in my head roughly how long it would take him to reach his third floor, and calmly went to take the car. And then the old man opens the building door and sees me. Turned out he'd forgotten something in the car. Not really a screw-up — that geezer wouldn't have caught me anyway… But unpleasant. I'd always been clean, never exposed myself, and then I almost got nailed… It worked out. And I lay low for a while.</text></string>

<string id="character_bandit_9"><text>There are idiots who go to the Zone willingly! Some even consider it romantic, interesting for them, supposedly… No way I'd have gone here if I hadn't been forced. I had to… \nI was never some hardened criminal. I just always knew how to pull things off cleverly so I never got exposed. I managed to arrange things so I didn't even have a single police record. I didn't want to end up behind bars, not at all. I had no desire to land in prison. And somehow my guardian angel watched over me. Until now. Fate, that bitch. I still ended up in the Zone. One way or another. He's probably laughing up there, looking down at me… I had to run. A buddy had just come back from one closed place — called the Zone. He explained: “The main thing is don't hesitate there. If someone comes at you with a gun, don't piss yourself — those stalkers only bluff, they'll be scared of you if you act right… Don't panic, it's not a real prison Zone, no guards, their own rules. But you still have to show yourself at first so they take you into a crew. Alone it's hell to survive, in a pack it's just right…” How I didn't want to go! But what choice did I have? The last warning was clearly the last — my whole body still hurts and my left eye only just opened… I was boxed in from all sides. Some demanded powder on time or else I was dead, others demanded money for it — same outcome if I didn't pay. And where was I supposed to get that much, and where to find that powder? Damn it, why did I get involved with drugs! If only I'd known what I was getting into… I told myself not to touch that stuff… And now I had to run, urgently. Because there was nowhere to go, nowhere to hide… I bought a gun from a buddy, paid him well for the tip, and went along the indicated path. That's how it went — I didn't want to go to prison, and ended up going to the Zone myself. Fate…</text></string>

<string id="character_spec_0"><text>In the Zone you have to kill people. Not because you want to, but because sometimes situations arise where if you don't kill, you'll be killed. But sometimes you see such scum that you start shooting first — not in self-defense, but because there's no sin in killing bastards like that... \nI tried real weapons very early. Very early. When I was a kid, my father constantly took me to the shooting range to fire an air rifle. I wasn't even in school yet — the rifle was bigger than me. He loaded it himself, held it, aimed it, all I had to do was pull the trigger. How happy I was when the bear fell headfirst or the mill started spinning! I rarely saw my father, so every meeting was a joy. One day he took me to a real shooting range... I had probably already started school by then, or maybe not. What got into his head — maybe he'd had a drink with Petrovich: “Want to shoot a revolver?” Of course I do! “Alright, Petrovich, calm down. A boy should know how to handle a weapon — he's a man, not a woman... I'll be right here, stop yelling...” One cartridge, my father behind me, holding my hand, then letting go: “Press smoothly, don't wave the barrel.” Bang! I got scared — I didn't expect such a blast, didn't expect my hand to jerk like that. And my father's laughter: “Don't yell, Petrovich. Well, what if he'd shot you — so what? There's no sin in shooting a goat like you... ha-ha, I'm joking, Petrovich.” For some reason I thought then that if I had killed that Petrovich, nothing would've happened to me. And I remembered my father's words: “you need to know how to handle a weapon” and “there's no sin in shooting a goat like that”...</text></string>

<string id="character_spec_1"><text>I wonder if controllers in the Zone have parents? They came from somewhere after all — not from a test tube, probably. And how did their parents control them?.. \nWe can't compare our parents to anyone — we only have them once, and for each of us they're usually the best. But I don't know whether I was lucky with mine. I remember some things, but not much: my father was from somewhere in the Baltics, my mother a Siberian. My father was practically a non-drinker, and my mother was constantly at work and always running late somewhere. That's basically it... There's also a feeling that my parents spoiled me too much. Maybe because they rarely saw me. Either work, or some tourist trip, or a business trip — one thing or another — and I was left in the care of my grandparents. Complete lack of supervision on their part — do whatever you want. But they always came back with gifts. So now you wonder whether I was lucky with them, or whether they were just dumping me as a burden, first on my grandmothers, then on my grandfathers. I hope I'll find out someday...</text></string>

<string id="character_spec_2"><text>For some reason long treks through the Zone don't exhaust me that much. As if I'm used to them... \nAt one of the schools where I studied, the biology teacher took our whole class on hikes outside the city. On foot across a field, with packs on our backs. Back then it was interesting — roasting potatoes in campfires, the forest... But we didn't go far then, and we didn't need to — a couple of kilometers from the city was enough. A small town, half an hour's walk and you're already in the woods outside it. And later in life I walked a lot too — forced marches in the army, and after the army as well. A familiar thing, in general... On one of those school hikes a girl kept whining: help me, it's heavy. Then the counselor or whatever she was called stepped in: “Well help Nastya, you're a strong boy, a man.” What the hell?! You knew what you were getting into, you asked to go on the hike yourself! What for — to walk light while others carry your stuff? No way! If you signed up, then carry it yourself... Here in the Zone there's no one to ask: carry my backpack. Everything on your own, only on your own. And that's fair...</text></string>

<string id="character_spec_3"><text>I wonder what soldiers are doing in the Zone? This isn't an armed conflict zone, not a border, yet they keep being sent here again and again. No conditions here, not even proper barracks... And they can't refuse or dodge — conscripts... \nAfter school I decided to apply to the nautical school of the White Sea–Baltic Shipping Company. Some relative of mine sailed, and his whole house was packed with imported equipment. I wanted all that too. I got into the school, it seems, without much trouble. But I didn't think I'd end up in barracks. The system was like this: you live in the barracks for two months, then for a year you're allowed to go home on Saturdays and Sundays, and later you can live at home altogether. Basically you just had to endure two or three months. But even that wasn't for me. In the barracks everything runs on brute rules. I didn't like anything there — their jokes, their interests, their talk, and especially the atmosphere. I don't remember how long I studied, but no more than a couple of weeks. My heightened sense of justice wouldn't have let me follow orders and daily routines any longer. I think I dodged it somehow and ended up dropping out... Now of course I regret it — you can't escape fate anyway — I still chose barracks in life. I should've endured it back then. I'd be sailing the seas, seeing the world, instead of trampling this rotten Zone...</text></string>

<string id="character_spec_4"><text>There's no place for weaklings in the Zone. That's as clear as two times two. I don't understand how unprepared people crawl into this hell. Some boys in tracksuits who haven't smelled real gunpowder, who are rookies and cowards in life, and yet as soon as they get a gun in their hands their fingers spread wide: “Hey man, come here, we need to talk.” It's even funny... \nIt was in the army. During basic training I stood out both in strength and agility. Naturally, the specialists noticed me. That's how I ended up in a special company. To say they drove us hard would be saying nothing — we were kept on a very tight leash. But I liked it. I liked the uniform, liked that pleasant exhaustion at the end of the day when you fall asleep dead, liked showing off in front of others... You'd walk past some motor pool — maroon beret tilted to the side so your forelock sticks out, top buttons undone so your neck shows, belt loosened... You could tell it was special forces from the second company of the fifth regiment. Anyone mouths off — straight in the face! It was hard, of course, some whined, some couldn't take it, but I endured because I knew — this was luck, a winning ticket. If I got through all this, in civilian life I'd be king and god! Who'd stand against me? In the face! Who's tougher than me? In the face! Anyone else disagree? In the face!.. There's no place for weaklings in life! Strength decides everything.</text></string>

<string id="character_spec_5"><text>Here in the Zone, at the slightest thing, idiots grab their weapons and start showdowns. Instead of stepping outside like men and settling it one on one. With fists, bare-chested. With a gun you're a hero. But try coming out without it. I'm sure in reality any lout wouldn't take even two punches... \nAfter the army I signed a contract. No surprise there. I'd learned a lot in the army, I could do a lot, I knew a lot. But all that knowledge wasn't for a peaceful, measured life. Specific skills require specific application. There was training for a while. We were stationed at so-called bases — basically camps. Discipline was there, of course, but from time to time we let loose — all young guys, hot-blooded... Once in a neighboring village the locals clashed with our guys in a club. Two of ours, including a buddy of mine, against almost the whole village, and our guys got beaten up. A stupid drunken village brawl... God, I was furious — my buddy, a specialist, beaten by some drunk villagers! We rolled up in a UAZ — eight of us. Not in uniform, but by our torsos it was clear we didn't wear out our pants in libraries. What could half-drunk men do against a special forces squad? We beat everyone in sight... I was kicking some big guy who was already on the ground, trying to smash his face, shouting: “That's for Andryukha.” From behind our driver was holding me and yelling in my ear: “Calm down, idiot, you've already broken everything he's got!..” Someone was badly maimed that day, maybe that big guy. But it worked out — our commander understood the situation, he didn't need extra noise himself, and he deliberately sent me away out of sight. “Pray to God you didn't kill anyone, idiots. And you — I see you've been idle too long. Tomorrow you're off to the point... You'll vent your righteous anger on the mountaineers there, not on the local village folk...”</text></string>

<string id="character_spec_6"><text>Why are there no women in the Zone? Seems like all women are fools, but no — they don't come here, so there's still a bit of reason in their heads... \nI realized back in my youth that you can't talk to women normally. One kept posturing in front of me. “I'm a bold girl, but persistent... I'm all this and that... What are you going to do to me... You're not a real man.” She thought I'd put up with it, or maybe she wanted to get under my skin — tried to provoke me. Fool! I hit her so hard she flew two meters. What did you expect, girl? You thought I'd listen to your jabs or melt looking at you?.. I landed it well back then, broke her nose... her own fault. Later, with my wife — I hit her too, without holding back. Sometimes Marishka wouldn't leave the house for a week, didn't know how to hide the bruises. And it was all deserved! Brainless hen! Let her go to the store alone — credits, loans... Money flew away like poplar fluff. And all that “blah-blah-blah” — we need to think about the kids, we need a dacha, we need a car, we need to think about the future... I had no strength left to endure it — we split up... After that I never married again, didn't find anyone for myself. Lived with one, then another, but never for long. And all because all women are the same, all fools...</text></string>

<string id="character_spec_7"><text>Sometimes someone points a gun at you and rasps something like “come here, just hide the gun,” or the other way around “get lost.” Blocks the way and thinks a Kalash will help him. Rambos, my ass! Don't stand in my way! All your Terminator crap lasts only so long — you might run into trouble... \nSomewhere in the mountains. When it was all over, we started counting losses. Three of ours — that we already knew. We pulled the enemy out of every hole and carried them to the center of the aul, or whatever they call their settlements... Laid them out in a row — about twenty bodies. There were old men and teenagers among them... What else could we do? War is war. Yes, maybe we could've avoided such a total sweep, but how would you sort them out? And why? They killed three of ours, they blew up a bridge before that and only a miracle saved me and the guys, they did a lot more — it had to be ended. For me they were all enemies, all of them. That old woman — she surely sheltered those bandits, fed them, gave them water, blessed them for a righteous war against infidels... Enemy! That boy — he brought some drink to the checkpoint in exchange for ammo, and later bullets from those same rounds, fired from their Kalashnikovs, came back to us... Enemy! That girl — she hung around, spying, drawing layouts of dugouts and firing points... Enemy! They're to blame themselves. They could've let us pass, could've come out and surrendered their weapons, but they stood in our way and had to pay for it. No, we weren't going to sort them — everything was done deliberately... How I hate them all!</text></string>

<string id="character_spec_8"><text>Should you help everyone who yells “Give me a medkit” in the Zone? You help him, and he'll shoot you in the back and take your loot on top of it. If you got yourself into trouble — that's your own fault, means you weren't meant to live. The Zone isn't for you. Nothing personal — the strongest survives, that's the law... \nIt was on some assignment: I crawled on my belly for two days. That's when the countdown started for me. I don't remember exactly what I'd signed up for. Everything was fine until the moment I saw that cursed message on the PDA. Back then I didn't even know who I was to them — a pursuer or prey. Or some mutant who'd crossed the most precious thing in life — human relations. What was I lacking? I had everything — respect, understanding, support, and most importantly, humane treatment from the guys, yet then I was like a cornered beast. I can still see it: sitting behind a boulder, counting the remaining rounds. It's scary to even think what I need that ammo for... But I want to eat, I want to live, and I'll kill again for this, even if miserable, life. I started noticing that with each day there were fewer enemies on my path. That's understandable — my resolve sharpened many times over, all my senses honed to understand... Understand what — I didn't know then. Just like now. I have no past now, a horrific present, and I don't even think about the future. And back then... back then I walked past a dying man. So what? I'm a modern fighter, soberly assessing my resources in a difficult situation. I had not a drop of sentimentality, humanity, or any of that crap that softens you... Yes. Just like now...</text></string>

<string id="character_spec_9"><text>Surely many come to the Zone voluntarily. They choose it themselves, no one forces them. But is there anyone who doesn't regret it later? And did I make the right choice by coming here?.. \nNo matter how badass a specialist you are, sooner or later you become “spent material.” And that's what I became. I never killed just for money — it was always a fight, an elimination operation, or self-defense... I don't even know why I agreed. Maybe I went for a big payout, or maybe I wanted something “spicy,” to play cat and mouse? Or finally use all my unused knowledge and skills to the fullest... I don't know. The job wasn't simple — the target was too prominent, always under guard, not easy to get close to. But I managed. I felt no remorse — nothing personal, it was work. Every person is worth something, and he was worth a lot... And then at some point I suddenly realized that I too was “worth” something. I felt it in my gut, a sixth sense — by the way the boss spoke to me, by how I was being “handled,” by the car parked nearby, by the apartment door left slightly ajar. I didn't go in, everything was clear. I was spent, I had to leave... Before departure Hawk gave instructions, talked about local customs, rules, factions, said where to attach myself right away, how to behave, what gear to take, how to survive. That didn't worry me — I can teach anyone how to survive myself. What worried me more was Hawk himself. Only he knew about my departure, I thought I could trust only him — but was that true? After everything, could I trust anyone at all? In any case I had no choice, someone had to get me through... And here I am in the Zone. Was it the right choice? Most likely. Who needs me out there, beyond the perimeter? There everything is clear for me: not me — then me, and sooner or later it would happen. And here... here I'm like a fish in water.</text></string>

<string id="character_hunter_0"><text>How many rounds do you need to wipe out all the monsters? An infinite amount. No matter how many you kill, they never seem to run out. Where do they even come from? It's easier to ignore them and try to keep your distance... \nWhen I was a kid, we used to go into the forest for blueberries or later for lingonberries. My parents always took me with them. My father would show me: “Look, a hare was nibbling its hare grass here, and here a bear's been — see the pile. Still fresh.” I remember thinking how he wasn't afraid, the bear had to be somewhere nearby... Then we came out to a river, and there was a bear on the other side, eating berries. Suddenly it stopped and stared at us. I almost screamed — that river was just a stream, no more than three meters across. My father whispered to me to stand still and not look straight at it, look a little to the side, don't pay it attention and don't make any sudden moves. The bear sniffed the air, waved its snout around, and went on along the bank. Later my father explained that it was full — plenty of berries, mushrooms, fish in the river — we weren't interesting to it unless we started bothering it ourselves. Every animal lives its own life, has its own animal concerns, and the last thing it thinks about is how to eat you; more likely it'll move away to stay out of trouble... Here in the Zone the beasts are special, but still, not every one of them sees you as lunch.</text></string>

<string id="character_hunter_1"><text>These Zone monsters are strange. Where do such mutations come from? That's heredity — it should take many generations. Although, who the hell really knows where their monstrous abilities come from... \nWe inherit things from our parents. I, for example, had some artistic talent. And a talent for music. I'm generally a fairly gifted person, as if I know a lot already from birth. Same with sensing things at a distance and knowing when and how to act. Somehow everything always came together naturally for me. Like now — I just feel where to go and what to do, that's it! I inherited this not even from my father, but from my grandfather. Yes — he used to pull off things like that... Though to me his tricks probably only seemed like miracles. Everything looks that way in childhood... When did he die? I was only about ten. He's buried somewhere in the south. We lived in the north, but apparently the south was his homeland — that's why he's buried there. Still, there's something about my perception, and it's not accidental — it's hereditary...</text></string>

<string id="character_hunter_2"><text>That's how it goes — you make a stash in the Zone, come back to check it, and some bastard has already shoved his own stuff in there with a note: “Mine. Anyone takes it — I'll kill them!” As if it was his stash all along. Isn't it low to pull crap like that?! And then he'll start arguing, asserting his rights... \nThere was an incident like that back in school days, in summer, at some kids' camp. One boy was the object of everyone's mockery. As it usually happens — the group silently picks an outcast they can bully without consequences. Among teenagers the main thing is to show yourself early on, so you don't become that one yourself. They bought a cake for someone's birthday, or some holiday — doesn't matter now... decided to eat it together after dinner. And my buddy and I were alone in the room. I said: “Let's put it under that loser's pillow. Everyone will start looking for the cake, we'll pretend to look too, and then — bam — I'll ‘accidentally' find it.” We did it... How he screamed afterward, tearing his throat: “It wasn't me, it wasn't me!” Choking on resentment — no words, smearing tears and blood over his face — someone had already hit him. We couldn't even get a word in, it all got sorted out without us. We just stood aside, kept quiet, stared out the window, because we couldn't raise our eyes to that kid... And what could he have proven back then?..</text></string>

<string id="character_hunter_3"><text>Is it possible to train a Zone dog? It'd be nice to have one for hunting. A real hunting dog is highly valued by a real hunter... \nRight before the army. I turned eighteen and my uncle gave me a shotgun. We did all the paperwork properly. And I decided to go on my first solo hunt with my first personal gun. My uncle gave me his best dog, everything as it should be... And I got lost, youth and all. Wandered around for a long time — evening already, getting dark. Finally I came out onto a trail. But Nayda was nowhere to be seen. I shouted, yelled, whistled... It was already dark and raining. Damn it all! I made it out, but the dog followed some track and went off. What to do? Usually in cases like that you mark the spot and leave footwraps under it. Next day you'll find the dog there — it won't go anywhere from those footwraps. That's what I did... Oh, how upset my uncle was, how he grieved: “How could you leave the dog! I'd sooner go hungry myself than not give my last piece to the dog. That's not just a friend — it's your best friend. A dog will never abandon you. And you left her...” I was young, I made excuses. What was I supposed to do? Rain, darkness, no water, no food, I'd lost my matches somewhere. Where would she go? We'll find her tomorrow... But we never did. We searched all week, called, left scents — nothing. Wolves probably killed her. My uncle never forgave me — Nayda was his favorite dog... I never went to visit him again after that.</text></string>

<string id="character_hunter_4"><text>Is there some kind of “hazing” in the Zone? Like dividing people into “you just arrived, I've been trampling the Zone for two years already...” I don't think that's possible when everyone has a gun and ammo... Sure, in every group there's someone senior, like a sergeant, but that's normal — someone has to be in charge... \nI ended up in the army like many others — age and no deferments. I don't think I wasted my time, especially since I didn't serve just anywhere, but in so-called “j?ger” units. That's what they called us — j?gers. In reality we weren't any kind of j?gers — just regular army, but for historical reasons the regiment was quite famous. Like how Moscow-region internal troops are called Chekists. I don't know about others — for us service was just service. But I don't think it was wasted time, especially since I was a sergeant... There was one incident in training: they started checking all units for hazing. Obviously just for show — hazing stayed as it was. Then they came to us. Started digging, asking questions, whether anything had happened, whether anyone had been oppressed... The guys asked me to help, since the opportunity was there. They said, just say a couple of words, that you saw something, that's all. There was this sergeant who was arrogant, showed himself off too much. He never did anything bad to me, but I “signed on” since the guys asked... And then everyone stood on the parade ground, orders were being read after the commission. They brought that sergeant out, tore off his stripes and sent him to the supply unit as a private, in front of everyone. When three hundred people watch you fall, and you know they'll be discussing it for days — and he had only two months left until discharge... I can imagine what he felt... The guys later took me to the canteen, supported me, said I did the right thing. And honestly, I didn't like that sergeant myself...</text></string>

<string id="character_hunter_5"><text>An agreement is worth more than money. That's how it is everywhere, and in the Zone too. If you take on something — do it; if you promise — fulfill it; if you make a deal — stick to its rules. Things are simple here: break an agreement and you might catch a bullet... \nI got a job in a wildlife reserve. As a ranger. Hunting was forbidden there, but sometimes we allowed ourselves culling to regulate population numbers. That day I was walking with a partner to “regulate the duck population” — that's what we called it. There wasn't much game, or rather not much you were allowed to shoot — only within limits. So the agreement was this: no matter what happens, no matter how things go, we shoot strictly in turns. Otherwise — a load of shot in the thigh. Those were the rules. We laughed a bit, but agreed. Everything went fine, we shot according to the deal. Then my partner moved a bit ahead, and I heard a shot... “What was I supposed to do, it flew up right under my nose, I reflexively raised the gun... Stop sulking, look what a drake, a beauty...” He didn't finish — I fired. The load wasn't heavy — small shot, number four. And I'm not an idiot — I didn't aim for bone, I shot into the soft part. The way he looked at me — he was baffled, he simply couldn't imagine I'd do something so “mean.” What did you expect? How is it mean? A deal is a deal. You thought it was a joke or what? No. And it wasn't me who broke the agreement — it was you... I bandaged him, of course, everything turned out fine in the end. But he never understood — for him that shot was a kind of shock. The director was also in shock when he ran into the medical station. “Idiot, who takes such an agreement seriously, it's just a hunters' tale... You wanted to put me under the monastery! That's a criminal case...” But it blew over. My partner took the blame, said it was negligence. Ïðàâäà, I had to leave — they didn't understand me there, and anyway after that incident we wouldn't have worked together anymore...</text></string>

<string id="character_hunter_6"><text>There are rival factions in the Zone. And if you want to remain a free stalker, you have to handle your business so as not to offend either side. The worst thing is if one side finds out you're doing something against them for the other. You have to be very careful here so no one learns anything. Otherwise — a permanent breakup with them... \nMy wife found out I was seeing another woman. Either someone told her, or she followed me, or she figured it out herself — female intuition. I came back from another “hunt.” “So, had your fill of hunting? Living it up with her, huh?..” And she looked at me like, I know everything, you don't have to say a word. I was about to start reciting my prepared explanation, but she didn't let me get a word out — pulled a suitcase from around the corner: here, go to your woman... And she started lamenting: “You said it, you swore you loved us... You lied to us and always lied... Fine, you can tell me whatever you want, but Polinka — what will you tell her, how will you explain the betrayal to her, you won't fool her...” What could I say? How do you explain that men are all males, polygamous by nature. I'm a hunter, I know animal behavior, and man is also part of nature — the same beast in his instincts... Yes, it happened, but it's not a universal catastrophe, everything can be discussed. You're my family, after all. No, and that's it! She's very principled, recognizes no compromises. Once or twice on the side and that's it — betrayed forever... I wanted to say something else, but then Polinka came out of the room: “Daddy, do you love another auntie, are you not living with us anymore?..” And she looked at me like that... Ah! What can you explain after that! I took the suitcase and left... And then the divorce.</text></string>

<string id="character_hunter_7"><text>What a life! Prices in the Zone for some services are rising like yeast. What kind of crazy inflation do they have here? You think you'll get something for one price, come back, and they demand triple for the same thing. The market... \nFor one season in the north I worked somewhere in a procurement office. By then everything had gotten old, I was too lazy even to get off my ass and force myself to go into the forest. What were those squirrels, arctic foxes, martens to me — I'd killed so many in my life. So I became a middleman of sorts with the Evenks or Nenets, who the hell can tell those northern tribes apart... Then problems piled up: I wrecked my car, had to buy a new one, and still pay off the loan on the old one. And for some reason I started building a house — in short, finances were singing the blues... And this stubborn old Evenk kept wheezing and whining: “Why so little? You said you'd give more... Wife very old, son sick... I gathered everything for you, no beast left, beast gone till spring... You promised three each... Why give one? How live now?” All lies, of course. What wife, what son? I didn't promise him anything. Prices were one thing before, now they're different — it's the market, these savages wouldn't understand anyway. And how was I supposed to know my own problems would pile up... He was a skilled hunter — what's a little more or less to him, he'd shoot more game later... Probably... If he didn't die — they're all tubercular or alcoholics up there, they don't live long...</text></string>

<string id="character_hunter_8"><text>Different monsters in the Zone are valued differently. That's understandable — dragging in a bunch of tushkan heads or a giant's paw, there's a difference, right? Or dragging in a controller's hand... Taking down a controller is a serious achievement. They're very rare and valuable, like tigers in the Ussuri taiga. They ought to be entered into the Zone's Red Book... \nSomewhere in the east, deep in the taiga. A friend of mine worked as a ranger in a reserve — Sanya. He urgently had to go somewhere, to his sick mother or something. We met, talked about life, about this and that, and I sang him a song: “Just guide a group of journalists, show them a tiger. They're doing nature shots, documentaries. I'll escort them, you know me, go without fear. Everything will be fine. I've marked all their trails...” He believed me... We took down a prime specimen and handed it over to the client. The payout was decent, more than I expected, and the impressions from that hunt were something else... Then we were drinking, Sanya ran in from somewhere already crooked, and spoiled all the impressions. Calling me a bastard, this and that, saying I not only turned out to be a scoundrel myself, but also set him up... He was yelling drunk, of course; sober he wouldn't have started like that, but I had to pay him off to calm him down. After that our paths parted, forever... To hell with him, some righteous man he turned out to be...</text></string>

<string id="character_hunter_9"><text>Is there anything interesting in the Zone? Something that could interest a person so much they'd go there just for that interest, just to dispel boredom? Surely there's something — plenty of interesting mysteries here. But that's not the only reason I came... \nBored — everything in life became boring. Bored in the city, bored in the forest too... You sit alone for half a year in a one-room Khrushchevka, waiting only for hunting season to open... Then half a year in the forest, also alone — I don't like partners, everyone's always dissatisfied, something's always wrong for them. Alone is better, but sometimes it's boring. On a hunt you might drink with company, talk, tell life stories... But alone? You drink, you eat, and who do you talk to? People stopped being talkative with me. For some reason everyone leaves me. What don't they like? My wife left, friends... well, not friends anymore, former colleagues too — they greet me, but you can see it's just out of politeness... That's how it is. I was sick of everything, needed to shake myself up, start something new, try myself in something out of the ordinary. Otherwise you could hang yourself from boredom or drink yourself to death. Or like this — first drink yourself to death, then hang yourself... And then they were recruiting hunters to work in a closed area — the Zone, that is. Why the hell do they need hunters and who's paying for the “hunt”? I found out later — some institutes, and mostly private clinics, were sponsoring an unusual project. They needed diverse genetic material, and the kind you won't find in an ordinary forest. For very unusual genetic material you need very unusual creatures, which live in a very unusual zone. And the hunters needed weren't ordinary either. In short, everything promised something new, interesting, previously unknown for me. Only that could dispel my boredom. And of course, I signed up...</text></string>

<string id="character_igrok_0"><text>How does a pseudodog attack? It has some special type of attack. Dogs have their own pattern, tushkanos have theirs — those are clear enough. But the pseudo has its own particular principle. Figure it out, and you'll always have the upper hand against it... \nAt the end of summer, in the evenings, we used to bake potatoes in bonfires in the yard with the guys. You poke them with a stick, and they're already all charred. But you won't find potatoes tastier than that. I can still remember the taste. There were lots of guys, but not enough potatoes — well, raw ones were plentiful, but once they were ready to eat, there wasn't enough for everyone around one fire. You couldn't just sit alone by your own fire and bake your own potatoes — that's no fun. So we had to draw lots: matches, bottle caps, whatever — like, “Who hits the tree on the first try gets a potato.” Usually the older guys won, the younger ones almost always lost. Sometimes I got lucky, sometimes I didn't. But with matches I quickly figured out the principle — usually the edge ones are more often at the edge or the middle, so you shouldn't pull from the very edge, but not from the very middle either. In the “hit the tree” game there was also a principle: the main thing was not to go first, but to wait. The first ones usually missed... something like that, I don't remember exactly why. The main thing I understood back then was this: in any game you need to understand the principle — then it becomes clear what to do to win more often... The Zone has its own principle of survival too. You need to understand it if you want to keep winning longer.</text></string>

<string id="character_igrok_1"><text>There are plenty of smartasses in the Zone. Everyone tries to show off, and the biggest show-offs start lecturing you and teaching you how to live. Lower your weapon, don't do this, don't do that, don't steal, don't mess with soldiers... Educators, my ass... \nMy mother was always trying to raise me. My parents didn't interest me much in general. I don't remember my father at all. My mother said he was never around in the first place. Later she tried to arrange her life somehow, and a stepfather appeared. I was afraid of him. He was a harsh man — anything wrong and you'd get a cuff on the back of the head, or even a slap in the face. And his palm was huge — could easily hide half a loaf of bread in his fist. At first my stepfather tried to please me in every way, but when he realized I didn't respect him at all and was slipping out of his control, he started “teaching” me life, “raising” me his way. Then, when we moved to another city, thank God, he took off somewhere. Supposedly even drank himself to ruin, but I didn't see that — my mother told me. My mother still made some attempts to raise me, but I didn't like it, and in general I didn't want to take any part in that process. So we came to an unspoken agreement — I'm on my own, she's on her own... And I like that position here too: I'm on my own, and everyone else can go to hell!..</text></string>

<string id="character_igrok_2"><text>How do you ensure financial independence in the Zone if everything you really need is traded for artifacts? Artifacts aren't mushrooms — today they're here, tomorrow they're gone. It's like a lottery, like a game — lucky or unlucky. What kind of independence is that, when everything depends not even on luck, but on the whims of the Zone... \nBack in my school years I got my first pleasant taste of winning. A slot machine hall opened in our town. They called it a club, but in reality it was just packed with one-armed bandits. People flooded in, and of course I tried it too. At first it was hit or miss. And then one evening I got lucky. I got several bonuses and left the club with a brand-new crisp bill. The next evening, of course, I was there again. I bought tokens with everything I had, fed them into the machine, and three hours later I won five times as much. I went home in style — by taxi. It seemed to me I'd found the winning formula: change the game every ten minutes, and once you get a certain amount, cash out and sit down at another machine. When on my third visit to the club I “took the bank” again, I had an epiphany: two or three times a week you could calmly earn a living. In a month you could make more than my mother earned at her little factory. From then on I became a regular at the club. I was lucky. The “system” worked... for a while. Sometimes it failed, but I didn't get discouraged — at least I had become financially independent. Or so it seemed to me...</text></string>

<string id="character_igrok_3"><text>In the Zone, as everywhere else, there are those who build their lives on other people's gambling. When you see some stalker staking his last on the line, you can't help but smile. But how am I any better?.. \nI always liked games, liked that anticipation of luck, that feeling of fortune... But my first big loss horrified me. Losing almost everything I'd managed to save in one evening, I was baffled. How could that be? Where did I make a mistake? The money I'd won flew away very quickly. My “system” failed, and a dark streak began. My own money ran out, I started borrowing from friends. I didn't want to take money from my mother, and there wasn't much to take anyway — in one evening I'd lose many times more than she could give me. For the first time in my life I realized what dependence on others was like, dependence on money. But I couldn't go and slave away at some office like everyone else. Work was boring routine, and I needed my dose of excitement. After another loss I left the club on unsteady legs and dragged myself home along a night street. My head hurt, my mood was rock bottom, hopelessness. There wasn't a penny in my wallet. I followed some woman for half a block, seriously deciding to attack her, take her wallet, and go back to the club. Thank God I managed to restrain my instincts then. After that, for some time I thought about only one thing — where to get money... But one way or another those thoughts faded into the background — I got drafted into the army, and there you don't really have time to think about money...</text></string>

<string id="character_igrok_4"><text>Poor Zone soldiers, what kind of service do they have here... Boredom, no entertainment, no leave. So they shoot dogs and tushkanos out of boredom. Arrange firing sessions... \nI know there are people who actually want to go into the army, even consider it their duty. That wasn't me. I didn't want the army and dodged it as long as I could. I kept hoping for luck — maybe they'd forget about me, maybe they didn't need me... They didn't forget. I considered that time crossed out of my life. What could be interesting or exciting there? Boredom. The only entertainment was the firing range. And that's where I came up with a game... It just so happened that we shot a lot — every two weeks there were firing exercises, sometimes by day, sometimes by night. The game was simple: two runs on the range, fifteen rounds each, three targets, two hits per target. Whoever used the fewest rounds, but not fewer than six, won. I shot well — otherwise I wouldn't have invented the game, knowing I'd be at a disadvantage. But others got the hang of it too, so we had to change the rules — still minimum rounds, but technically: exactly two per target, and with time measured too... The company sergeant major was unhappy, yelled at us, cursed — he didn't want to recount and hand in the leftovers after each of our sessions: “Idiots! Can't shoot for shit — they give you a magazine, so just fire it all into the air! I have to haul the crates back afterward!” But by then we had excitement. We played among ourselves, between squads, pair against pair, rookies against old-timers... Different ways. At first we played for butter, for sugar, for “who takes someone to the canteen,” but what did I care about food. I already understood how to arrange things and came up with a game for duty — the loser takes duty, the winner gets exempted from it... So I only worked duties during the first third of my service; after that I always tried to come out on top...</text></string>

<string id="character_igrok_5"><text>Some stalkers rush in blindly, wherever they can, like children. If you want guaranteed success, read the instructions, get maps, study the materials, develop your own system. And only then go in prepared... \nAfter the army I got a job, but my working career didn't last long. I had no desire to slave away from bell to bell, no interest, no motivation. You'd have to go to some boring job for a month, stare at the ceiling, and wait for payday just to blow it all in one evening and then spend another month in dull anticipation of the next paycheck... No thanks. That wasn't for me. But luck smiled on me. That day the first computer gaming club opened in our rundown town. Of course I couldn't miss such an event. And that's where I first learned that you could play poker online. That there were exchanges, clubs... and that it was all for real — real money, real bets, real winnings. That very day I bought all the manuals on card games from a little bookstore. Poker interested me the most. I began to study and drill everything thoroughly. But that wasn't enough, so I went online for instructions. I immersed myself in “studying.” Of course, I started going to the club, testing my strength, but at the same time I was developing “my system.” Before I started placing big bets, I had to be prepared...</text></string>

<string id="character_igrok_6"><text>There's a simple way to solve difficult everyday questions — it's called drawing lots. Flip a coin — heads or tails — a kind of handheld random number generator for decision-making, a simple game. Here in the Zone you often have to do it like that — go right or left... \nThat's how I got married, stupidly enough — I was used to blaming everything on fate. There was Lyubakha — so-so girl, but well-off; and there was Nadyukha — a great girl, but poor as dirt and with a whole harem of sisters. And I was full of doubts. I relied on chance — how the card would fall. So I cast lots and married Nadyukha. And then they all started sawing at me with their whole harem — this isn't enough, that isn't enough, you're this, you're that, you drag money out of the house for your games... That alone would've been tolerable, if not for the mother-in-law. If I met her now, I'd shoot her. A real sawmill, that one! “Parasite, loafer... Everyone else is like people, only you have nothing but games on your mind — a grown man, and you wear out your pants in clubs. If you were at least wasting your own money, but you don't bring in a penny and even drag it out of the house...” Damn it, that's all I remember from my whole “happy” family life. Nothing else comes to mind...</text></string>

<string id="character_igrok_7"><text>You can't lose track of time in the Zone. You need to know when night is coming — night is dangerous; you need to know when an emission is due and how long it will last. You have to calculate your strength if you take on a courier job, to make it on time. Time matters in the Zone... \nThe breath of the Internet touched me too, like many others. Life went on in waves, sometimes a white streak, sometimes a black one, depending on luck. But I managed to buy a computer and get connected. And then a completely different life began. Now I didn't have to go to the club to “work,” now I decided myself when my workday started and how long I could “work.” Sometimes I worked myself to exhaustion. One week I almost dropped dead. I spent a total of six days at the computer, eighteen hours each... I bet and won, then lost almost everything, then went all-in with the remainder and won again. I built up a huge bank, thought that just a little more and I'd leave the game — but the next draw wasn't mine and I crashed out... I swung like a pendulum, with rare breaks for four or five hours of sleep. I didn't cook anything for myself, drank tea and occasionally ordered pizza. It was as if I were tied to the computer — I was obsessed with the game, the thrill, the thirst for profit. The world around me didn't interest me, time stopped, I didn't know whether it was day or night outside... That week I wore myself out completely and left the game only because the connection was cut. Turns out I'd lost track of time and forgotten to pay the provider. They disconnected me. I collapsed exhausted and slept for a full day. Later, when I did the math, I realized I'd ended up with only a small bonus, like on the first day of the game. Turns out I could've quit back then already...</text></string>

<string id="character_igrok_8"><text>In my opinion, the main thing in the Zone isn't finding fat, rare artifacts, but managing to sell them quietly so you stay unnoticed. So no one understands why that stalker was poor as a church mouse and now lives it up. That means he's got something else. Where from? That means he needs to be felt out — made to share... \nLuck favors the prepared. I heard that phrase somewhere, in some movie. And it's true... One evening OMON stormed our “youth interest club.” They'd been tipped off that drug dealers were covering this gambling den. That didn't interest me much — I'd never messed with drugs. I wandered in out of old habit, to visit acquaintances. The only thing that interested me was the game, the thrill, the hope of success, that adrenaline that makes life not so dreary as it is outside the club. So they searched me on the way out and let me go, like everyone else who'd come just for interest... And so I'm walking home, taking the direct route — through the front garden; I already had a superstition about it — that path led to luck... I didn't immediately realize what I'd found, what kind of briefcase it was. But when I opened it... Yes! That was it! Luck. The bird of happiness. I always knew I'd catch it by the tail. I was ready to put it in my cage... It wasn't hard to piece things together — I understood perfectly what kind of money it was and why there was so much in one place, but I had no strength to refuse it. I held out for a week, then when I decided things had settled down, I started spending a little, then more, and then I went all out, living large... But how can you live with money and not gamble? Of course they noticed me — noticed the bets I was placing, sifted through the channels, matched events and facts, and also realized that the money hadn't fallen into my lap from the sky... After that everything was simple. A serious talk with serious people, a demand to return what was “not mine,” otherwise... By then I didn't even have a quarter of that amount left. And I decided to win it back. That day I put everything on the bank...</text></string>

<string id="character_igrok_9"><text>What draws people to the Zone more? The desire to run away from their problems, the thirst for adventure, or the wish to get rich quick, to grab a big haul?.. \nIf it were up to me, I'd never have come here voluntarily. What kind of idiot did you have to be to believe all those tales those guys were pouring into my ears at that apartment of the lame guy near Kyiv. One was pimply, the other reeked of tobacco — he smoked nonstop. Now I understand they were recruiters themselves, telling exactly what they needed to tell... But who needed it? Who are those gray figures that lure suckers like me here? And why did I, the fool, bite — I don't understand, for the life of me. My head was buzzing, my vision darkening, I was either drunk or drugged... And for some reason I wasn't afraid, I even believed them about fast, easy money, about a colossal jackpot you couldn't get in any other game. And that you didn't have to do anything — wealth would just fall into your hands. But I still can't understand who one of them was talking to when he said: “You'll work it off, kid, for your debts... And don't take what isn't yours. It's fine, you'll rise fast there... There's no point in a dead man, but this way you'll pay us back with interest, and for starters we'll take what you have — you'll sign a deed of gift.” What else they said, I can't remember. Seems we were drinking something, my vision was swimming, one of them was whispering something in my ear, and the other kept pushing some sheet of paper and a pen at me... it kept falling out of my hands, he'd pick it up, shove it back and keep pointing with his finger where to sign... No, if I'd been in my right mind back then, I'd never have come here...</text></string>
